<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="fileXSL.xsl"?>
<regions>
    <region area="nav-world">
        <news>
            <title>This is the messy truth about Ebola</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/health/2014/10/09/this-is-the-messy-truth-about-ebola-miguel-marquez-graphic-orig.cnn.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>What happens when you get Ebola? CNN's Miguel Marquez explains (Sources: CDC and WHO).
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>This is the messy truth about Ebola</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/health/2014/10/09/this-is-the-messy-truth-about-ebola-miguel-marquez-graphic-orig.cnn.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>What happens when you get Ebola? CNN's Miguel Marquez explains (Sources: CDC and WHO).
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>ISIS trying to overtake Anbar province</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/world/2014/10/12/pkg-wedeman-anbar-falling-to-isis.cnn.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>New recruits are bolstering the ISIS advance, while the Iraqi army is suffering from abandonment and incompetence.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>ISIS trying to overtake Anbar province</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/world/2014/10/12/pkg-wedeman-anbar-falling-to-isis.cnn.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>New recruits are bolstering the ISIS advance, while the Iraqi army is suffering from abandonment and incompetence.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Chinese court sentences cult members to death over McDonald's killing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/asia/china-eastern-lightning-death-sentence/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>Five members of a Chinese cult have been sentenced for a murder in a McDonald's
Two were sentenced to death for the killing of a woman who refused to give them her number
The group, Church of Almighty God, has been banned in China since 1995
Its members believe Jesus has been reincarnated as a Chinese woman
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>809</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Two members of a banned Chinese doomsday cult were sentenced to death Saturday for the brutal murder of a woman in a McDonald's restaurant in May, Chinese state media reported.
Zhang Fan and Zhang Lidong were among five members of the Church of Almighty God, or "Quannengshen," tried on murder charges in August over the killing in Zhaoyuan, Shandong Province, the state-run Xinhua agency reported.
Three fellow cult members, Lyu Yingchun, Zhang Hang and Zhang Qiaolian, were sentenced to life, 10 and seven years in prison respectively for their roles in the attack. The four Zhangs were related, according to the report.
A court statement said the victim, a 37-year-old woman named Wu Shuoyan, was attacked after refusing to give her phone number to the group, who were allegedly attempting to recruit new members.
Zhang Fan and Lyu called her an "evil spirit," before Zhang bludgeoned her head with a chair, then jumped on her and trampled her head, the statement said.
Zhang Lidong bashed the victim's head with a mop hard enough to break it, and stomped on her face and head, while Lyu kicked her waist and prevented McDonald's staff from intervening, the court statement said.
IN DEPTH: 'Eastern Lightning,' the banned religious group that has China worried
Linked to kidnappings, violence and extortion, the Church of Almighty God has been on a list of 14 banned religious groups issued by China's Ministry of Public Security since 1995.
Founded in the 1990s in Henan Province, the group believes that Jesus has been reincarnated as Yang Xiangbin, the wife of the group's founder, Zhao Weishan. The couple fled to the United States in 2000, Xinhua reported.
The group, also known as Eastern Lightning ("Dongfang Shandian"), preaches that the righteous are engaged in an apocalyptic struggle against China's Communist Party -- which it refers to as the "great red dragon."
Belonging to a tradition of heterodox, quasi-Christian Chinese religious movements, the cult was estimated as having between several hundred thousand and one million members, according to Emily Dunn, an Asian studies academic at the University of Melbourne who wrote her doctoral thesis on the group.
In August, Chinese state media reported that police had arrested nearly 1,000 suspected members of the group, including nearly 100 "backbone members."
The report said those arrested were responsible for "numerous" suicides and murders, including those of their own family.
In 2012, hundreds of members were rounded up after the group publicly proclaimed the end of the world was imminent.
In a statement provided to CNN in June, Hong Kong-based members of the group responsible for its English-language website said it was "very natural" for the Chinese Communist Party to blame the group for the McDonald's death because the party slandered and then suppressed those that disagreed with it.
"They always find some excuse in advance and fabricate things and slander them," said the statement.
READ MORE: The future of Christianity in China
CNN's Dayu Zhang and Katie Hunt contributed to this report.
</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140604013136-eastern-lightning-split-story-top.png</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Oscar Pistorius a 'broken man,' psychologist says at sentencing hearing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/africa/south-africa-pistorius-sentencing/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Oscar Pistorius "will be able to love somebody else," prosecutor says
The judge in his case cleared him of murder but found him guilty of culpable homicide
There is no legal minimum or maximum term for culpable homicide
Pistorius will also be sentenced on one weapons-related charge involving a restaurant shooting
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1359</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark and Faith Karimi, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Oscar Pistorius is a "broken man" after the death of his girlfriend, a psychologist said Monday, as his defense used a sentencing hearing to try to convince a judge of his fragile emotional state.
Dr. Lore Hartzenberg said the Olympian described his girlfriend, Reeva Steenkamp, as the love of his life. He lost faith in himself and his abilities after the killing, she said.
But the prosecution dismissed her findings.
"We're dealing with a broken man, but he's still alive," Prosecutor Gerrie Nel said in an apparent reference to the fact that Steenkamp is not. "He has lost his love relationship ... but he will be able to love somebody else like that."
What would Pistorius face if he's sent to prison
New woman?
Nel questioned the psychologist about a woman the Olympian allegedly started seeing after the death of his girlfriend. Hartzenberg said she's not aware of his new relationship, and the two never discussed it during their sessions.
The onetime South African sporting hero was found guilty of negligent killing last month in Steenkamp's death. The hearing that will determine whether he's going to prison began Monday and is scheduled to continue Tuesday.
Joel Maringa, a social worker at the South Africa Department of Correctional Services, recommended "correctional supervision" rather than prison time. His report was at the request of the defense.
Guilty of culpable homicide
Judge Thokozile Masipa, who presided over Pistorius' high-profile trial and delivered the verdict last month, will decide his sentence.
Pistorius was found guilty of culpable homicide, the South African term for unintentionally, but unlawfully, killing a person. However, the judge cleared him of murder in Steenkamp's death and granted him bail pending the sentencing hearing.
The hearing is likely to take several days, as the prosecution and defense put their arguments before the court.
There is no legal minimum sentence for culpable homicide in South African law, so it will be up to the judge to decide.
A typical sentence is five to eight years. But it is a principle of South African law that the sentence should be tailored to the culprit as a whole person, as opposed to the crime. That makes predicting a sentence difficult, said Kelly Phelps, a CNN legal analyst.
The judge also found Pistorius guilty of one weapons-related charge involving a shooting at a restaurant.
The maximum penalty for that is five years behind bars. But he could get a lesser sentence, such as a fine or the loss of his gun license.
What would prison life be like?
If Pistorius is sent to prison, it's unclear whether his disability would allow him any special treatment. And daily life behind bars probably would not be easy.
Born with a congenital abnormality, he had his legs amputated below the knee before his first birthday and uses prosthetic limbs to get around. The carbon-fiber blades he used to compete on the track -- before Steenkamp's killing abruptly halted his running career -- earned him the nickname "Blade Runner."
During his trial, his defense highlighted his vulnerability when on his stumps and a court-ordered psychiatric assessment found he was depressed, suffering from post-traumatic stress and a suicide risk.
South Africa's prisons are notorious for overcrowding, which puts a strain on sanitation, ventilation and medical care for inmates.
Pistorius probably would receive far better treatment than the average prisoner, as he has throughout the judicial process, said Nooshin Erfani-Ghadimi, project coordinator for the Johannesburg-based Wits Justice Project, a civil society group.
Even so, she said, it will not make much difference.
"I don't think anyone with a disability necessarily will be able to be provided for at the moment in a way that ensures that they would have the correct medical treatment, that they have the correct physical structures," she said.
Steenkamp: model and law graduate with 'wicked' sense of humor
'Conduct was negligent'
Pistorius, 27, has always admitted firing the bullets that killed Steenkamp, 29, a model and reality TV star. He pleaded not guilty to murdering her in his home on Valentine's Day last year, saying he mistook her for an intruder.
But in grabbing his gun and heading toward the supposed threat, Pistorius "acted too hastily and used excessive force," the judge ruled last month.
"His conduct was negligent" and not what a reasonable man would do in the circumstances -- not even a disabled one, she said.
Who is 'Blade Runner' Oscar Pistorius?
Appeals process
Pistorius can appeal the verdict or the sentence, potentially to the Supreme Court of Appeal and even eventually to the South African Constitutional Court.
The state can appeal only if it believes the judge misinterpreted the law in reaching her verdict.
The right to appeal depends on whether, based on the facts of the case, the initial judge or magistrate believes a different court could possibly reach a different verdict.
CNN's Emily Smith and Richard Allen Greene contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Taliban attack on military convoy kills 14 Afghan soldiers and police</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/asia/afghanistan-attacks/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>Insurgents strike a military convoy in northern Afghanistan and kill 14 people, officials say
200 Taliban fighters attack 180 Afghan forces in a remote part of Sar-e-Pul province
Taliban capture six soldiers, Afghan forces kill 23 Taliban in the fighting, officials say
A suicide car bomb in Wardak province kills 14 people, including nine civilians
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1444</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Susanna Capelouto and Masoud Popalzai, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Taliban insurgents have killed 14 Afghan National Security forces, including two policemen, in northern Afghanistan, government officials said.
About 180 Afghan security forces were traveling in a convoy Sunday when more than 200 Taliban fighters attacked them in a very remote part of Sar-e-Pul province, Gov. Abdul Jabar Haqbeen told CNN.
The Taliban captured six soldiers, 17 others were injured, and 23 Taliban insurgents were killed in the fighting, Haqbeen said.
Also on Sunday, a suicide attack in Wardak province killed 14 people, including nine civilians, a province spokesman said.
A car full of explosives blew up near an Afghan National Army vehicle, according to Wardak officials.
Two other vehicles with civilians were also destroyed in the blast, and six people were injured, officials said.
Drone strikes kill 8 in Afghanistan, Pakistan
Mohammad Ehsan Popalzai contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Scuffles as protest opponents try to tear down Hong Kong barricades</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/china-hong-kong-protest/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Scuffles as people opposing occuption try to remove protest barricades
Democracy campaigners have been blocking key routes through the city
C.Y. Leung: Protests a "mass movement that has spun out of control"
Students write open letter to Chinese President Xi Jinping
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>852</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Hilary Whiteman, CNN</author>
            <text>Hong Kong (CNN) -- Rowdy scenes erupted at the main Occupy Central protest site in Hong Kong on Monday after hundreds of people opposing the pro-democracy occupation tried to tear down protest barricades.
Police formed a human chain to separate the protesters and people intent on breaking up their three-week long occupation of the Admiralty district, near the city's financial center.
Dozens of men, some wearing surgical masks, were seen jostling with protesters and demanding that police remove the barricades and clear the roads, according to live images from local television station iCable.
They were heard screaming at protesters, accusing them of damaging their livelihoods. The television commentator identified them as taxi drivers, transport industry workers and other people who said they weren't affiliated with any groups.
However, protesters could be heard yelling, "there are triads here," a reference to criminal gangs in the city known for controlling smuggling, prostitution and illegal gambling rings.
Police on loudspeakers called for calm, and eventually convinced protesters to form a corridor to allow their opponents to leave.
Earlier, police started to remove barricades from protest sites in Admiralty and Mong Kok, but issued a statement saying they were moving "obstacles" to relieve traffic "not to clear the scene."
Police "pushed back a couple of barricades, dismantling them," said CNN's Ivan Watson, from the Admiralty protest site. He said the protesters had responded by moving their tents closer to the barrier but the streets had remained peaceful.
READ: Who is C.Y. Leung?
Protest disruption
At the peak of the protests, which started in late September, tens of thousands of demonstrators crowded onto the streets demanding a greater say in how the city is run.
Protesters have been guarding barricades erected at the protest sites, and for many nights slept in the open air on bitumen before the arrival of reinforcements with tents on the weekend.
Traffic in the other parts of the city has been clogged due to road closures, bus and tram cancellations and the need for cars to drive around the protest sites. Taxi drivers say their takings are down, and businesses have claimed the protests have cost them income.
While protest numbers dwindled towards the end of last week, they started building again over the weekend when protest leaders called for reinforcements after the government called off talks planned for Friday.
First live address
Over the weekend, Hong Kong Chief Executive C.Y. Leung made his first live address since protesters blocked key routes through the city. Speaking on local free-to-air station TVB, Leung said the protests were not a "revolution," but a "mass movement that has spun out of control."
He said student leaders had "almost zero chance" of pushing Beijing to chance its stance on how Hong Kong's leader is elected. He added he would not accede to the protesters' demands that he resign, because his resignation "will not solve the problem."
"It is because the students and other occupation protesters demand more than that. They want the Standing Committee to withdraw its August 31 decision. That is impossible," he said.
READ: Who's who in the protests?
Beijing white paper
He was referring to the white paper issued by the Standing Committee of China's National People's Congress stating that Hongkongers would be able to vote on their leader in 2017, but only from an approved shortlist of candidates.
In response to Leung's comments, the three main groups leading the occupy campaign said it was the government that was out of control -- "a government that fires tear-gas at unarmed citizens and unilaterally terminated dialogue with the students (sic)."
On September 28, police fired 87 tear gas rounds into the crowd after protesters failed to disperse. The move was seen as a miscalculation and only served to garner support for the protesters who accused the government of heavy handedness and of stifling free speech.
READ: The end of police trust?
Open letter to China
Over the weekend, student leaders from protest group Scholarism and the Hong Kong Federation of Students wrote an open letter to Chinese President Xi Jinping, urging him to closely consider their cause.
"There will only be more citizens, disillusioned with our corrupted institutions, marching and protesting, as long as no genuine democracy is practiced in this place," they wrote.
The letter said the occupation was "definitely not a colour revolution or its alike, but rather a movement for democracy," referring to the term "umbrella revolution" which was coined after protesters used umbrellas to shield themselves from pepper spray and tear gas.
View from China
Xi has not commented on the protests, but Chinese censors have been busy blocking reports of the movement, including access to the photo-sharing site Instagram.
A commentary published in China's state-controlled People's Daily on Monday, entitled "Why is the U.S. so keen on Color Revolutions?", accused the U.S. of meddling in Hong Kong affairs.
"It is hardly likely that the U.S. will admit to manipulating the "Occupy Central" movement, just as it will not admit to manipulating other anti-China forces. It sees such activities as justified by "democracy," "freedom," "human rights" and other values," it said.
It said the mainstream U.S. media had shown "exceptional interest" in "Occupy Central" and had tried to portray it as Hong Kong's version of a "Color Revolution," referring to pro-democracy movements around the world including the "Arab Spring" and Ukraine's "Orange Revolution."
"The U.S. may enjoy the sweet taste of interfering in other countries' internal affairs, but on the issue of Hong Kong it stands little chance of overcoming the determination of the Chinese government to maintain stability and prosperity," it added.
CNN's Wilfred Chan and Anjali Tsui contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un misses shrine visit, KCNA reports</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/world/asia/kim-jong-un-north-korea/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: U.S. officials downplay Kim's absence at Friday tribute
Kim's name is missing from a list of attendees at a shrine visit
The North Korean leader was expected to attend the annual ceremony at his father's shrine
Kim hasn't been seen in weeks; he'd been expected to attend Workers' Party ceremonies
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2202</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Madison Park, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The mystery of Kim Jong Un's whereabouts deepened Friday after the North Korean leader appeared to have missed a ceremony to pay tribute to his late father and grandfather on what is an important national anniversary.
Kim's name was absent from the list of attendees at the Kumsusan Palace of the Sun in Pyongyang on the 69th anniversary of the Workers' Party of North Korea, issued by state news agency KCNA on Friday.
The Workers' Party, founded in 1945, is North Korea's political party and is considered one of the country's most crucial institutions alongside the military.
According to KCNA, flowers were presented at the shrine in Kim's name, but the most senior official to attend was Hwang Pyong So, North Korea's second most important leader, who recently attended the closing ceremony of the 17th Asian Games in South Korea.
Kim hasn't been seen in public since he reportedly attended a concert with his wife on September 3. It's his longest absence from official events since he made his first public appearance in 2010, said NK News, a website devoted to analyzing North Korea.
Analysts are puzzled and speculation is running rampant about why Kim has been out of the public eye.
State media attempted to explain his absence by saying Kim was experiencing "discomfort."
He had been seen hobbling earlier in the summer, prompting theories ranging from weight gain to gout. There have also been questions about the possible meaning behind his absence: Is he genuinely sick, or are there machinations within the North Korean power circle?
Is Kim Jong Un's sister in charge?
North Korea as Rorschach test
"Whenever someone doesn't show up in the public, we tend to speculate something of a power struggle," said Han Park, author of "North Korea Demystified."
Because not much is known about North Korea's internal politics, observers scrutinize public functions and ceremonies to see who appears and who does not.
"We're always operating on this incomplete info," said Joshua Stanton, a North Korea observer who created the website One Free Korea, which is critical of the regime.
Drawing conclusions about what's happening in North Korea has been likened to a Rorschach test -- it's a reflection of the views of whoever is drawing the conclusions, rather than an informed analysis based on facts. And the facts in the reclusive country are murky at best.
"People have a tendency to see the things they want to see," Stanton said. "We should default to skepticism."
Opinion: Why Kim is probably still in charge
South Korean official: Kim probably near hospital
South Korea's defense minister told reporters in Seoul on Friday that he "has reason to believe that Kim Jong Un is probably staying in one of his homes" near an exclusive hospital in North Korea's capital, Pyongyang, with his wife and sister.
The facility named by the official, Bongwha hospital, is known to be an exclusive facility catering to high-ranking members of North Korea's ruling party.
It wasn't immediately clear why the defense minister said he thought Kim was staying near the hospital.
U.S. officials downplay Kim's absence
Senior officials in U.S. President Barack Obama's administration said Friday they believe there's no indication that Kim has been sidelined or is in very bad health.
While they acknowledge there is little information available, the officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Kim is believed to have non-life-threatening medical problems, citing the limping seen this summer.
"He is overweight, smokes and drinks heavily and doesn't do any exercise," one senior U.S. official said. "He can't be in good shape, but there is no indication of serious trouble in terms of health or stability."
With Kim out of sight, North Korean top brass visit South
The sources downplayed Kim's absence at Friday's tribute and said there was nothing to substantiate speculation that other members of the regime had marginalized him.
"We don't believe fundamentally there is anything afoot," a second senior U.S. official said. "There is nothing affecting our policy choices in any way."
The officials noted that previous North Korean leaders Kim Il Sung and Kim Jong Il disappeared for long stretches of time, only to re-emerge and cast aside rumors about their leadership.
"It's a dictatorship," the second U.S. official said "But it gets them attention and makes the ultimate big reveal that much more newsworthy."
North Korea's diplomacy efforts
With its top leader missing in action, North Korea has extended its diplomatic efforts with the outside world.
One of its officials said the regime was ready to restart the six-party nuclear talks, which include Russia, the United States, China, Japan and South Korea. It has also reached out to the European Union and South Korea.
High-ranking Pyongyang officials visited South Korea on Saturday, but just days later, the two countries were exchanging fire at a disputed maritime demarcation line.
North and South Korea exchange fire
The mixed messages reflect Pyongyang's "state of constant and ever-shifting cost-benefit calculation to maximize its national self interests," said Jasper Kim, founder of the Asia-Pacific Global Research Group.
"Every move North Korea makes is a negotiation attempt to see which states will accede and offer something of value in exchange for some level of stability. This has and always will be North Korea's dominant negotiation strategy."
Longest absence
Kim made only one official appearance in September. This has happened only once before, in September 2010, and that was the month in which Kim made his first official public appearance alongside his father at Kumsusan Palace of the Sun, NK News said.
Before this absence, his longest disappearance from public view as Supreme Leader was a 24-day period between June 7 and July 1, 2012. His second longest absence ever was for 29 days between July 28 and August 27, 2011 -- while his father was still alive, NK News said.
Kim's sole public appearance in September was at a Moranbong Band concert at Pyongyang's Mansudae Art Theatre, reported by state media on September 4. He was accompanied by his wife, Ri Sol Ju, his sister Kim Yo Jong and several top officials including Hwang Pyong So.
CNN's Elise Labott, Paula Hancocks, KJ Kwon, Michael Martinez, Brian Todd and Dugald McConnell and journalist Jung-eun Kim contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Vongfong slams into Kyushu, continues destructive path across Japan</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/tropical-storm-vongfong-japan/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>Tropical Storm Vongfong hits Kyushu, the southernmost of Japan's four main islands
At least 36 injuries have been reported
Japan's four main islands are expected to get up to 40cm of rain
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1408</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Junko Ogura and Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>Tokyo (CNN) -- The latest and strongest in a string of powerful storms to hit Japan -- Vongfong -- slammed into Kyushu, the southernmost of the country's four main islands, Monday morning as it continued its destructive path across the country.
Vongfong first made landfall in Japan in Okinawa early Sunday. It wreaked havoc across the prefecture, knocking out power before losing strength and being downgraded from a typhoon to a tropical storm.
Meteorologists expect the storm to pass over the country's largest island, Honshu, hitting the capital, Tokyo, before dawn on Tuesday.
At least 36 injuries related to the storm were reported across Okinawa, Kagoshima and Miyazaki prefectures, officials said, while at least 44,000 across the country were without power.
Authorities have ordered more than 100,000 people to evacuate their homes.
Police in Shizuoka said one man remained missing after three people were swept into water on Sunday at the city's port.
Although a high-wave advisory had been issued at the time of the accident, the incident was classified as a water accident and not officially linked to the storm, according to Shizuoka police.
Flights in and out of Kyushu and neighboring Shikoku were canceled Monday, along with local ferry and train operations.
The Japan Meteorological Agency said Vongfong was expected to bring up to 40 centimeters of rain.
The storm comes on the heels of Typhoon Phanfone, which swept over southern Japan last week, washing three U.S. airmen out to sea off Okinawa.
U.S. and Japanese search crews found the last airman's body on Wednesday, according to a news release issued by authorities at Kadena.
Japan was previously saturated by storms Halong, Neoguri and Nakri.
CNN's Tom Sater contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Boko Haram hostages freed in Cameroon</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/world/2014/10/12/pkg-kinkade-cameroon-hostages-freed.cnn.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>27 hostages freed from Boko Haram have arrived in the capital of Cameroon. Lynda Kinkade reports.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Boko Haram hostages freed in Cameroon</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/world/2014/10/12/pkg-kinkade-cameroon-hostages-freed.cnn.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>27 hostages freed from Boko Haram have arrived in the capital of Cameroon. Lynda Kinkade reports.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Russia says it's pulling 17,000 troops from near Ukrainian border</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/europe/russia-ukraine/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Ukrainian teams will be granted access to MH17 crash site, Dutch official says
Russia says the troops were stationed near the border for training exercises
But the troop presence has been viewed as a threat to invade Ukraine
It's not clear whether the withdrawal has actually taken place
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>16</time>
            </date>
            <author>From Matthew Chance and Holly Yan, CNN</author>
            <text>Moscow (CNN) -- Russian President Vladimir Putin has ordered 17,600 troops near the Ukrainian border to return to their bases, state-run media reported.
The reason? The Russian troops' training exercises in the southern Rostov region have ended, according to the RIA Novosti news agency.
But many did not believe such exercises were taking place. The troop buildup near the Ukrainian border has been widely interpreted as a threat to invade eastern Ukraine.
If the troops do indeed leave the border area, the withdrawal could mark a removal of that threat. So far, NATO has not confirmed whether the troops have actually began to withdraw.
Tensions in the region have flared since April, when separatist leaders in Ukraine declared independence from Kiev and violence broke out in two Ukrainian regions that border Russia.
The conflict between the pro-Russian rebels and the Ukrainian military has cost more than 2,500 lives, according to the United Nations.
War: What is it good for?
Russia's announcement of the troop pullback comes as Putin and Ukrainian President Petro Poroshenko prepare to meet in Milan on sidelines of the Asia-Europe Meeting later this month.
In another sign that tensions have cooled somewhat, Ukrainian emergency services will be granted passage Monday to the site in rebel-controlled eastern Ukraine where Malaysia Airlines Flight 17 crashed in July.
After negotiations led by the Organization for the Security and Co-operation in Europe, Ukrainian teams will be allowed to gather belongings of crash victims at the site and from locals in the area, Dutch Security and Justice Ministry Spokesman Jean Fransman told CNN.
Ukraine and Russia have been under a shaky cease-fire since last month, when government officials from the two countries as well as rebel leaders from eastern Ukraine hashed out a deal in Belarus.
Yet the bloodshed continued.
Ten civilians were killed when a school in the city of Donetsk was shelled, according to the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe.
And one day later, Swiss Red Cross worker Laurent DuPasquier was killed when a shell landed near an International Committee of the Red Cross building in Donetsk.
Matthew Chance reported from Moscow; Holly Yan wrote from Atlanta. CNN's Laura Smith-Spark contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-us">
        <news>
            <title>Teen killed after haunted hayride in Maine flips over</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/us/maine-hayride-accident/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>The accident killed a 17-year-old high school student, officials say
More than 20 others were injured, a CNN affiliate reports
Authorities are investigating the cause of the accident
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>15</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Anne Woolsey and Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A 17-year-old girl died after a haunted hayride flipped over in Maine, police said Sunday.
The teen was airlifted to a hospital after the accident Saturday night, Central Maine Medical Center spokesman Chuck Gill said.
More than 20 other people were injured, CNN affiliate WMTW reported.
The accident happened during what's called The Gauntlet, a spooky hayride through forest that includes "things that jump and scream in the night." The activity is part of Pumpkin Land, a venue featuring a variety of Halloween-themed activities in Mechanic Falls, about 30 miles north of Portland.
The 17-year-old who died was on the ride with other students from Messalonskee High School in Oakland, Maine, according to WMTW.
Investigators say they think a mechanical problem prevented a Jeep that was towing a tractor-trailer from stopping, WMTW reported, citing the state fire marshal's office. The Jeep went off the road, careened down a hill and slammed into a tree in a heavily wooded area around 8:30 p.m. Saturday, the CNN affiliate said.
Authorities have impounded the Jeep and are investigating what caused the crash.
CNN's Greg Botelho, Kristina Sgueglia and David Shortell contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Child who fell into jaguar exhibit at Arkansas Zoo is in stable condition</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/us/child-injured-zoo/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Child now listed in stable condition, according to hospital
Yellow jaguar "bit the clothing near the neck area"
Witnesses say the little boy fell approximately 15-16 feet
Zoo staff are trained to use fire extinguishers to ward off dangerous animals
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1654</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Azadeh Ansari and Joshua Berlinger, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A child who fell into a jaguar exhibit at the Little Rock Zoo in Arkansas on Friday is now listed in stable condition, according to a hospital spokesman.
The 3-year-old boy's condition has been updated from critical to stable, according to a press release from Arkansas Children's Hospital obtained by CNN affiliate KARK.
The child, who is not being named, is expected to improve.
"We respect the wishes of the child's guardian, who asked that the child's name and any additional information not be shared at this time," said Dan McFadden, director of communications for the hospital.
Witnesses say screams for help rang out loudly after the 3-year-old boy slipped through the exhibit rail feet first, plummeting into the cat pit, according to a Little Rock police report.
The child was with his father and grandfather at the time of the incident. The father told Little Rock police he was leaning over the rail in an attempt to take a photograph of the animals and observed his son's feet go over the rail out of his peripheral vision. The child's grandfather says the little boy fell approximately 15-16 feet, police said.
Two jaguars in the enclosure attacked the toddler. "The black cat had bit the child on the foot area and the yellow jaguar had bit the clothing near the neck area," read the police report, quoting the grandfather.
Fire extinguishers were used to ward off the big cats in the exhibit, while a zookeeper lowered a ladder, climbed into the cat pit and retrieved the child, according to a statement released by the zoo.
Zookeepers said the rescued child was conscious and responding.
Though doctors said the wounds are not life-threatening, the toddler had an extensive scalp laceration, a depressed skull fracture and minor puncture wounds, according to the police report.
"Our thoughts and prayers are with the child and the family. The safety of our citizens is of paramount value and our staff followed training procedures on rescuing the child and were able to respond quickly and efficiently and work with emergency personnel, said Bruce Moore, Little Rock city manager, in a statement.
City officials said a full investigation into the incident is being conducted.
Family settles lawsuit in mauling death of boy at Pittsburgh Zoo
CNN's Carma Hassan and Chandler Friedman contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>5,000 spiders force family from home</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/us/2014/10/11/pkg-5000-brown-recluse-spiders-force-family-from-home.kmov.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>Around 5,000 brown recluse spiders forced a family to move from their home worth nearly $500,000.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>5,000 spiders force family from home</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/us/2014/10/11/pkg-5000-brown-recluse-spiders-force-family-from-home.kmov.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>Around 5,000 brown recluse spiders forced a family to move from their home worth nearly $500,000.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Shocking video in NFL fan brawl</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/crime/2014/10/11/pkg-simon-49ers-fans-beating-paralyzes-man.cnn.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>Prosecutors say two men face assault charges after a brawl in a Levi Stadium bathroom left one man partially paralyzed.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Shocking video in NFL fan brawl</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/crime/2014/10/11/pkg-simon-49ers-fans-beating-paralyzes-man.cnn.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>Prosecutors say two men face assault charges after a brawl in a Levi Stadium bathroom left one man partially paralyzed.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Judge overturns Alaska's same-sex marriage ban that dates to 1998</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/us/alaska-same-sex-marriage/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>The state says it will appeal the judge's ruling
But how much luck it will have remains to be seen
Five gay couples sued the state in May to overturn the ban
Sunday's ruling is yet another victory for supporters of same-sex marriage
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1145</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Saeed Ahmed, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- In 1998, Alaska became the first of two states to pass a constitutional amendment to ban same-sex marriage.
On Sunday, a federal judge overturned the 16-year ban, saying the Constitution guarantees equal protection to all.
The judge's ruling makes Alaska the latest state where gay and lesbian couples can legally marry.
"The plaintiffs in this case do not ask the court to recognize an entirely new fundamental right to same-sex marriage; rather, plaintiffs wish to participate in the existing liberty granted to other couples to make a deeply personal choice about a private family matter," U.S. District Judge Timothy Burgess wrote in his 25-page ruling.
Alaska says it will appeal.
"As Alaska's governor, I have a duty to defend and uphold the law and the Alaska Constitution," Gov. Sean Parnell said.
But how much luck the state will have going that route remains to be seen.
An appeal will take the case to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, which last week ruled against Idaho and Nevada in similar cases.
First-in-the-nation ban
Alaska passed its amendment in 1998 and joined Hawaii as the first of two states to define marriage as a union between a man and a woman.
At the time, Alaska said the ban "does not target anybody or deny anybody their rights."
Burgess said it does.
"By singling out homosexual couples and banning their ability to marry an individual of their choosing, it is impossible to assert that all Alaskans are equal under the state's laws."
Five gay couples sued the state in May to get the constitutional amendment overturned.
Another victory
Sunday's ruling is yet another victory for supporters of same-sex marriage.
In a surprise move on October 6, the Supreme Court refused to get involved in the constitutional debate over same-sex marriage. That decision allowed same-sex couples to wed legally in five states -- Virginia, Utah, Oklahoma, Indiana and Wisconsin.
Then, a three-judge panel from the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit concluded the bans in Idaho and Nevada violated the equal protection rights of homosexuals to legally marry.
On Friday, a federal judge in North Carolina ruled that same-sex marriage can begin there.
"Alaska had the misfortune of being the first state, in 1998, to ban equal marriage and bake discrimination into our constitution," said Joshua Decker, executive director of the Alaska ACLU. "Today's decision allows Alaskans to marry and to have their outside marriages recognized here. This victory brings equal rights to thousands of Alaskan couples who are in loving, committed relationships."
Like dominoes falling
Here's where things stand. At least 27 states now allow same-sex marriage -- an increase of at least 13 states since the beginning of the month.
Those states are: California, Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Hawaii, Idaho, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Minnesota, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Utah, Vermont, Virginia, Washington state and Wisconsin, plus the District of Columbia.
Eight more states, including Alaska, could soon legalize it, after the cases wind their way through the federal appeals process: Alaska, Arizona, Kansas, North Carolina, Montana, South Carolina, West Virginia and Wyoming.
CNN's Bill Mears contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>California drought victims drink in grandmother's kindness</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/us/california-drought-homes-without-running-water/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>California's historic drought leaves nearly a thousand people without water
Residents filled with dread when water stopped coming out of their taps
A grandmother ends her retirement to help out neighbors who don't have water
She buys and delivers bottled water, inspiring donations
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1910</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Michael Martinez, Sara Sidner and Traci Tamura, CNN</author>
            <text>East Porterville, California (CNN) -- California's historic drought has finally delivered its ultimate devastation: hundreds of homes in one community bone dry, devoid of tap water.
The Central Valley farming community of East Porterville is a place where 400 homes are without running water. No showers. No flushing toilets. No way to wash dishes.
That's because private wells have run dry. Turning the spigot is a futile exercise.
"At first, it was dread that came over us. What are we going to do?" said Tony Alvarez, 62, a father of five whose home has been without water for weeks. "We are a low-income family. Things are hard enough as it is, trying to get everybody to school and get everybody ready."
The worst of the drought is tormenting the Tulare County community 160 miles north of downtown Los Angeles.
In East Porterville, drinking water comes from private wells, not public utilities. Of the community's 7,300 residents, nearly 1,000 are without running water, county officials said.
Into this void has stepped a 71-year-old grandmother who saw a need and responded.
She started by buying bottled water with her own money and delivering it to a list of people -- which just kept getting longer.
'An angel'
What began as a mission of charity by Donna Johnson, a retiree, is now a well-publicized relief effort, inspiring businesses and others to donate bottled water.
"She has a big heart. She's an angel," resident Angelica Gallegos said of Johnson.
Johnson regularly visits Gallegos' door to ensure that she, her 5- and 10-year-old girls and husband have enough water for the week, Gallegos said. Johnson does the same for the elderly, the sick and anyone who needs it.
She interrupted her retirement when she discovered just how many of her neighbors were living without running water.
"So many people were not informed of what to do in a drought like this. I thought there are people who don't speak English, people that are elderly, they're pregnant, have diabetes, that are ill, everyday people. It doesn't have any prejudice. It affects everybody from the low-income to the higher-income person," Johnson said.
State of emergency
Johnson's humanitarian project comes as 100% of California faces at least a moderate drought and more than half of the state faces the worst category of dryness, called an exceptional drought, the U.S. Drought Monitor says.
California isn't the only state feeling an absence of rain. As of late September, 30% of the Lower 48 faced at least a moderate drought, particularly in the Southwest states neighboring California and in Texas, the Drought Monitor says.
But none of those states is facing the extremes of California, where the drought has been a slowly building natural disaster since 2012. In fact, Gov. Jerry Brown this year declared a state emergency, saying his constituents are facing "perhaps the worst drought that California has ever seen since records (began) about 100 years ago."
On September 16, Brown signed "historic legislation" that creates "a framework for sustainable, local groundwater management for the first time in California history," the governor's office said. Before the new legislation, California was the only Western state that didn't manage its groundwater, officials said.
In the meantime, dramatic struggles and responses are unfolding in communities like East Porterville, whose new heroine is receiving national attention.
With one jug of water in each arm, Johnson moves at a frantic pace through the dust and often 100-degree heat to deliver drinking water to as many people as possible, as fast as she can. She is now assisted by Matt Rogers, her 19-year-old neighbor who saw how she helps people suffering from the drought.
"It's almost like an illness. It kind of spreads and all of a sudden it's a catastrophe, and it is a disaster," Johnson said.
Ahead of officials
Without Johnson's effort, officials say they would not have known just how many people were hurting.
"She really helped raise awareness about how bad it was in this confined area," Tulare County Emergency Services Manager Andrew Lockman said.
Many residents never thought the drought could so profoundly alter their lives.
"You never expect it and you never want to live through this. It's really hard," 17-year-old Sandra Tapia said as Johnson delivered water.
Her father, a field hand, came home one day in August and discovered there was no running water for his family of six.
"You can't go to the bathroom, you can't take a shower, you can't wash dishes. You have to conserve every single drop," Tapia said.
Officials say they value Johnson's bringing attention to the disaster because some residents simply don't know what would happen if they told authorities about their lack of running water.
Community in fear
For example, some residents worried the government would red-tag their homes and make them move. Migrant workers worried their landlords would kick them out if they reported the problem. Undocumented immigrants panicked about being deported if they had contact with authorities.
Authorities sought to soothe those suspicions and fears.
"We're not here to make things worse," Lockman said.
The 400 private wells without water in East Porterville are just a fraction of the 30,000 private wells throughout Tulare County, which also includes portions of the Sierra Nevada and the Sequoia and Kings Canyon national parks, officials said.
As distressing as the empty wells are, officials are also concerned it will take a long time to restore all of them, whether empty or low.
"The issue is we still expect this to get worse, even if we get a substantial rainfall this winter. A lot of the areas in the county are going to take a year or two years to recharge their water levels," Lockman added.
There is no quick fix.
A grandmother weeps
Homes with private wells aren't hooked up to water mains, and such a connection could take years, officials said. The original deal was that residents with private wells would not get a water bill but were responsible for maintaining the wells.
That became a problem in the drought because many residents can't afford the thousands of dollars it takes to drill a deeper well. Moreover, even if residents have the money, there is up to a two-year backlog to hire a company to do the job, officials said.
In the meantime, county officials are helping residents secure grants for delivery of commercial bottled water.
For now, the county is offering a 5,000-gallon tank of water outside the local fire department. Residents can't use that water to drink or wash dishes because it's not potable, but they can use it for toilets, baths and laundry. Residents show up not just with buckets but 55-gallon drums.
On a recent afternoon, as he filled up several jugs of water, Alvarez, the father of five whose home has been without water for weeks, called the tank a real help, but he worried about folks who don't have transportation and are out of water.
That is where Johnson comes in.
At first, she bought the bottled water with her own money and delivered it herself, but now she enjoys donations of bottled water and help from the young neighbor who was inspired by her work.
She labors voluntarily through the heat three days a week, but the demands of one recent day proved to be overwhelming: Johnson broke down in tears, feeling the depths of the insidious disaster.
She finds comfort in her work, though. That's because her private well has run dry, too, and she savors the kindness of donations.
"Without water, you can't survive, you can't keep your home and you can't keep water in it, and my heart goes out to everybody," she said.

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Ferguson protests: Weekend of demonstrations, day of action</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/us/ferguson-protests/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Protest organizers: "Police brutalized peaceful people protesting their brutality"
About 2,000 people attended an interfaith rally where activist Cornel West spoke
Demonstrators are angry about police killings of Vonderrit Myers and Michael Brown, both 18
At St. Louis QuikTrip, police pepper spray protesters in reminder of violence in Ferguson
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1409</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Sara Sidner, CNN</author>
            <text>St. Louis (CNN) -- A weekend of protests is expected to culminate in a day of action in Ferguson, Missouri, on Monday.
Demonstrators demanding the arrest of the police officer who killed Michael Brown say they will take part in a "series of actions" Monday morning, but they haven't said what or where those will be.
On Sunday night, about 2,000 people attended an interfaith rally, where activist and Princeton University professor Cornel West was the featured speaker.
Before he took the stage at the St. Louis University's Chaifetz Arena, some protesters demanded a chance to speak.
"If you can see a dead black boy lie in the streets for four hours and that doesn't make you angry, you lack humanity," a woman, who didn't give her name, told the crowd.
She was referring to how long the body of Brown lay on a street before investigating officers removed it.
The protests, dubbed a "Ferguson October" and "Weekend of Resistance," are taking place in Ferguson, St. Louis and the surrounding area.
Demonstrations focused on the August 9 encounter between Brown, 18, and Police Officer Darren Wilson, who authorities said shot Brown after he attacked him and tried to take his gun.
Mom, daughter trek 750 miles on $100 budget to join 'Weekend of Resistance'
But witnesses said the unarmed teenager had his hands in the air when he was shot.
The shooting prompted weeks of protests in Ferguson, which sometimes became violent when demonstrators and police clashed.
The demonstrators are demanding that Wilson be charged with a crime -- a point that West also made.
"Everybody knows if you shoot somebody down, you should be arrested," he said.
He asked the crowd to channel their rage into a plan of action for change.
New wave of protests
Before this week, protests had died down considerably.
But early Sunday, protesters threw rocks at police and tried to storm a QuikTrip store, according to tweets from St. Louis Metropolitan Police Chief Sam Dotson.
In the Shaw neighborhood of St. Louis, protesters have also rallied against the death of Vonderrit Deondre Myers, 18.
Protests erupted there after a white police officer fatally shot the black teenager. But this one was different from the Brown case because the teenager was armed and fired at the officer, according to authorities.
#ferguson #shawshooting protestors take moment of silence @st louis university clock tower. #CornelWest in crowd pic.twitter.com/BOOqOECv19
Two groups of hundreds of protesters gathered in Shaw before splitting and reconvening at St. Louis University, according to CNN affiliate KTVI.
One group threw a volleyball and jumped rope while chanting, "This is what a game looks like. We aren't playing games."
The group marched to a QuikTrip, a reminder of the violence that happened in Ferguson, where protesters destroyed a QuikTrip in the days after the Brown shooting. Police were at the convenience store, which had been closed as a precaution, the station reported.
The crowd prompted Dotson to tweet that demonstrators were trying to "storm" the gas station, and he warned that "protesters engaging in illegal behavior will be subject to arrest."
After clerks locked the QuikTrip door, fearing the store could be looted and burned like the one in Ferguson, police in riot gear used pepper spray on sitting protesters surrounding the QuikTrip, CNN affiliate KPLR reported.
Police told the protesters to disperse, but they wouldn't, so officers moved in, clacking their night sticks on their leg shields as they approached, the station said. Dotson tweeted that protesters threw rocks at police.
Seventeen people were arrested for unlawful assembly, but no injuries or property damage was reported, KPLR said.
'They attacked people'
Ferguson October, the group that helped organize the protests, took issue with Dotson's tweets, saying they only made matters worse.
"Today protestors in St. Louis showed the best of our democracy and the St. Louis police demonstrated the worst of their out-of-control law enforcement agency. The police brutalized peaceful people protesting their brutality," the statement said. "With batons and chemical agents they attacked people peacefully sitting on the ground and the reporters who were there with them."
At St. Louis University, roughly 2 miles from the Shaw neighborhood where Myers was shot, about 1,000 protesters gathered on campus, using the hashtag #OccupySLU to convince people and businesses to donate supplies or join an all-night sit-in. As of 5:30 a.m., about 80 protesters remained on campus, CNN affiliate KMOV reported.
"The goal was to occupy SLU and to kind of wake up the campus. I think there's a sense in the community that SLU is kinda shut off from what happens outside of SLU. But this latest incident was six blocks from SLU, so it does affect us," freshman David Gramling told the station.
Young Nigel waits for the rest of the #FergusonOctober marchers to catch up. pic.twitter.com/p41U76eQOp
Early Monday morning, about 200 protesters marched from the site where Myers was shot, holding signs that read, "Black lives matter."
Police with riot gear showed up on a bridge near the St. Louis University campus. The protesters turned on the other side of the street, stayed on the sidewalk and walked past them.
The demonstrations were peaceful, and the protesters said they were serious about keeping them that way. On Sunday, Ferguson October was training protesters in nonviolent civil disobedience.
"Nonviolence is really important because you're not going to change someone's mind by being violent. And also there is just so much more power in taking a stand and doing it nonviolently," Jasmin Maurer, who is taking part in the peaceful training, told KPLR.
Meanwhile, authorities also took additional steps to prepare for the protests, as police told KMOV that every patrol officer in St. Louis -- city and county -- is working 12-hour shifts and days off have been canceled. City police would not say how many officers were working in the area, but a county police sergeant told the station there were about 200 officers in Ferguson alone.
CNN's Eliott C. McLaughlin contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Seven teens charged in Sayreville High School assaults</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/new-jersey-football-abuse-scandal/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>Six of seven teens charged are taken into custody
Upperclassmen allegedly turned off the locker room lights, howled and abused freshmen
Superintendent: "Incidents of harassment, intimidation"
Parents and players vented frustration over the season's shutdown
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>648</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Azadeh Ansari, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Six teenage football players accused of hazing and sexual assault at a New Jersey high school were taken into custody Friday evening, according to the Middlesex County Prosecutors office.
Upperclassmen howled as they flipped off the lights then sexually abused their younger classmates at Sayreville High School, parents and players say.
The identities of the teens, ranging in age from 15 to 17, are being withheld because of their ages, but the Middlesex County Prosecutor's Office released details of the charges in a statement Friday. A seventh teen also has been charged.
"Three of the juvenile defendants are charged with aggravated sexual assault, aggravated criminal sexual contact, conspiracy to commit aggravated criminal sexual contact, criminal restraint, and hazing for engaging in an act of sexual penetration upon one of the juvenile victims," the release stated. "One of those juvenile defendants and the remaining four juvenile defendants were charged with various counts including aggravated assault, conspiracy, aggravated criminal sexual contact, hazing and riot by participating in the attack of the remaining victims."
A family court will decide whether the six teens will be held at a detention facility pending a court hearing or will be released to the custody of their parents or guardians pending the hearing, the prosecutor's office also said in the press release.
The coach and officials would not comment on details of the abuse, but it may have gone on for a year. A Sports Illustrated article indicated that it likely did not involve intercourse.
"There were incidents of harassment, intimidation that took place on a pervasive level, in which the players knew, tolerated and in general accepted," says Superintendent Richard Labbe, who has canceled the successful team's football season.
The Sayreville Bombers took the state championship three out of the last four years. Now parents used to watching their sons' spirited team reign victorious on the gridiron are upset the season won't continue.
"I've never seen so much dedication out of my son, and I want him to play the rest of this season," a mother said at a school meeting to the roar of applause. Despondent players vented frustration over not being able to finish what they've started.
They are at odds with parents and players who broke the allegations. That group is less vocal and declined to be interviewed on camera, afraid to voice grievances out loud.
Parents on both sides have hired lawyers.
A hearing date has not been determined, according to the Middlesex County Prosecutor's Office.
CNN's Ben Brumfield, Miguel Marquez and Kristina Sgueglina contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>113-year-old time capsule found in Boston</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/boston-time-capsule/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>Time capsule hidden since 1901 in Boston is discovered
It holds photographs, campaign buttons and news clippings from the day
The copper box is found in a statue atop the State House
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1656</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Kevin Conlon</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A time capsule hidden for more than a hundred years at one of Boston's most popular tourist attractions was opened on Friday in Boston.
According to the Bostonian Society, which maintains the 1713-built Old Massachusetts State House, the rectangular copper box containing a variety of artifacts from 1901 was sealed inside one of two iconic statues -- a lion and a unicorn -- that have been a familiar sight atop the Old State House for a couple of centuries.
The Bostonian Society didn't -- or couldn't -- fully divulge the 113-year-old time capsule's contents, explaining that "the process of extracting documents that are old and probably fragile will need to be slow and careful." But a Boston Globe article from February 24, 1901, detailed what went into the box, which the story predicted would "prove interesting when the box is opened many years hence."
According to the Globe, the box included the photographs and autographs of local statesmen such as Massachusetts Gov. Winthrop M. Crane and Boston Mayor Thomas Norton Hart, as well as news clippings of the day from several city newspapers and even a "letter to posterity from the reporters of the Boston Daily newspapers assigned to City Hall."
It also included a photograph of the "5th Massachusetts Regiment on its way to Framingham to be mustered in as U.S. volunteers for service in the war against Spain," as well as "campaign buttons for McKinley, Roosevelt and John D. Long for vice president."
The box was sealed inside the lion's head by Samuel Rogers, a local coppersmith who was part of the crew renovating the nearly 200-year-old State House. Although the occasion was detailed in the city's largest newspaper, the Bostonian Society said its current staff was unaware of the time capsule until they received a letter from a descendent of Rogers alerting them to it.

</text>
        </news>
        <news/>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-africa">
        <news>
            <title>For Ebola caregivers, enormous fear, risk and bravery</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/health/ebola-health-care-workers/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>WHO: At least 416 health care workers have contracted Ebola; at least 233 have died
Caregivers deal with fear among patients and themselves; many grapple with lack of equipment
A Dallas nurse became the first person known to have contracted Ebola inside the U.S.
The nurse was treating a Liberian national in Dallas who died from the virus last week
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2057</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Ashley Fantz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- They dedicate their lives to saving others, but as Ebola spreads worldwide, health care workers must also focus on saving themselves.
An American doctor and a North Carolina missionary working with Ebola victims were the first to bring the deadly virus to the United States when they contracted the virus in Liberia and were flown home for treatment.
Now, a Dallas nurse has set a similar milestone, becoming the first person known to have contracted the disease inside the U.S. She was wearing the proscribed protective gear -- gloves, mask and shield -- while recently caring for Liberian national Thomas Eric Duncan at a Dallas hospital. Duncan died last week.
While the Texas nurse remains in isolation, a nurse in Spain who contracted the virus after treating a patient in that country is struggling for her life.
There are so many caregivers who've become patients. At least 416 health care workers have contracted Ebola, and at least 233 have died, the World Health Organization reports. In Liberia, the worst-affected country, the virus has killed more than 100 medical workers.
Since the Ebola outbreak began -- the worst the world has seen -- doctors and nurses have described working conditions no one should endure.
Every single move they make in treating a patient must be perfect. One slip-up -- a torn glove or the smallest splat of infected fluid that gets on them -- could cost them their lives.
One provider in West Africa spoke of waking up every morning with a sore throat from constantly breathing in the fumes from chlorine that must be constantly sprayed to kill the virus that is capable of thriving not just in living organisms but on surfaces for some time if conditions are right.
Health care workers battle not just a disease but rumors among patients in Africa that Ebola is a myth the government is perpetrating. In a profession that already demands much emotionally and physically, these caregivers are pushed to the edge in both respects. They have lost friends, colleagues and patients.
All this as they beat back their own understandable paranoia and fear. Have I done everything correctly? Could I be next?
Caregivers' cry for help
Last week, Doctors Without Borders, an independent international organization that helps victims of tragedies in the world's most dangerous zones, said that a Norwegian staffer had contracted Ebola. The staffer had been working in the Sierra Leone city of Bo and was being sent to Europe for treatment.
Doctors Without Borders said it's repeatedly asked for help from the international community but "to this date, very little has materialized in concrete action on the ground," its website says. The organization's teams, composed of 3,058 staff working in Guinea, Liberia, Nigeria, Sierra Leone and Senegal, are seeing "critical gaps in all aspects of the response, including medical care, training of health staff, infection control, contact tracing, epidemiological surveillance, alert and referral systems and community education and mobilization."
In September, CNN visited Bomi County, Liberia, where there were only two doctors covering its 85,000 residents and trying to care for Ebola patients in a 12-bed facility that wasn't even a proper Ebola treatment center.
A nurse inside a Monrovia clinic wore a camera showing his job, revealing that he worked inside a clinic with seemingly unclean conditions. Patients were lying on stretchers on floors that appear filthy, and there were open buckets lying around with objects and substances in them.
The situation for caregivers across Liberia has become so dire that nurses are now are threatening to strike.
Just days ago, CNN's cameras captured crowds of caregivers yelling outside Liberia's largest Ebola treatment center in Monrovia.
Underscoring the serious consequences of a Liberia without health care workers, President Ellen Johnson Sirleaf arrived to try to calm the crowd.
"We're trying to meet all their needs, and we'll continue to do that," she told CNN, struggling to be heard above the shouting.
"I don't want to strike," one caregiver said, telling CNN that he foresees deaths increasing several thousand-fold if facilities' conditions don't improve.
"But the President has to listen to the massive health care workers out there," he said. "There are angry people. You don't want to have angry people knocking on your doors during this kind of emergency situation."
This weekend, The Washington Post detailed horrific conditions at a Monrovia Ebola facility where one doctor died from Ebola and another tested positive for the virus. The Post reported: "Doctors put on their protective gear in the kitchen. There is no incinerator, so a 10-foot pile of Ebola-laced garbage and excrement sits in the back yard. There is no morgue, so bodies sometimes decay outside, next to where patients sit in white lawn chairs. There are no protective hoods for the full-body medical suits," so caregivers make their own.
There have also been questions about how tight security is at health care centers. In August, CNN reported that an Ebola treatment facility in Monrovia was overrun by an armed mob who stole mattresses and equipment. Ebola patients fled, local authorities said.
A legacy of self-sacrifice
The mother of modern nursing, Florence Nightingale, suffered for her dedication to treating patients during the Crimea War. It's believed that she also contracted a bacterial infection as she treated the wounded, dealing the effects of the illness for much of her life.
Just as Nightingale was revered as a hero, so too was Dr. Sheik Umar Khan, a top doctor from Sierra Leone who specialized in Ebola. He died in late July from the virus.
He had been overseeing Ebola treatment at Kenema Government Hospital, about 185 miles east of Sierra Leone's capital city, Freetown. Doctors Without Borders was treating him.
If Khan could get sick, then any other caregiver could, wrote Dr. Oliver Johnson from King's College London, who treated Ebola patients this summer.
Read more: Ebola's frontline -- battling fear and the deadly virus
Even before the Ebola outbreak, Sierra Leone had already been suffering from a shortage of doctors, nurses and infrastructure, he said. The jobs of health care workers were made all the worse when they attempted to track and monitor the contacts of infected people because roads were difficult to traverse. Crowded housing made the effort even more difficult, he said.
Yet even with the best medicine in the most modern facilities does not guarantee safety.
The nurse at Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital in Dallas who has Ebola had "extensive contact" at the same hospital with an Ebola patient who died last week, health officials said.
The woman had on a gown, gloves, mask and a shield when she visited the patient multiple times, they said, but there was a breach in treatment protocol.
Dr. Tom Frieden, the director of The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, did not detail what that breach might have been.
But Frieden did say that merely taking off protective gear is "a major potential area for risk" if not done meticulously, and officials are investigating whether that's what might have caused the nurse to become infected.
Hours after Frieden spoke, nurses who are part of the union National Nurses United gathered in Oakland, California, for their own news conference. Holding up signs that said "Stop blaming nurses. Stop Ebola," they blasted the notion that they would be at fault.
Her voice rising as she spoke, Katy Roemer, a 20-year nursing veteran, said that colleagues throughout the United States. have reported to the union that they are not being adequately trained to recognize and care for Ebola patients even though they have asked employers for that.
"They have not given us this information," she said.
Enormous pressure and risks
What does it feel like to know you're going to treat a patient with a disease that kills 90% of its victims?
What is it like to have never before dealt with Ebola, but know that a patient is about to land in your hospital under your care?
"There was no way to fully prepare for the pressure, the national focus, the immensity of being responsible for curing a patient whose deadly disease was at the center of global debate," wrote Angela Hewlett in The Washington Post. The infectious disease physician is an assistant medical director for the Nebraska Biocontainment Patient Care Unit at the Nebraska Medical Center where she treated American Dr. Richard Sacra.
Sacra, who had worked as a missionary in Liberia, was treated in isolation at the Nebraska Medical Center in Omaha and then released after testing negative for the virus.
She wrote about going through drills and training and about feeling nervous before he arrived. She talked with her family about what they might experience from people judging or making comments born of ignorance and fear about the virus.
She also illuminated the difference between a doctor who able to connect and comfort a patient through touch by placing a hand on an arm. Establishing that calm and assurance is a vital and human part of being a caregiver. But Ebola takes that from nurses and doctors. It is interrupted by bulky gear. The key to not getting Ebola, after all, is to keep those suffering separate from others.
And yet nurses and doctors continue their work out of practical necessity and because it's their commitment and passion and because, as Hewlett noted, they are fascinated by how medicine might defeat a virus that's considered a global threat.
And for some in West Africa, it really is a matter of survival.
"What's else can we do? If we don't do it, who will do it for us?" one Liberian nurse told CNN. "So we have to take the risk and care for the patients or else our country will be wiped away."
Read more: Cuban doctor train to fight Ebola
CNN's Nima Elbagir contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Blast rocks Somalia's capital, killing at least 10 people, police say</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/africa/mogadishu-blast/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>At least 10 people have been killed in a car bombing in Mogadishu, police say
The explosion happened outside a popular restaurant in Somalia's capital
15 others are wounded; the Al-Shabaab terror group claims responsibility
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>29</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Omar Nor and Chandrika Narayan, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A car packed with explosives blew up outside a popular restaurant in Somalia's capital Sunday evening, killing at least 10 people, police said.
Fifteen others were wounded in the blast in the heart of Mogadishu, senior Somali police Officer Farhah Aden said.
He said the death toll could rise, since many of the victims were seriously injured.
The car was parked at the gate of the Oromo restaurant before it was detonated, Aden said. The hotel is popular with Somalian government officials and is just a few kilometers from the country's parliament compound.
An eyewitness said he saw a ball of smoke rising into the sky after the explosion.
"I was inside the restaurant at the time of the blast," Ibrahim Mohamed said. "I heard a loud sound of an explosion from the gate of the building and went outside, where I saw dead bodies lying on chairs they were sitting down in, using the Internet."
The Al-Shabaab terror group has claimed responsibility for the attack, according to the spokesman for the group, Sheikh Abdiaziz Abu Musab. Last month, the group's leader was killed in an American airstrike.
Intelligence reports at the time indicated the group was planning new attacks after the death of Ahmed Godane.

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Texas nurse who had worn protective gear tests positive for Ebola</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/health/ebola/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>A "close contact" of the nurse is being monitored, says CDC
The worker helped care for an Ebola patient multiple times, CDC director says
He says there was a breach in protocol and his agency is investigating
Nurse was wearing protective gear when she helped care for Thomas Eric Duncan
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1112</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Elizabeth Cohen, Steve Almasy and Holly Yan, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The deadly Ebola virus has been contracted by someone inside the United States for the first time.
A nurse who had worn protective gear during her "extensive contact" at a Dallas hospital with an Ebola patient who died tested positive during a preliminary blood test, officials said Sunday.
The woman had on a gown, gloves, mask and a shield during her multiple visits with Thomas Eric Duncan, but there was a breach in protocol, health officials said.
The patient is a nurse at Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital in Dallas, an official who is familiar with the case told CNN.
The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Atlanta conducted testing on the blood sample, and confirmed the results Sunday, marking the first known transmission of Ebola in the United States and the second diagnosis in the country.
She was involved in Duncan's care after he was placed in isolation -- his second trip to the hospital after coming to the United States from Liberia -- said Dr. Tom Frieden, the director of the CDC.
The nurse is in stable condition, Texas Health Resources chief clinical officer Dan Varga said. Duncan, the first person to be diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died Wednesday.
What's a hospital supposed to do if an Ebola patient shows up?
The nurse had "extensive contact" on "multiple occasions" with Duncan, Frieden said.
"At some point, there was a breach in protocol, and that breach in protocol resulted in this infection," he said at a news conference Sunday. "The (Ebola treatment) protocols work. ... But we know that even a single lapse or breach can result in infection."
Also, Varga said that someone who is a "close contact" of the nurse has been "proactively" placed in isolation.
The hazardous materials unit of the Dallas Fire Department has cleaned up and decontaminated the public areas of the health worker's apartment complex, Mayor Mike Rawlings said. Police are keeping people out of the area and are talking to residents nearby.
"We have knocked on every door on that block," the mayor said.
Hazardous materials units have also cleaned out the nurse's car and will work on her apartment Sunday.
"This development is understandably disturbing news for the patient, the patient's family and colleagues and the greater Dallas community," the CDC said in a statement, announcing the nurse's test results.
It sought to play down a wider risk.
"The CDC and the Texas Department of State Health Services remain confident that wider spread in the community can be prevented with proper public health measures, including ongoing contact tracing, health monitoring among those known to have been in contact with the index patient, and immediate isolations if symptoms develop," the CDC said.
Complete coverage on the Ebola outbreak
Case was anticipated
"We knew a second case could be a reality, and we've been preparing for this possibility," Dr. David Lakey, commissioner of the Texas Department of State Health Services, said in a statement Sunday morning.
"We are broadening our team in Dallas and working with extreme diligence to prevent further spread."
The nurse reported a low-grade fever Friday night and was isolated, the health department said. The preliminary test result came in late Saturday.
President Barack Obama received two briefings Sunday on the second Dallas Ebola case, including one from Health and Human Services Secretary Sylvia Burwell. According to a White House statement, the President wants federal authorities to immediately take further measures to ensure health care professionals are able to follow protocols for treating Ebola patients.
'A sign the system is working'
The news that a health care worker might have the disease is not completely unexpected, an infectious disease specialist told CNN's "New Day."
"I think we've always expected that there may be another individual who will come down with the Ebola from the transmission of this one particular person, and we always felt that it was going to likely be one of his close contacts or one of the health care workers, because that's the way this virus works," Dr. Frank Esper said.
For Ebola caregivers, enormous fear, risk and bravery
Esper said Texas officials have been keeping a close eye on people who had contact with Duncan.
"I will tell you that the fact that we identified this individual so quickly is actually to me a sign that the system is working," he added.
Globally, the disease has wrought catastrophic consequences.
The World Health Organization estimates more than 8,300 people have contracted Ebola during this year's outbreak. Of those, more than 4,000 have died.
Ebola not very contagious
Ebola is actually difficult to catch. People are at risk if they come into very close contact with the blood, saliva, sweat, feces, semen, vomit or soiled clothing of an Ebola patient, or if they travel to affected areas in West Africa and come into contact with someone who has Ebola.
Those stricken with Ebola suffer ghastly symptoms, including vomiting, diarrhea, muscle pain, fever and internal bleeding.
Three countries -- Sierra Leone, Guinea and Liberia -- have been hardest hit. And many of those who care for the ill have also come down with the disease.
The World Health Organization estimates at least 416 health care workers have contracted Ebola, and at least 233 have died.
In Liberia, health care workers are threatening to strike if their work conditions don't improve.
The first infection outside of Africa happened in a nurse's aide in Spain, Teresa Romero Ramos. She became sick after she helped treat an Ebola-stricken Spanish missionary.
Her case has prompted questions from fellow medical professionals about whether they are properly equipped to safely treat Ebola patients.
Spanish Ebola patient's condition worsens, doctor says
Another search begins
For weeks, health officials have been monitoring those who had contact with Duncan before he was hospitalized and isolated.
Duncan left Liberia on September 19 and arrived in Dallas on September 20. Four days later, he began feeling ill; the following night, he went to Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital.
But despite telling a hospital worker that he had arrived from Liberia, Duncan was sent home with antibiotics. He returned a few days later and tested positive for Ebola.
And now, the search begins for all the contacts whom the nurse came in contact with.
"We need a whole new crew of people to do contact tracing," said Elizabeth Cohen, CNN senior medical correspondent.
Because Ebola's incubation period can last up to 21 days, the health nurse's contacts will have to be monitored for three weeks.
The Texas health department said officials have interviewed the patient and are identifying any contacts or potential exposures.
"This is not an easy thing," Cohen said. "Keeping track of large numbers of people, taking their temperature twice a day, making sure they don't ... leave town, all of that is a lot of work."
CNN's Joe Sutton, Cassie Spodak and Jen Christensen contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Texas health care worker may be first person to contract Ebola in U.S.</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/health/ebola-up-to-speed/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Texas health worker reports fever Friday, preliminary positive test for Ebola on Saturday
Airport screenings started Saturday at JFK airport in New York
Spokesman: US Airways followed CDC guidelines after health scare on Dominican flight
Hotel closed in Macedonia after sudden death, ministry says
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1540</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Faith Karimi and Ashley Fantz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Concerns about the Ebola virus were heightened Sunday when a health care worker in Texas had a positive preliminary test for the disease. If confirmed by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the worker's case would mark the first known transmission of Ebola in the United States and the second-ever diagnosis in the country.
With developments pouring in from all corners of the world, here's what you need to know to quickly get caught up:
WEST AFRICA
No relief in sight:
The number of deaths attributed to the current Ebola outbreak has climbed to 4,033, the World Health Organization reported Friday. The tally brings the total number of confirmed, probable and suspected cases of Ebola to 8,399. The numbers were reported from Guinea, Liberia, Nigeria, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Spain and the United States.
A possible $32 billion hit:
The outbreak could cost the African economy $32 billion over the next two years if it spreads to its larger neighbors, the World Bank estimates.
The steps some countries have taken to prevent the spread of the Ebola virus amount to "putting a towel under the door of a building on fire," World Bank president Jim Kim told CNN's Richard Quest on Thursday.
Complete coverage on Ebola
Liberia postpones election:
Liberia's President on Thursday postponed a senatorial election that had been set for this week, citing the Ebola outbreak in the country.
The nation's election commission had recommended the delay, saying the prevalence of the virus, authorities' efforts to combat it and citizens' efforts to isolate themselves weren't conducive to a free and open election.
Officials have not yet revealed any new date for the election, which had been set for Tuesday.
U.S. troops arrive in Liberia:
A group of 90 U.S. Marines and airmen arrived in Liberia on Thursday to help Ebola response efforts, along with four V-22 Osprey aircraft and two C-130 transport planes.
Their arrival brings the total number of U.S. troops deployed in Liberia to 334, military spokesman Lt. Col. Dave Doherty said. There are more coming. In late October, 700 troops from the 101st Airborne Division are scheduled to deploy to Liberia.
U.S. troops battle invisible enemy in Liberia
U.S. CASES
New case in Texas:
A person who helped to treat Thomas Eric Duncan may be the first person to contract the disease while in the United States. The health care worker from Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital tested positive in a preliminary test Saturday after reporting a low-grade fever Friday. The CDC is working to confirm the diagnosis.
'Modest improvement' for NBC cameraman:
The family of NBC cameraman Ashoka Mukpo, who contracted Ebola while working in Liberia, is cautiously optimistic after doctors said his condition at a Nebraska hospital has improved slightly.
Mukpo, an American citizen, has shown "very modest improvement," according to The Nebraska Medical Center, where he is being treated.
Mukpo is receiving an experimental drug called brincidofovir, or CMX001.
"Mr. Mukpo's condition is slightly improved," medical director Dr. Phil Smith said. "He's been taking in some fluids and drinking Gatorade. But everyone needs to be reminded that this is still a very serious illness we're dealing with and no one has a lot of experience treating it."
Thomas Duncan dies:
Thomas Eric Duncan, the first person diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died Wednesday, 10 days after he was admitted to Dallas' Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital. His family wonders whether the outcome would have been different if doctors had admitted him to a hospital on September 25, the first time he showed up with a fever and stomach pain.
Duncan's family has criticized the care he received. The Dallas hospital that treated him says staff members did everything they could.
Ebola test negative for Dallas deputy:
An Ebola test was negative for a Dallas deputy who was hospitalized with possible symptoms of the deadly virus, officials said. The deputy, Sgt. Michael Monnig, didn't have any direct contact with Duncan but had reported contact with Duncan's family.
Physicians at Texas Health Presbyterian discharged him Thursday, soon after the negative test came back, hospital spokeswoman Candace White said.
New travel screening:
Five of America's biggest, busiest airports are beefing up measures. On Saturday, people arriving from the three nations hardest hit by Ebola started getting special screening, including having their temperature taken, at New York's JFK airport. Washington's Dulles, Newark, Chicago's O'Hare and Atlanta international airports will begin screening Thursday.
Ebola worries spread:
In New York, fire officials said a patient in Brooklyn with Ebola-like symptoms had recently returned from the North African country of Sudan, the New York Daily News reported.
The patient was undergoing tests, but the New York Health Department said there were no patients in the city suspected of having Ebola. The patient was "never at risk for Ebola and never met the definition of an Ebola suspect," the Health Department said.
Sudan is far removed from the West African center of the outbreak -- as far away from it as Atlanta is from Los Angeles. Still, fear of the often deadly disease has bred much caution.
"I have seen several people who had acute illnesses worried that they may have Ebola," said Dr. Mark Reiter, an emergency room physician in Tennessee and president of the American Academy of Emergency Medicine.
Reiter said many patients in his state are unlikely candidates, not having been to West Africa, nor having had any contact with a symptomatic Ebola patient.
"But it has gotten a tremendous amount of media coverage and some people are especially concerned about it, even if it is highly unlikely," Reiter said.
In Los Angeles, a patient who was isolated at Centinela Hospital's emergency room after being transported from Los Angeles International Airport earlier this week has undergone all necessary tests required by the CDC and Los Angeles County Department of Public Health. The patient was approved for discharge.
Linda Bradley, hospital CEO, said the patient, who had traveled recently from Liberia, underwent numerous tests, which came back negative.
Cuban doctors train, then fight Ebola in Africa
IN OTHER COUNTRIES
Spain Ebola patient has no significant change in condition:
Teresa Romero Ramos, a nurse's assistant in Spain who is the first person to contract Ebola outside Africa, "is conscious and talking" but was in "stable but serious" condition Saturday after taking a turn for the worse earlier in the week.
She has been treated with the anti-influenza drug Avigan, hospital sources with knowledge of the case said.
Spain ramps up response:
After Romero became the first person to contract Ebola outside Africa, 16 people related to the case were being monitored in a Madrid hospital, including an emergency room doctor, the neighborhood doctor who saw her before the case was confirmed, and the nurse's husband, according to a government source.
A special committee created by the Spanish government to tackle the Ebola crisis reported no significant changes in her condition. The committee, which will include representatives from government and health care, will coordinate national efforts to control the virus and establish protocols to deal with it, the source said.
A nurse under observation at the hospital tested negative for the Ebola virus, the committee said. The nurse has been discharged but will remain under observation outside the hospital until her quarantine ends on October 16, the committee said.
Sporadic infections unavoidable, the WHO says:
Sporadic Ebola infections will be unavoidable in some European countries because of direct travel from their hubs to hotspot areas in West Africa, the World Health Organization said Wednesday. But the risk of spread, it said, is avoidable and extremely low.
Australia scare:
A 57-year-old woman who returned to Australia after treating Ebola patients in Sierra Leone has been isolated at a hospital and is undergoing tests, including one for the deadly virus, authorities said. She had isolated herself at home and checked her temperature twice daily since her return, as recommended by national guidelines.
The Queensland Department of Health announced early Friday that initial tests on the woman came back negative for Ebola.
United Kingdom:
The UK's Heathrow and Gatwick airports and Eurostar railway terminals will begin screening passengers arriving from Ebola-affected Liberia, Sierra Leone and Guinea, a government spokesman said. Screening will involve assessing passengers' recent travel history, who they have been in contact with and future travel arrangements, as well as a possible assessment performed by medical personnel.
CNN's Steve Almasy, Joe Sutton, Ray Sanchez, Greg Botelho, Alexander Felton, Khushbu Shah, Saskya Vandoorne, Richard Quest, Brent Swails and Nima Elbagir contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Ebola fears sideline Guinea football star</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/sport/football/football-ebola-guinea-bangoura/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>Guinea star Alhassane (Lass) Bangoura withdraws from national squad
Bangoura cites fears of his Rayo Vallecano club teammates over Ebola
Guinea due to play against Ghana in Morocco
"I am fine" Bangoura says when asked about his health
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1652</time>
            </date>
            <author></author>
            <text>Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Guinea international Lass Bangoura pulled out of a key African Cup of Nations match against Ghana Saturday because his club teammates were worried he could contract Ebola.
Bangoura, who plays for Rayo Vallecano in Spain, told the La Liga side's official website that he had been told of their fears in a phone call while training for the Group E qualifier.
With Guinea one of the worst affected countries by the deadly virus, the international match had already been moved to the Moroccan city of Casablanca, but that apparently did not satisfy his fellow Rayo squad members.
"My teammates were afraid and at the end of practice I spoke with the (Guinea) coach Michel Dussuyer and said there was a problem, because of Ebola.
"I asked him if I could be excused because I didn't want any problems with the club, because they are the ones who pay my salary," he said.
Bangoura has now returned to his club, who are based in the Spanish capital Madrid where earlier this week a nurse became the first person in Europe to contract Ebola outside of West Africa.
She remains critically ill in hospital.
"My Rayo teammates welcomed me back," Bangoura said. "They have confidence in me, but what people need to understand is that when you are summoned for the national team, you have to see a doctor and get tested.
"Every national team has its own doctor who takes care of these issues. I am fine, there is no problem (with my health)," he added.
The 22-year-old Bangoura is a regular in the Rayo first team and has also established himself in his national squad.
He was concerned that his withdrawal could lead to problems for his family back home in Guinea.
"I just spoke to my mother, we have been talking. It is the first time I have left the national team and I am scared that there could be some crazy person who harms my family.
"This afternoon I'll be speaking on my country's radio to say I have no issue with the national team and to say I'm sorry."
The spread of the Ebola virus has had a serious impact on football in affected countries, with all competitive games stopped in Sierra Leona.
African Cup of Nations qualifiers involving its national team, Guinea and Liberia have also been relocated by the Confederation of African Football.

</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141010120628-bangoura-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>American emergency rooms prepare as Ebola fear spreads</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/health/ebola-crisis/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Nephew: Hospital gave Duncan inferior treatment because he was black
Emergency rooms in the United States are preparing for possible cases
Doctor: Some people are already coming into hospitals worrying they have Ebola
Spain's government sets up committee to probe the Ebola crisis there
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>25</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Jen Christensen and Mariano Castillo , CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Emergency rooms around the United States are preparing for the people who may have Ebola and for the people who just think they have Ebola.
"I have seen several people who had acute illnesses worried that they may have Ebola," said Dr. Mark Reiter.
He works as an emergency room doctor in Tennessee. He's also president of the American Academy of Emergency Medicine.
Reiter says these patients are unlikely candidates, not having been to West Africa, nor having had any contact with a symptomatic Ebola patient.
"But it has gotten a tremendous amount of media coverage and some people are especially concerned about it, even if it is highly unlikely," Reiter said.
Emergency rooms typically see a small uptick in traffic after a disease has been in the news a lot.
A 2010 study that looked at emergency room traffic when swine flu was in the news saw a 7% increase in emergency room visits.
Parents must also have been worried about their children catching it as pediatric visits increased 19.7%.
A recent Pew study showed 21% of respondents are somewhat worried about Ebola and their personal health.
Dr. Abdul Memon, the chief medical officer for disaster and emergency preparedness at Jackson Health System in Miami, said officials have not seen a significant patient increase with the Ebola scare. They do, however, get cases from time to time where people think they may have it. The hospital is careful, he said to rule it out.
"Our health department and the media does a really reasonable job of educating the community about how people get it," Memon said. "I think people are listening and we have not seen this rush of people."
"If someone has had contact with someone who has Ebola symptoms or they have been in one of these countries, we want them to come in if they feel sick, and we are ready for it. We will pay close attention" Memon said.
The number of deaths attributed to the current Ebola outbreak has topped 4,000, the World Health Organization reported Friday.
The latest count brings the total number of confirmed, probable, or suspected cases to 8,399 and the total deaths to 4,033.
The numbers were reported from Guinea, Liberia, Nigeria, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Spain and the United States.
Complete coverage on Ebola
But along with news of the rising death toll, some suspected Ebola cases around the world -- as fears spread across four continents -- have turned out to be false.
Concerns about protective measures, especially for those caring for the infected, remain high.
A total of 416 health care workers are among those believed to have contracted Ebola. Of those, 233 of have died, the WHO says.
'We just don't really know'
An American aid worker who contracted Ebola in Liberia and overcame the virus was said to have become infected while treating Ebola patients there, but she told CNN on Friday that there is no way to be sure.
Nancy Writebol was working with Samaritan's Purse in Liberia, caring for Ebola patients, when she became ill and was eventually transferred to an Atlanta hospital, where she recovered.
The belief has been that she contracted Ebola while working in a clinic with infected patients, but the survivor said that isn't necessarily the point of infection.
"Well, it's very possible that I contracted Ebola outside of the (medical) unit, not within," Writebol said. "Of course, I came in contact with people outside of our hospital, and I remember knowing and being with a gentleman one time that later died of Ebola. And it's possible that there was, you know, some contact there. We just don't really know."
Writebol was released from Emory University Hospital on August 19, once doctors determined she posed "no public health threat."
Her recovery has been gradual, Writebol said, but she is gaining strength each day.
How the Ebola virus spreads
The lack of clarity about where she became infected is significant as questions are raised worldwide about safety precautions at hospitals and communities as the outbreak stokes fears.
The sole person to be diagnosed with the virus on American soil, Thomas Eric Duncan, died this week, as new details of his hospitalization were revealed. He had traveled from Liberia last month.
Duncan first went to the hospital on September 25, but the hospital said he only had a "low grade fever and abdominal pain," and was released with some antibiotics and a pain reliever.
On Friday, Duncan's nephew Josephus Weeks told CNN that Duncan in fact had a 103-degree fever when he left the hospital, according to the discharge papers.
Talking to CNN's Erin Burnett on Friday night, Weeks alleged that the fact Duncan was black, poor and didn't have insurance affected his care.
"Had that been another or another color, he probably would be living today, he would have survived it," Weeks said. "And that's what's hurting me the most: ... They treated him the way they did because of the color of his skin... You stand a chance if you're white, but you don't if you're back."
While it hasn't responded to these latest allegations, Dallas' Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital did issue a statement Thursday explaining and defending its treatment of Duncan.
Why wasn't he immediately given an experimental drug? Because one wasn't available, the hospital explained.
Why didn't he get a blood transfusion, like other Ebola patients in the United States? Because "his blood type was not compatible with the serum donors."
And as to whether Duncan got inferior treatment because of his nationality or wealth, Texas Health Presbyterian said more than 50 people cared for him and a 24-bed intensive care unit was devoted to his care.
"Our care team provided Mr. Duncan with the same high level of attention and are that would be given any patient, regardless of nationality or ability to pay for care," the hospital said. "... We have a long history of treating a multicultural community in this area."
Suspected case comes back negative
On Thursday, a test to see whether a Dallas sheriff's deputy had Ebola came back negative, state health officials said.
Word of the test result was welcome news a day after the death of Duncan.
The deputy had reported being inside the Dallas apartment where Duncan had been staying and having "some contact" with Duncan's family members, Frisco Fire Chief Mark Piland told reporters.
Ebola spreads through infected bodily fluids.
The deputy, Michael Monnig, on Friday spoke about awaking after having been on duty at Duncan's apartment "feeling like a truck had hit me."
He identified them as flu-like symptoms, but following the guidance of the county doctor, he went to the clinic, and explained that he had been in the apartment.
"At that point, I knew all the bells and whistles would start up, but at that point, it was out of my control because I had answered yes to the question," he said.
He broke down crying when he learned he didn't have Ebola, Monnig said.
CDC director on Ebola: 'Only thing like this has been AIDS'
Spain creates a committee
In Spain, where a nurse's assistant was confirmed to have Ebola, authorities are taking measures to tackle the crisis.
The Spanish government will create a special committee to examine the issue, Deputy Prime Minister Soraya Saenz de Santamaria told reporters in Madrid.
The committee, which will include representatives from government and health care, will coordinate national efforts to control the virus and establish protocols to deal with it, she said.
The nurse's assistant, Teresa Romero, is the first person to contract Ebola outside of West Africa.
A nurses' union spokesman told CNN that "some nurses and other workers from the Carlos III Hospital (where Romero is being treated) are taking leave for psychological reasons."
To cover those jobs, the Spanish health service is "making short term contracts hiring nurses that might be unemployed."
Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy visited Carlos III Hospital.
"The situation isn't a normal situation," he said. "It is difficult, but I'm absolutely convinced that everything necessary will be done, especially from the professionals, to overcome this in the future."
CNN's Al Goodman, Elwyn Lopez, Jason Hanna, Catherine E. Shoichet, Greg Botelho and Ashley Fantz contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Ebola updates: Cameraman shows some improvement</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/health/ebola-up-to-speed/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>Spain creates a committee to tackle the Ebola crisis
Spokesman: US Airways followed CDC guidelines after health scare on Dominican flight
After negative test, Texas sheriff's deputy is discharged
Hotel closed in Macedonia after sudden death, ministry says
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2025</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Faith Karimi and Ashley Fantz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The family of NBC cameraman Ashoka Mukpo, who contracted Ebola while working in Liberia, is cautiously optimistic after doctors said that his condition at a Nebraska hospital has improved slightly.
With developments pouring in from all corners of the world, here's what you need to know to quickly get caught up:
WEST AFRICA
No relief in sight:
The number of deaths attributed to the current Ebola outbreak has climbed to 4,033, the World Health Organization reported Friday. The tally brings the total number of confirmed, probable and suspected cases of Ebola to 8,399. The numbers were reported from Guinea, Liberia, Nigeria, Senegal, Sierra Leone, Spain and the United States.
A possible $32 billion hit:
The outbreak could cost the African economy $32 billion over the next two years if it spreads to its larger neighbors, the World Bank estimates.
The steps some countries have taken to prevent the spread of the Ebola virus amount to "putting a towel under the door of a building on fire," World Bank president Jim Kim told CNN's Richard Quest on Thursday.
Complete coverage on Ebola
Liberia postpones election:
Liberia's President on Thursday postponed a senatorial election that had been set for next week, citing the Ebola outbreak in the country.
The nation's election commission had recommended the delay, saying that the prevalence of the virus, authorities' efforts to combat it and citizens' efforts to isolate themselves weren't conducive to a free and open election.
Officials have not yet revealed any new date for the election, which had been set for Tuesday.
U.S. troops arrive in Liberia:
A group of 90 U.S. Marines and airmen arrived in Liberia on Thursday to help Ebola response efforts, along with four V-22 Osprey aircraft and two C-130 transport planes.
Their arrival brings the total number of U.S. troops deployed in Liberia to 334, military spokesman Lt. Col. Dave Doherty said. And there are more coming. In late October, 700 troops from the 101st Airborne Division are scheduled to deploy to Liberia.
U.S. CASES
'Modest improvement' for NBC cameraman
The condition of Ashoka Mukpo, the American citizen who got infected in Liberia, has shown "very modest improvement," according to The Nebraska Medical Center, where he is being treated.
Mukpo, a cameraman for NBC, is receiving an experimental drug called brincidofovir, or CMX001.
"Mr. Mukpo's condition is slightly improved," medical director Dr. Phil Smith said. "He's been taking in some fluids and drinking Gatorade. But everyone needs to be reminded that this is still a very serious illness we're dealing with and no one has a lot of experience treating it."
Thomas Duncan dies:
Thomas Eric Duncan, the first person diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died Wednesday, 10 days after he was admitted to Dallas' Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital. His family wonders whether the outcome would have been different if doctors had admitted Duncan to a hospital on September 25, the first time he showed up with a fever and stomach pain.
Duncan's family has criticized the care he received. The Dallas hospital that treated him says staff members did everything they could.
Ebola test negative for Dallas deputy:
An Ebola test was negative for a Dallas deputy who was hospitalized with possible symptoms of the deadly virus, officials said. The deputy, Sgt. Michael Monnig, didn't have any direct contact with Duncan but had reported contact with Duncan's family.
Physicians at Texas Health Presbyterian discharged him Thursday, soon after the negative test came back, hospital spokeswoman Candace White said.
New travel screening:
Five of America's biggest, busiest airports are beefing up measures. Now, people arriving from the three nations hardest hit by Ebola will get special screening, including having their temperature taken. The airports are: New York's JFK, Washington Dulles, Newark, Chicago O'Hare and Atlanta international airports.
IN OTHER COUNTRIES
Spain to create a committee to fight Ebola:
The Spanish government will create a special committee to tackle the Ebola crisis, Deputy Prime Minister Soraya Saenz de Santamaria told reporters Friday in Madrid. The committee, which will include representatives from government and health care, will coordinate national efforts to control the virus and establish protocols to deal with it, she said.
Spain ramps up response:
After a nurse's assistant in Spain became the first person to contract Ebola outside Africa, five people related to the case were being monitored in a Madrid hospital, including her husband, an emergency room doctor and the neighborhood doctor who saw her before the case was confirmed.
Sporadic infections unavoidable, the WHO says:
Sporadic Ebola infections will be unavoidable in some European countries because of direct travel from their hubs to hotspot areas in West Africa, the World Health Organization said Wednesday. But the risk of spread, it said, is avoidable and extremely low.
Australia scare:
A 57-year-old woman who returned to Australia after treating Ebola patients in Sierra Leone has been isolated at a hospital and is undergoing tests, including one for the deadly virus, authorities said. She had isolated herself at home and checked her temperature twice daily since her return, as recommended by national guidelines.
The Queensland Department of Health announced early Friday that initial tests on the woman came back negative for Ebola.
United Kingdom:
The UK's Heathrow and Gatwick airports and Eurostar railway terminals will begin screening passengers arriving from Ebola-affected Liberia, Sierra Leone and Guinea, a government spokesman said. Screening will involve assessing passengers' recent travel history, who they have been in contact with and future travel arrangements, as well as a possible assessment performed by medical personnel.
CNN's Greg Botelho, Alexander Felton, Khushbu Shah, Saskya Vandoorne, Richard Quest, Brent Swails and Nima Elbagir contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Kenyan President Uhuru Kenyatta at ICC over charges linked to 2007 violence</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/08/world/africa/kenya-icc-status-hearing/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>Kenyatta is the first sitting President to appear before the ICC
He says he is attending the hearing as a private citizen
He has been accused of five counts of crimes against humanity for his alleged role in a disputed 2007 election
The Kenyan leader has pleaded not guilty
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>8</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1237</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Faith Karimi, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Kenyan President Uhuru Kenyatta on Wednesday became the first sitting head of state to appear before the International Criminal Court, where he faces charges of crimes against humanity.
Kenyatta, 52, is accused of five counts of crimes against humanity for allegedly orchestrating violence after a disputed presidential election in 2007.
Shortly before he left for the Netherlands, he appointed his deputy president to serve as acting President, saying he is attending the hearing at The Hague as a private citizen.
More than 1,000 people died and hundreds of thousands were displaced when ethnic groups loyal to leading candidates torched homes and hacked rivals in violence that raged until early 2008.
Kenyatta, who backed then-incumbent Mwai Kibaki in that election, is accused of funding a local militia that conducted reprisal attacks.
The second day of the status hearing will determine whether his case can proceed to trial. The first day was held Tuesday, but he was not required to attend. The court mandated that he be present on the last day.
During the hearing Tuesday, the prosecution accused the Kenyan government of not providing key documents in the case against its leader. The defense denied the allegation.
Kenya is the second African nation after Sudan to have a sitting president face charges at the International Criminal Court.
But Sudanese President Omar al-Bashir does not cooperate with the court, and has rejected ICC warrants for his arrest for alleged war crimes in Darfur.
Lack of evidence
"My conscience is clear, has been clear, and will remain forever clear that I am innocent of all the accusations leveled against me," Kenyatta said before he boarded the plane in Nairobi.
The ICC prosecutor has postponed the start of the trial numerous times, citing lack of evidence. The prosecution has suffered a series of setbacks, with witnesses withdrawing and others admitting to lying.
"In ordinary circumstances, the insufficiency of evidence would cause the prosecution to withdraw the charges," the ICC said in September.
"However, it would be inappropriate for the prosecution to withdraw the charges at this stage in light of the government of Kenya continuing failure to cooperate fully with the court's requests for assistance in this case."
This is the first time Kenyatta is attending a hearing in person since he assumed office in April last year.
Deputy president also facing charges
The ICC has also accused Deputy President William Ruto of orchestrating attacks. His trial started in September 2013.
Both leaders have denied any links to the violence among their respective ethnic groups, and have said they will cooperate with the court to clear their names.
ICC withdrawal?
The International Criminal Court was set up in 2002 to prosecute genocide, crimes against humanity and war crimes.
The Parliament of Kenya voted in September to withdraw from ICC jurisdiction after repeatedly calling on the court to drop the cases. But a withdrawal would take a while to implement because it involves steps such as a formal notification to the United Nations. The ICC has said the trials will proceed.
The nation's previous administration reneged on a deal to set up a special tribunal to try suspects in the post-election violence, prompting the international court to step in.
African Union accuses ICC of bias, seeks delay of cases against sitting leaders

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Dallas sheriff's deputy discharged after Ebola test comes back negative</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/health/ebola-crisis/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>Wife to WFAA: "It's just been blown out of proportion"
Sgt. Michael Monnig reported having contact with Ebola patient's family
The Texas deputy's Ebola test results are negative
Hospital official: Doctors discharged him
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1754</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Catherine E. Shoichet and Ashley Fantz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A test to see whether a Dallas sheriff's deputy has Ebola came back negative, state health officials said Thursday.
Tests of a specimen from Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Dallas, where he was treated, were negative for the deadly virus, the Texas Department of State Health Services said.
"The professionals at Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital Dallas are relieved for Deputy Michael Monnig's family and friends that the blood test has been returned quickly and was negative for Ebola," the hospital said in a statement.
A short time later, hospital spokeswoman Candace White said that physicians had discharged Monnig.
"The family has asked for privacy at this time," White added.
Six ways Duncan's case differs from other U.S. Ebola cases
Word of the test result is welcome news a day after the death of Thomas Eric Duncan, the Texas Ebola patient who was the first person diagnosed with the virus on American soil.
The deputy had reported being inside the Dallas apartment where Duncan had been staying and having "some contact" with Duncan's family members, Frisco Fire Chief Mark Piland told reporters.
Ebola spreads through infected bodily fluids.
Health officials earlier had said there was little chance Monnig had Ebola because he never had direct contact with Duncan and didn't have a fever.
"The risk is extremely low because this individual didn't have contact with the Ebola patient, but we want to err on the side of caution," said Dr. David Lakey, Texas health commissioner. "We understand there's a lot of anxiety in the community, and we hope getting test results back will help calm those fears."
Spanish Ebola patient's condition worsens, doctor says
Monnig was at Duncan's apartment on October 1, accompanying county health officials who were issuing an order temporarily forbidding the apartment's occupants to leave the unit, CNN affiliate WFAA reported. The visit happened three days after Duncan was admitted to the Dallas hospital.
Monnig woke up Wednesday feeling sore and fatigued and with a stomachache.
"With the situation, what's happened, he just decided it would be better to be safe than sorry," Logan Monnig told KTVT.
The deputy went to get checked out at a CareNow clinic for help with his stomach pain.
It wasn't long before he called his wife with a startling report, WFAA reported.
"His exacts words were, 'I'm at CareNow, and all hell's about to break loose,' " Lisa Monnig told WFAA. "And I said, 'Why?' And he said, 'I hear helicopters overhead.' "
One early report from officials about the case described the possibility of a second Ebola patient who'd been in direct contact with Duncan. Another said he'd been to West Africa. Neither turned out to be true.
Complete coverage on Ebola
Soon, Monnig was in ambulance on the way to the same hospital that cared for Duncan.
There, he was placed into isolation, WFAA said, and his family wasn't allowed to see him.
"I understand that there's procedures and protocols that need to be followed. I just think with all the media attention, it's just been blown out of proportion," his wife told WFAA.
The real diagnosis?
His wife told WFAA he has an upper respiratory virus.
Read more about changes at airports
CNN's Matthew Stucker and Elizabeth Cohen contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Hospital worker: Spaniard exposed in ER for 8 hours after positive Ebola test</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/08/world/europe/ebola-spain/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>A nurse's assistant got infected while caring for an Ebola patient in Madrid
Spokeswoman: This woman sought treatment twice, got sent home both times
She was admitted to hospital a third time; waited hours for transfer, worker says
5 are with her in a hospital; dozens of others are being monitored for Ebola
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>9</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>153</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Greg Botelho, Laura Smith-Spark and Laura Perez Maestro, CNN</author>
            <text>Madrid (CNN) -- Teresa Romero Ramos sought out help three times.
Finally, one week after first seeing a doctor, Romero found out why she felt so sick: She had Ebola.
Even after her Ebola test came back positive at Madrid's Alcorcon hospital, Romero had to wait.
According to a worker at that hospital, Romero lay in the emergency room -- exposed to other patients as well as medical staff, going back and forth -- for eight hours before being transferred to a hospital in the Spanish capital that specializes in infectious diseases.
While Romero was "doing better" Wednesday, according to a regional health spokesman said Wednesday, parts of Spain's medical establishment is looking worse and worse the more that comes out about what she's gone through from how she contracted Ebola to how her case has been handled.
Her plight can also be compared to that of Thomas Eric Duncan, the Liberian citizen who was sent home from a Dallas, Texas, hospital days before eventually being admitted for Ebola. Duncan, the first person diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died on Wednesday.
Speaking about what's unfolding in Madrid, Health Minister Ana Mato told Parliament that Spain is going to revise its protocols for handling Ebola.
Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy also said that his country is "facing a matter that is of international concern." But that doesn't mean Spaniards should hunker down or become overly alarmed, urging them to "keep calm."
"I would like to ask you to allow the health workers to work," he said. "The Spanish health system is one of the best in the world."
1st person to contract Ebola outside Africa
The Ebola virus has been voracious, infecting more than 8,000 people and killing at least 3,800, according to the World Health Organization. It's also been largely confined, with every person catching the disease in West Africa.
Deadliest Ebola outbreak: What you need to know
Until Romero.
She is the first person to contract the deadly virus outside Africa. Dr. German Ramirez, who is among those treating her, said the nurse's assistant at Madrid's Carlos III hospital may have been exposed while removing protective gear she'd donned to treat a Spanish missionary infected with Ebola in West Africa.
"That's what we were working on -- on the errors possibly made while removing the protective suit," Ramirez told reporters, saying it's possible the protective suit or gloves may have touched her face.
Angry doctors and nurses outside Carlos III Hospital said Tuesday they were outraged that two missionaries -- Miguel Pajares and Manuel Garcia Viejo, were almost dead when they arrived -- had been brought to the hospital. Both priests ended up dying at the Madrid hospital.
How did Spanish nurse catch Ebola?
That Romero may have gotten Ebola while doing her job is a major cause of concern, especially if she did -- as she told Spanish newspaper El Mundo -- follow the necessary protocols while caring for the missionary.
So, too, is how her treatment was handled afterward.
According to a Carlos III hospital spokeswoman, who isn't named as is customary in Spain, Romero started feeling ill on September 29. She went the next day to her doctor, who did not properly identify her problem and sent her home.
But Romero didn't get better. She called Carlos III hospital on October 2 and was directed, per protocol, to an external medical department under the umbrella of Madrid's regional health service, the hospital spokesman.
Romero ended back home again. On Monday, she ended up calling an ambulance, which took her to Alcorcon hospital.
It was there, on Tuesday, that Romero got tested for Ebola. The positive result came back two hours later, according to an Alcorcon doctor.
Yet it wasn't until eight hours later, a worker at the same hospital said, when she was transported to the hospital where she worked, Carlos III.
Dog of nursing assistant put down
As she battles the deadly virus, Romero has company.
Five others related to her case were also at Carlos III hospital as of late Wednesday, including two doctors and a male nurse admitted earlier in the day, Carlos III hospital said in a press release.
The nurse's assistant is the only one confirmed to have Ebola. Besides the three new cases, the others include the woman's husband, judged to be at high risk of infection, and a nurse from the same hospital. Two others were released from Carlos III hospital earlier in the today -- a Spanish man who'd recently come from Nigeria and a female nurse.
Others are being tracked from afar.
Authorities said Tuesday that a total of 30 people from Carlos III Hospital and 22 others -- from the Alcorcon hospital where the woman first sought care, plus family members -- are being monitored.
Already, there's one victim in this case: Romero and her husband's dog, Excalibur.
It's not known if Ebola can be passed through canines. The WHO has said, though, that it's infected chimpanzees, gorillas, fruit bats, monkeys, forest antelope and porcupines. Yet human infections, to date, have not been linked to dogs.
Nonetheless, health authorities felt they had to take action in case Excalibur had the disease.
About 400,000 people signed an online petition to save the dog from being killed, contending that that "it would be much easier to isolate or quarantine the dog just as they have the victim's husband," rather than forcing the couple to lose "one of the family."
But this push was for naught, as Madrid health authorities put down the dog Wednesday.
'Save Excalibur' campaign fails
CNN's Greg Botelho reported and wrote from Atlanta, Laura Smith-Spark from London and Laura Perez Maestro from Madrid. CNN's Isa Soares, Al Goodman, Elwyn Lopez, Lindsay Isaac, Erin McLaughlin, Alex Felton and Pierre Meilhan contributed to this report, as did journalist Nuri Saani in Liberia.
</text>
        </news>
        <news/>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-asia">
        <news>
            <title>Chinese court sentences cult members to death over McDonald's killing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/asia/china-eastern-lightning-death-sentence/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>Five members of a Chinese cult have been sentenced for a murder in a McDonald's
Two were sentenced to death for the killing of a woman who refused to give them her number
The group, Church of Almighty God, has been banned in China since 1995
Its members believe Jesus has been reincarnated as a Chinese woman
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>809</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Two members of a banned Chinese doomsday cult were sentenced to death Saturday for the brutal murder of a woman in a McDonald's restaurant in May, Chinese state media reported.
Zhang Fan and Zhang Lidong were among five members of the Church of Almighty God, or "Quannengshen," tried on murder charges in August over the killing in Zhaoyuan, Shandong Province, the state-run Xinhua agency reported.
Three fellow cult members, Lyu Yingchun, Zhang Hang and Zhang Qiaolian, were sentenced to life, 10 and seven years in prison respectively for their roles in the attack. The four Zhangs were related, according to the report.
A court statement said the victim, a 37-year-old woman named Wu Shuoyan, was attacked after refusing to give her phone number to the group, who were allegedly attempting to recruit new members.
Zhang Fan and Lyu called her an "evil spirit," before Zhang bludgeoned her head with a chair, then jumped on her and trampled her head, the statement said.
Zhang Lidong bashed the victim's head with a mop hard enough to break it, and stomped on her face and head, while Lyu kicked her waist and prevented McDonald's staff from intervening, the court statement said.
IN DEPTH: 'Eastern Lightning,' the banned religious group that has China worried
Linked to kidnappings, violence and extortion, the Church of Almighty God has been on a list of 14 banned religious groups issued by China's Ministry of Public Security since 1995.
Founded in the 1990s in Henan Province, the group believes that Jesus has been reincarnated as Yang Xiangbin, the wife of the group's founder, Zhao Weishan. The couple fled to the United States in 2000, Xinhua reported.
The group, also known as Eastern Lightning ("Dongfang Shandian"), preaches that the righteous are engaged in an apocalyptic struggle against China's Communist Party -- which it refers to as the "great red dragon."
Belonging to a tradition of heterodox, quasi-Christian Chinese religious movements, the cult was estimated as having between several hundred thousand and one million members, according to Emily Dunn, an Asian studies academic at the University of Melbourne who wrote her doctoral thesis on the group.
In August, Chinese state media reported that police had arrested nearly 1,000 suspected members of the group, including nearly 100 "backbone members."
The report said those arrested were responsible for "numerous" suicides and murders, including those of their own family.
In 2012, hundreds of members were rounded up after the group publicly proclaimed the end of the world was imminent.
In a statement provided to CNN in June, Hong Kong-based members of the group responsible for its English-language website said it was "very natural" for the Chinese Communist Party to blame the group for the McDonald's death because the party slandered and then suppressed those that disagreed with it.
"They always find some excuse in advance and fabricate things and slander them," said the statement.
READ MORE: The future of Christianity in China
CNN's Dayu Zhang and Katie Hunt contributed to this report.
</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140604013136-eastern-lightning-split-story-top.png</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>6 die as Cyclone Hudhud uproots trees and light poles in India</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/india-cyclone/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>More than 200,000 people have been evacuated
The cyclone comes in on top of high tide, which could mean a higher storm surge
Hudhud has the strength of a category 3 hurricane
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1634</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Harmeet Shah Singh, CNN</author>
            <text>New Delhi (CNN) -- Six people have died in Cyclone Hudhud on Sunday, Indian authorities said. The storm, which made landfall on India's eastern coast, has also uprooted trees and utility poles.
When the storm blew ashore, the coast was nearly emptied out. More than 200,000 people were evacuated a day before, officials said.
India's science and technology minister, Jitendra Singh, described the cyclone as "very severe."
Hudhud's sustained winds of 205 kilometers per hour (127 miles per hour) made it a category 3 storm at landfall, CNN meteorologist Derrick Van Dam. Gusts rose to 250 kmh (155 mph).
The storm rode in at high tide, which could result in surge as high as 2 meters (7 feet).
At least 100,000 residents from four districts of the state of Andhra Pradesh were moved to safer locations, such as schools and other structurally strong buildings, authorities said.
In neighboring Odisha state, another 100,000 people have also been evacuated, according to a senior emergency official.
The Indian military has mobilized its resources to areas vulnerable to Hudhud, defense officials said.
In New Delhi, Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi was briefed about the government's plans to prepare for and recover from the surging storm.
CNN's Joshua Berlinger contributed to this report
</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141012090302-india-cyclone-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Powerful storms hitting Asia</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/weather/2014/10/12/nr-derek-van-dam-storms-hit-asia.cnn.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>Cyclone Hudhud hits India while Japan gets soaked by Typhoon Vongfong. Derek Van Dam reports.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Powerful storms hitting Asia</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/weather/2014/10/12/nr-derek-van-dam-storms-hit-asia.cnn.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>Cyclone Hudhud hits India while Japan gets soaked by Typhoon Vongfong. Derek Van Dam reports.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Vongfong slams into Kyushu, continues destructive path across Japan</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/tropical-storm-vongfong-japan/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>Tropical Storm Vongfong hits Kyushu, the southernmost of Japan's four main islands
At least 36 injuries have been reported
Japan's four main islands are expected to get up to 40cm of rain
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1408</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Junko Ogura and Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>Tokyo (CNN) -- The latest and strongest in a string of powerful storms to hit Japan -- Vongfong -- slammed into Kyushu, the southernmost of the country's four main islands, Monday morning as it continued its destructive path across the country.
Vongfong first made landfall in Japan in Okinawa early Sunday. It wreaked havoc across the prefecture, knocking out power before losing strength and being downgraded from a typhoon to a tropical storm.
Meteorologists expect the storm to pass over the country's largest island, Honshu, hitting the capital, Tokyo, before dawn on Tuesday.
At least 36 injuries related to the storm were reported across Okinawa, Kagoshima and Miyazaki prefectures, officials said, while at least 44,000 across the country were without power.
Authorities have ordered more than 100,000 people to evacuate their homes.
Police in Shizuoka said one man remained missing after three people were swept into water on Sunday at the city's port.
Although a high-wave advisory had been issued at the time of the accident, the incident was classified as a water accident and not officially linked to the storm, according to Shizuoka police.
Flights in and out of Kyushu and neighboring Shikoku were canceled Monday, along with local ferry and train operations.
The Japan Meteorological Agency said Vongfong was expected to bring up to 40 centimeters of rain.
The storm comes on the heels of Typhoon Phanfone, which swept over southern Japan last week, washing three U.S. airmen out to sea off Okinawa.
U.S. and Japanese search crews found the last airman's body on Wednesday, according to a news release issued by authorities at Kadena.
Japan was previously saturated by storms Halong, Neoguri and Nakri.
CNN's Tom Sater contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Pakistani airstrikes kill at least 21 militants</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/pakistan-militants-killed/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>One strike kills 10 and another kills 11 in remote villages in North Waziristan
Strikes target militant hideouts in volatile tribal area
Militants targeted were members of the Pakistan Taliban, sources say
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1606</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Zahir Shah Sherazi and Chandrika Narayan, CNN</author>
            <text>Peshawar, Pakistan (CNN) -- At least 21 militants were killed in Pakistani airstrikes Sunday in a volatile area close to the Afghan border, officials said.
Ten militants died as jets targeted their hideouts in the Khyber tribal district, Pakistan's Inter Services Public Relations reported. The strikes demolished four hideouts, officials said.
Separate strikes killed 11 militants and destroyed two terrorist hideouts in another remote village in North Waziristan, sources said.
Drone strikes kill 8 in Afghanistan, Pakistan
North Waziristan is a Pakistan Taliban stronghold in the country's loosely governed tribal areas bordering Afghanistan. The area is dangerous and hard for journalists to reach, making it difficult to independently verify the military account.
Military and local sources on the ground said the militants were affiliated with the Pakistan Taliban.
Militants from Tehreek-e-Taliban, or TTP, have long conducted an insurgency against the Pakistani government and have claimed a number of violent attacks. Early this year, the government suspended peace talks with the group.
Pakistan's northwestern region is home to loosely governed tribal areas. It's also a base for foreign fighters and a refuge for members of the militant Haqqani network, an insurgent force affiliated with the Taliban and al Qaeda.
Zahir Shah Sherazi reported from Peshawar, Pakistan, and Chandrika Narayan wrote in Atlanta.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>North and South Korea exchange fire</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/world/asia/koreas-fire-exchange/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>North, South Korea exchange fire after North opens up on balloons with anti-aircraft guns
The balloons carried leaflets critical of the North, South Korean Defense Ministry says
The exchange comes amid continuing speculation over the fate of the North's missing leader
North Korea has also made some diplomatic overtures in recent days
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1508</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Michael Pearson, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- North and South Korea exchanged fire Friday after gunners in the North targeted balloons carrying leaflets critical of the country's reclusive regime, the South Korean Defense Ministry said.
North Korean gunners fired anti-aircraft rounds at the balloons for 20 minutes, and some of the shots landed on South Korean soil, the ministry said. After a warning, South Korea responded with a 40 rounds from a heavy machine gun, the ministry said.
South Korean activists released the balloons filled with fliers critical of the North on Monday, the Defense Ministry said.
The exchange is the latest in a series of similar incidents between the two countries, the most recent of which came Tuesday, when patrol boats from North Korea and South Korea exchanged fire in the Yellow Sea, according to the South Korean Defense Ministry.
It also comes amid tentative diplomatic overtures by North Korea and continuing intrigue over the status of the country's leader, Kim Jung Un, who has not been seen publicly for more than a month.
Kim Jong Un misses shrine visit
A North Korean official said last week that the country was ready to resume negotiations over the country's nuclear efforts with Russia, the United States, China, Japan and South Korea.
High-ranking Pyongyang officials also visited South Korea on Saturday, saying the North was willing to hold a new round of diplomatic talks between the two countries.
North Korea has also reached out to the European Union. Ri Tong Il, the North Korean deputy ambassador to the United Nations, said Tuesday that North Korea and the European Union would hold human rights talks at the end of the year.
Why has North Korea decided to talk now?
Kim's disappearance from public view has also stoked discussion about who is leading the country and what's next.
He missed a ceremony Friday in honor of his late father and grandfather on the 69th anniversary of one of the most powerful institutions in North Korean life, the Workers' Party of North Korea.
Kim, 31, who first appeared as the North's top leader in 2010, has not been seen publicly since September 3, according to NK News.
Is Kim Jong Un's sister in charge?
CNN's Christine Theodorou, K.J. Kwon and Ben Brumfield contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Drone strikes kill 8 in Afghanistan, Pakistan, sources say</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/world/asia/pakistan-afghanistan-drone-strikes/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>One strike kills four militants in Afghanistan, near Pakistan border, Pakistani officials say
Another four militants killed in northwestern Pakistan, sources say
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1807</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Zahir Shah Sherazi and Jason Hanna, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Two suspected U.S. drone strikes in in the Pakistan-Afghanistan border region have killed at least eight militants, Pakistani officials said Saturday.
One strike targeted a hideout in eastern Afghanistan, near Pakistan's Khyber Agency, which is part of Pakistan's loosely governed tribal areas, the officials said on condition of anonymity. That strike killed at least four militants and injured many others, the source said.
In the other incident, missiles hit a vehicle in Pakistan's North Waziristan -- another tribal area that borders Afghanistan -- killing four militants, including a commander, according to Pakistani intelligence sources.
It wasn't immediately clear when the attacks happened. The sources didn't say which group or groups the militants represented.
The tribal areas in northwestern Pakistan have long been a base for anti-government militants, including those with the Islamist Haqqani movement.
The United States routinely does not comment on suspected drone strikes.

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un misses shrine visit, KCNA reports</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/world/asia/kim-jong-un-north-korea/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: U.S. officials downplay Kim's absence at Friday tribute
Kim's name is missing from a list of attendees at a shrine visit
The North Korean leader was expected to attend the annual ceremony at his father's shrine
Kim hasn't been seen in weeks; he'd been expected to attend Workers' Party ceremonies
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2202</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Madison Park, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The mystery of Kim Jong Un's whereabouts deepened Friday after the North Korean leader appeared to have missed a ceremony to pay tribute to his late father and grandfather on what is an important national anniversary.
Kim's name was absent from the list of attendees at the Kumsusan Palace of the Sun in Pyongyang on the 69th anniversary of the Workers' Party of North Korea, issued by state news agency KCNA on Friday.
The Workers' Party, founded in 1945, is North Korea's political party and is considered one of the country's most crucial institutions alongside the military.
According to KCNA, flowers were presented at the shrine in Kim's name, but the most senior official to attend was Hwang Pyong So, North Korea's second most important leader, who recently attended the closing ceremony of the 17th Asian Games in South Korea.
Kim hasn't been seen in public since he reportedly attended a concert with his wife on September 3. It's his longest absence from official events since he made his first public appearance in 2010, said NK News, a website devoted to analyzing North Korea.
Analysts are puzzled and speculation is running rampant about why Kim has been out of the public eye.
State media attempted to explain his absence by saying Kim was experiencing "discomfort."
He had been seen hobbling earlier in the summer, prompting theories ranging from weight gain to gout. There have also been questions about the possible meaning behind his absence: Is he genuinely sick, or are there machinations within the North Korean power circle?
Is Kim Jong Un's sister in charge?
North Korea as Rorschach test
"Whenever someone doesn't show up in the public, we tend to speculate something of a power struggle," said Han Park, author of "North Korea Demystified."
Because not much is known about North Korea's internal politics, observers scrutinize public functions and ceremonies to see who appears and who does not.
"We're always operating on this incomplete info," said Joshua Stanton, a North Korea observer who created the website One Free Korea, which is critical of the regime.
Drawing conclusions about what's happening in North Korea has been likened to a Rorschach test -- it's a reflection of the views of whoever is drawing the conclusions, rather than an informed analysis based on facts. And the facts in the reclusive country are murky at best.
"People have a tendency to see the things they want to see," Stanton said. "We should default to skepticism."
Opinion: Why Kim is probably still in charge
South Korean official: Kim probably near hospital
South Korea's defense minister told reporters in Seoul on Friday that he "has reason to believe that Kim Jong Un is probably staying in one of his homes" near an exclusive hospital in North Korea's capital, Pyongyang, with his wife and sister.
The facility named by the official, Bongwha hospital, is known to be an exclusive facility catering to high-ranking members of North Korea's ruling party.
It wasn't immediately clear why the defense minister said he thought Kim was staying near the hospital.
U.S. officials downplay Kim's absence
Senior officials in U.S. President Barack Obama's administration said Friday they believe there's no indication that Kim has been sidelined or is in very bad health.
While they acknowledge there is little information available, the officials, speaking on condition of anonymity, said Kim is believed to have non-life-threatening medical problems, citing the limping seen this summer.
"He is overweight, smokes and drinks heavily and doesn't do any exercise," one senior U.S. official said. "He can't be in good shape, but there is no indication of serious trouble in terms of health or stability."
With Kim out of sight, North Korean top brass visit South
The sources downplayed Kim's absence at Friday's tribute and said there was nothing to substantiate speculation that other members of the regime had marginalized him.
"We don't believe fundamentally there is anything afoot," a second senior U.S. official said. "There is nothing affecting our policy choices in any way."
The officials noted that previous North Korean leaders Kim Il Sung and Kim Jong Il disappeared for long stretches of time, only to re-emerge and cast aside rumors about their leadership.
"It's a dictatorship," the second U.S. official said "But it gets them attention and makes the ultimate big reveal that much more newsworthy."
North Korea's diplomacy efforts
With its top leader missing in action, North Korea has extended its diplomatic efforts with the outside world.
One of its officials said the regime was ready to restart the six-party nuclear talks, which include Russia, the United States, China, Japan and South Korea. It has also reached out to the European Union and South Korea.
High-ranking Pyongyang officials visited South Korea on Saturday, but just days later, the two countries were exchanging fire at a disputed maritime demarcation line.
North and South Korea exchange fire
The mixed messages reflect Pyongyang's "state of constant and ever-shifting cost-benefit calculation to maximize its national self interests," said Jasper Kim, founder of the Asia-Pacific Global Research Group.
"Every move North Korea makes is a negotiation attempt to see which states will accede and offer something of value in exchange for some level of stability. This has and always will be North Korea's dominant negotiation strategy."
Longest absence
Kim made only one official appearance in September. This has happened only once before, in September 2010, and that was the month in which Kim made his first official public appearance alongside his father at Kumsusan Palace of the Sun, NK News said.
Before this absence, his longest disappearance from public view as Supreme Leader was a 24-day period between June 7 and July 1, 2012. His second longest absence ever was for 29 days between July 28 and August 27, 2011 -- while his father was still alive, NK News said.
Kim's sole public appearance in September was at a Moranbong Band concert at Pyongyang's Mansudae Art Theatre, reported by state media on September 4. He was accompanied by his wife, Ri Sol Ju, his sister Kim Yo Jong and several top officials including Hwang Pyong So.
CNN's Elise Labott, Paula Hancocks, KJ Kwon, Michael Martinez, Brian Todd and Dugald McConnell and journalist Jung-eun Kim contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Still no sign of Kim Jong Un</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/world/2014/10/10/nr-hancocks-kim-jong-un.cnn.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>North Korean's ruling party is celebrating its 69th anniversary, but where is Kim Jong Un? Speculation mounts.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Still no sign of Kim Jong Un</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/world/2014/10/10/nr-hancocks-kim-jong-un.cnn.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>North Korean's ruling party is celebrating its 69th anniversary, but where is Kim Jong Un? Speculation mounts.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Malala Yousafzai and Kailash Satyarthi share Nobel Peace Prize</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/world/europe/nobel-peace-prize/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>Pakistan's Malala Yousafzai: Children around the world "should stand up for their rights"
India's Prime Minister congratulates winners for determination and courage
Pakistani PM Nawaz Sharif says Yousafzai has "made her countrymen proud"
India's Kailash Satyarthi says award honors everyone working for child rights
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1925</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The Nobel Peace Prize was awarded Friday to India's Kailash Satyarthi and Pakistan's Malala Yousafzai for their struggles against the suppression of children and for young people's rights, including the right to education.
Thorbjorn Jagland, chairman of the Norwegian Nobel Committee, said, "Children must go to school, not be financially exploited."
Yousafzai came to global attention after she was shot in the head by the Taliban -- two years ago Thursday -- for her efforts to promote education for girls in Pakistan. Since then, after recovering from surgery, she has taken her campaign to the world stage, notably with a speech last year at the United Nations.
Through her heroic struggle, Yousafzai has become a leading spokeswoman for girls' rights to education, said Jagland.
According to the Nobel committee, at 17 she's the youngest ever peace prize winner.
Yousafzai said that the award is a "great honor for me," and that she's honored to share it with Satyarthi.
"I'm proud that I'm the first Pakistani and the first young woman or the first young person getting this award," she said in Birmingham, England.
Yousafzai learned she won the award while she was in chemistry class in England on Friday morning, she said. She wasn't expecting to get the award, and at 10:15 a.m., she was sure she hadn't won. But soon afterward, a teacher called her over and told her she had.
Yousafzai said she continued to attend classes, and it was a "normal day," besides teachers and fellow students congratulating her.
She said she doesn't believe that she deserved the award but considers it an encouragement to continue her campaign and "to know that I'm not alone," Yousafzai told reporters.
New beginnings
Her award will not mark the end of her campaign to advocate for girls' education, she said.
"I think this is really the beginning," she said, adding that children around the world "should stand up for their rights" and "not wait for someone else."
Yousafzai spoke with Satyarthi by phone Friday, and they agreed to work together to advocate that every child is able to go to school. She said they also decided to try to build a stronger relationship between their countries, which are longtime rivals.
She said she wants the Prime Ministers of India and Pakistan to attend the December ceremony where she and Satyarthi will receive their awards. Peace between the two nations, Yousafzai said, is important for their progress.
Awarding the Peace Prize to a Pakistani Muslim and an Indian Hindu "gives a message to people of love between Pakistan and India, and between different religions," Yousafzai said. The decision sends a message that all people, regardless of language and religion, should fight for the rights of women, children and every human being.
The Malala Fund, set up to promote girls' education, said via Twitter that Yousafzai called the prize "an encouragement for me to go forward. It means we are standing together to ensure all children get quality education."
Committee commends Satyarthi's courage
Meanwhile, Satyarthi, age 60, has shown great personal courage in heading peaceful demonstrations focusing on the grave exploitation of children for financial gain, the committee said.
Satyarthi told reporters that the award was about many more people than him -- and that credit should go to all those "sacrificing their time and their lives for the cause of child rights" and fighting child slavery.
"It is a great honor for all those children who are deprived of their childhood globally," he said.
"It's an honor to all my fellow Indians who have got this honor -- it's not just an honor for me, it's an honor for all those fighting against child labor globally."
'She has made her countrymen proud'
Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif congratulated Yousafzai.
"She is (the) pride of Pakistan, she has made her countrymen proud," he is quoted as saying in a statement. "Her achievement is unparalleled and unequaled.
"Girls and boys of the world should take lead from her struggle and commitment."
His Indian counterpart, Narendra Modi, congratulated both Nobel laureates via Twitter.
"Kailash Satyarthi has devoted his life to a cause that is extremely relevant to entire humankind. I salute his determined efforts," he said, adding that "Malala Yousafzai's life is a journey of immense grit (and) courage."
A spokesman for the Pakistani Taliban, formally known as Tehrik-i-Taliban Pakistan, via email called Yousafzai a "beloved servant" of "infidels" who was awarded the Nobel "for her services to them." The Islamist group, which has intimate links to the Afghan Taliban and al Qaeda, unabashedly confirmed two years ago that it tried to kill the teen activist as she rode home from school in a van.
The spokesman, Ehsanullah Ehsan, said she was targeted because of what he called her "propaganda against Islam."
Nobel Peace Prize: They didn't win, either
The Nobel committee said it "regards it as an important point for a Hindu and a Muslim, an Indian and a Pakistani, to join in a common struggle for education and against extremism.
"It has been calculated that there are 168 million child labourers around the world today. In 2000 the figure was 78 million higher. The world has come closer to the goal of eliminating child labour."
U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon congratulated both winners, describing Yousafzai as "a brave and gentle advocate of peace who through the simple act of going to school became a global teacher" and Satyarthi as having carried out heroic work to combat child exploitation.
"The true winners today are the world's children," he added.
Opinion: Malala is the new symbol of hope
'Absolutely thrilled'
Nigel Chapman, chief executive of the Plan International aid organization, said the award brought a "fantastic glow" to his heart.
"I think anybody who's interested in campaigning for children's rights is absolutely thrilled by this news," he said, speaking to CNN from New York.
"It's often hard to get these issues at the top of the agenda, and the fact that these two really important figures have been honored today is terrific news."
Chapman praised the Nobel committee for its smart move in awarding the prize jointly to Yousafzai and Satyarthi, who are "two major heroes" in their countries.
The issues of education and child labor are intimately linked together, he said, "because one of the reasons that girls in particular don't go to school is because they are working, often in difficult and dangerous circumstances, trying to earn money for their families."
There are still 65 million girls worldwide who are not in school, he said. Millions start lessons but drop out for reasons including having to work or being forced to marry very young.
He said it was also a great boost for campaigners on the eve of the International Day of the Girl.
Pakistani campaigner: Hard work is needed
Mosharraf Zaidi, a Pakistani education campaigner and former adviser to the Foreign Ministry, welcomed the award but cautioned that there is still a long way to go in his country.
In Pakistan, he told CNN, there are 25 million children ages 5 to 16 who are not in school, more than half of whom are girls.
"So there's a huge need for a campaigner and a voice like Malala's," he said. "Unfortunately, that voice hasn't been welcome in Pakistan in the way that we would've hoped and the work that needs to be done to fulfill the dreams that Malala has, has not yet begun.
"Pakistan's politicians have become very good at paying lip service to the needs of Pakistan's children without doing any of the hard work that's needed."
Pakistan needs to dramatically increase its spending on education and improve how that money is spent, he said, and it "needs to get serious" about giving every child a good education.
Courage, determination and vision
Former UK Prime Minister Gordon Brown, who is the U.N. special envoy for global education, described the two winners as "the world's greatest children's champions."
They "deserve the Nobel Peace Prize for their courage, determination and for their vision that no child should ever be left behind and that every child should have the best of chances," he said.
"Kailash's life-long work in India fighting child labour -- which I have had the privilege to see at first hand -- complements Malala's work standing up for girls' rights to education from Pakistan to the rest of the world."
European Union leaders Jose Manuel Barroso and Herman Van Rompuy said the prize was a victory for all the children around the world who aspire to go to school.
When the European Union won the peace prize in 2012, they said, it decided to use the money for the same purpose, through an EU program for children in conflict zones.
U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein said the award sends an important message of support to all those working for children's rights and rewards "two extraordinarily inspirational human rights defenders" who "have demonstrated tremendous courage in the face of powerful adversaries."
He said he hoped it would bolster the political will of countries and institutions worldwide to uphold the rights of children.
Salil Shetty, secretary general of Amnesty International, hailed the pair's work as representing the struggle of millions of children around the world.
"This is an award for human rights defenders who are willing to dedicate themselves entirely to promoting education and the rights of the world's most vulnerable children," he said.
Prerequisite for peace
The Norwegian Nobel Committee makes the point that 60% of the current population is under 25 years of age in the poorest countries of the world.
"It is a prerequisite for peaceful global development that the rights of children and young people be respected," it said. "In conflict-ridden areas in particular, the violation of children leads to the continuation of violence from generation to generation."
Yousafzai was among the favorites for the prize last year, which instead went to the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons, for its longstanding efforts to "do away with a whole category of weapons of mass destruction."
The Norwegian Nobel Committee received a record 278 nominations for the 2014 prize, 47 of which were for organizations.
Each prize carries with it a monetary reward of 8 million Swedish kronor (about $1.1 million) to be divided among the winners.
CNN's Ray Sanchez, Lindsay Isaac, Alexander Felton, Sophia Saifi and Radina Gigova contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Nobel Peace Prize goes to Malala</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/bestoftv/2014/10/10/nobel-peace-prize-winner-earlystart.cnn.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>The 2014 Nobel Peace Prize is awarded to Indian Kailash Satyarthi and Pakistani Malala Yousafzai.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Nobel Peace Prize goes to Malala</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/bestoftv/2014/10/10/nobel-peace-prize-winner-earlystart.cnn.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>The 2014 Nobel Peace Prize is awarded to Indian Kailash Satyarthi and Pakistani Malala Yousafzai.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Bianchi family reveal F1 driver has suffered 'diffuse axonal injury'</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/07/sport/motorsport/motorsport-bianchi-injury-family-update/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>Family of F1 driver injured at Sunday's Japanese GP reveal further details on condition
Jules Bianchi suffering from an "diffuse axonal injury" according to family statement
The injury causes widespread tearing of nerve fibers in brain, according to UK brain injury charity
Bianchi collided with a recovery vehicle attempting to remove a competitor's car at side of track
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>8</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1028</time>
            </date>
            <author></author>
            <text>Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- The family of Jules Bianchi, the Formula One racing driver who was critically injured at Sunday's Japanese Grand Prix, have revealed that he is suffering from a "diffuse axonal injury."
It is a potentially devastating type of brain injury which causes widespread tearing of nerve fibers across the whole of the brain, according to the UK brain injury charity, Headway.
The 25-year-old Marussia driver remains in a critical but stable state, his family said in a statement released via the F1 team's official Facebook page.
"Jules remains in the Intensive Care Unit of the Mie General Medical Center in Yokkaichi. He has suffered a diffuse axonal injury and is in a critical but stable condition," the statement said.
"The medical professionals at the hospital are providing the very best treatment and care and we are grateful for everything they have done for Jules since his accident."
The Frenchman sustained his injuries after coming off the track and colliding with a recovery vehicle that was removing Adrian Sutil's Sauber car -- the German driver had skidded off the track at turn seven moments earlier in a rain-affected race.
"This is a very difficult time for our family, but the messages of support and affection for Jules from all over the world have been a source of great comfort to us. We would like to express our sincere appreciation," the statement said.
"We are also grateful for the presence of Professor Gerard Saillant, President of the FIA Medical Commission, and Professor Alessandro Frati, Neurosurgeon of the University of Rome La Sapienza, who has travelled to Japan at the request of Scuderia Ferrari.
"They arrived at the hospital today and met with the medical personnel responsible for Jules' treatment, in order to be fully informed of his clinical status so that they are able to advise the family.
"The hospital will continue to monitor and treat Jules and further medical updates will be provided when appropriate."
Read more: Marussia request patience on Bianchi condition
Read more: Bianchi suffers 'severe head injury'

</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-europe">
        <news>
            <title>Malala Yousafzai and Kailash Satyarthi share Nobel Peace Prize</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/world/europe/nobel-peace-prize/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>Pakistan's Malala Yousafzai: Children around the world "should stand up for their rights"
India's Prime Minister congratulates winners for determination and courage
Pakistani PM Nawaz Sharif says Yousafzai has "made her countrymen proud"
India's Kailash Satyarthi says award honors everyone working for child rights
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1925</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The Nobel Peace Prize was awarded Friday to India's Kailash Satyarthi and Pakistan's Malala Yousafzai for their struggles against the suppression of children and for young people's rights, including the right to education.
Thorbjorn Jagland, chairman of the Norwegian Nobel Committee, said, "Children must go to school, not be financially exploited."
Yousafzai came to global attention after she was shot in the head by the Taliban -- two years ago Thursday -- for her efforts to promote education for girls in Pakistan. Since then, after recovering from surgery, she has taken her campaign to the world stage, notably with a speech last year at the United Nations.
Through her heroic struggle, Yousafzai has become a leading spokeswoman for girls' rights to education, said Jagland.
According to the Nobel committee, at 17 she's the youngest ever peace prize winner.
Yousafzai said that the award is a "great honor for me," and that she's honored to share it with Satyarthi.
"I'm proud that I'm the first Pakistani and the first young woman or the first young person getting this award," she said in Birmingham, England.
Yousafzai learned she won the award while she was in chemistry class in England on Friday morning, she said. She wasn't expecting to get the award, and at 10:15 a.m., she was sure she hadn't won. But soon afterward, a teacher called her over and told her she had.
Yousafzai said she continued to attend classes, and it was a "normal day," besides teachers and fellow students congratulating her.
She said she doesn't believe that she deserved the award but considers it an encouragement to continue her campaign and "to know that I'm not alone," Yousafzai told reporters.
New beginnings
Her award will not mark the end of her campaign to advocate for girls' education, she said.
"I think this is really the beginning," she said, adding that children around the world "should stand up for their rights" and "not wait for someone else."
Yousafzai spoke with Satyarthi by phone Friday, and they agreed to work together to advocate that every child is able to go to school. She said they also decided to try to build a stronger relationship between their countries, which are longtime rivals.
She said she wants the Prime Ministers of India and Pakistan to attend the December ceremony where she and Satyarthi will receive their awards. Peace between the two nations, Yousafzai said, is important for their progress.
Awarding the Peace Prize to a Pakistani Muslim and an Indian Hindu "gives a message to people of love between Pakistan and India, and between different religions," Yousafzai said. The decision sends a message that all people, regardless of language and religion, should fight for the rights of women, children and every human being.
The Malala Fund, set up to promote girls' education, said via Twitter that Yousafzai called the prize "an encouragement for me to go forward. It means we are standing together to ensure all children get quality education."
Committee commends Satyarthi's courage
Meanwhile, Satyarthi, age 60, has shown great personal courage in heading peaceful demonstrations focusing on the grave exploitation of children for financial gain, the committee said.
Satyarthi told reporters that the award was about many more people than him -- and that credit should go to all those "sacrificing their time and their lives for the cause of child rights" and fighting child slavery.
"It is a great honor for all those children who are deprived of their childhood globally," he said.
"It's an honor to all my fellow Indians who have got this honor -- it's not just an honor for me, it's an honor for all those fighting against child labor globally."
'She has made her countrymen proud'
Pakistani Prime Minister Nawaz Sharif congratulated Yousafzai.
"She is (the) pride of Pakistan, she has made her countrymen proud," he is quoted as saying in a statement. "Her achievement is unparalleled and unequaled.
"Girls and boys of the world should take lead from her struggle and commitment."
His Indian counterpart, Narendra Modi, congratulated both Nobel laureates via Twitter.
"Kailash Satyarthi has devoted his life to a cause that is extremely relevant to entire humankind. I salute his determined efforts," he said, adding that "Malala Yousafzai's life is a journey of immense grit (and) courage."
A spokesman for the Pakistani Taliban, formally known as Tehrik-i-Taliban Pakistan, via email called Yousafzai a "beloved servant" of "infidels" who was awarded the Nobel "for her services to them." The Islamist group, which has intimate links to the Afghan Taliban and al Qaeda, unabashedly confirmed two years ago that it tried to kill the teen activist as she rode home from school in a van.
The spokesman, Ehsanullah Ehsan, said she was targeted because of what he called her "propaganda against Islam."
Nobel Peace Prize: They didn't win, either
The Nobel committee said it "regards it as an important point for a Hindu and a Muslim, an Indian and a Pakistani, to join in a common struggle for education and against extremism.
"It has been calculated that there are 168 million child labourers around the world today. In 2000 the figure was 78 million higher. The world has come closer to the goal of eliminating child labour."
U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon congratulated both winners, describing Yousafzai as "a brave and gentle advocate of peace who through the simple act of going to school became a global teacher" and Satyarthi as having carried out heroic work to combat child exploitation.
"The true winners today are the world's children," he added.
Opinion: Malala is the new symbol of hope
'Absolutely thrilled'
Nigel Chapman, chief executive of the Plan International aid organization, said the award brought a "fantastic glow" to his heart.
"I think anybody who's interested in campaigning for children's rights is absolutely thrilled by this news," he said, speaking to CNN from New York.
"It's often hard to get these issues at the top of the agenda, and the fact that these two really important figures have been honored today is terrific news."
Chapman praised the Nobel committee for its smart move in awarding the prize jointly to Yousafzai and Satyarthi, who are "two major heroes" in their countries.
The issues of education and child labor are intimately linked together, he said, "because one of the reasons that girls in particular don't go to school is because they are working, often in difficult and dangerous circumstances, trying to earn money for their families."
There are still 65 million girls worldwide who are not in school, he said. Millions start lessons but drop out for reasons including having to work or being forced to marry very young.
He said it was also a great boost for campaigners on the eve of the International Day of the Girl.
Pakistani campaigner: Hard work is needed
Mosharraf Zaidi, a Pakistani education campaigner and former adviser to the Foreign Ministry, welcomed the award but cautioned that there is still a long way to go in his country.
In Pakistan, he told CNN, there are 25 million children ages 5 to 16 who are not in school, more than half of whom are girls.
"So there's a huge need for a campaigner and a voice like Malala's," he said. "Unfortunately, that voice hasn't been welcome in Pakistan in the way that we would've hoped and the work that needs to be done to fulfill the dreams that Malala has, has not yet begun.
"Pakistan's politicians have become very good at paying lip service to the needs of Pakistan's children without doing any of the hard work that's needed."
Pakistan needs to dramatically increase its spending on education and improve how that money is spent, he said, and it "needs to get serious" about giving every child a good education.
Courage, determination and vision
Former UK Prime Minister Gordon Brown, who is the U.N. special envoy for global education, described the two winners as "the world's greatest children's champions."
They "deserve the Nobel Peace Prize for their courage, determination and for their vision that no child should ever be left behind and that every child should have the best of chances," he said.
"Kailash's life-long work in India fighting child labour -- which I have had the privilege to see at first hand -- complements Malala's work standing up for girls' rights to education from Pakistan to the rest of the world."
European Union leaders Jose Manuel Barroso and Herman Van Rompuy said the prize was a victory for all the children around the world who aspire to go to school.
When the European Union won the peace prize in 2012, they said, it decided to use the money for the same purpose, through an EU program for children in conflict zones.
U.N. High Commissioner for Human Rights Zeid Ra'ad Al Hussein said the award sends an important message of support to all those working for children's rights and rewards "two extraordinarily inspirational human rights defenders" who "have demonstrated tremendous courage in the face of powerful adversaries."
He said he hoped it would bolster the political will of countries and institutions worldwide to uphold the rights of children.
Salil Shetty, secretary general of Amnesty International, hailed the pair's work as representing the struggle of millions of children around the world.
"This is an award for human rights defenders who are willing to dedicate themselves entirely to promoting education and the rights of the world's most vulnerable children," he said.
Prerequisite for peace
The Norwegian Nobel Committee makes the point that 60% of the current population is under 25 years of age in the poorest countries of the world.
"It is a prerequisite for peaceful global development that the rights of children and young people be respected," it said. "In conflict-ridden areas in particular, the violation of children leads to the continuation of violence from generation to generation."
Yousafzai was among the favorites for the prize last year, which instead went to the Organisation for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons, for its longstanding efforts to "do away with a whole category of weapons of mass destruction."
The Norwegian Nobel Committee received a record 278 nominations for the 2014 prize, 47 of which were for organizations.
Each prize carries with it a monetary reward of 8 million Swedish kronor (about $1.1 million) to be divided among the winners.
CNN's Ray Sanchez, Lindsay Isaac, Alexander Felton, Sophia Saifi and Radina Gigova contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Nobel Peace Prize goes to Malala</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/bestoftv/2014/10/10/nobel-peace-prize-winner-earlystart.cnn.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>The 2014 Nobel Peace Prize is awarded to Indian Kailash Satyarthi and Pakistani Malala Yousafzai.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Nobel Peace Prize goes to Malala</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/video/data/2.0/video/bestoftv/2014/10/10/nobel-peace-prize-winner-earlystart.cnn.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <author></author>
            <text>The 2014 Nobel Peace Prize is awarded to Indian Kailash Satyarthi and Pakistani Malala Yousafzai.
If your browser has Adobe Flash Player installed, click above to play. Otherwise, click below.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Ebola: More fears, more measures after first patient diagnosed in the U.S. dies</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/health/ebola-up-to-speed/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Liberian president "a bit more confident" about avoiding most dire predictions
NEW: Spokesman: US Airways followed CDC guidelines after health scare on Dominican flight
After negative test, Texas sheriff's deputy is discharged
Hotel closed in Macedonia after sudden death, ministry says
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>204</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Faith Karimi and Ashley Fantz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- As the death of the first patient diagnosed with Ebola in the U.S. sparks more fears, airports are beefing up screening for people from affected nations.
With developments pouring in from all corners of the world, here's what you need to know to quickly get caught up on the latest:
WEST AFRICA
No relief in sight:
The world's largest outbreak of Ebola has killed more than 3,800 people, the World Health Organization said Wednesday. The numbers reflect confirmed Ebola cases in Guinea, Liberia, Nigeria, Senegal, Sierra Leone and the United States, the WHO said.
The virus is affecting medical workers. A United Nations official is being treated in Liberia after contracting Ebola. The unnamed worker is the second U.N. member infected with the virus in Liberia. The first one died last month.
A possible $32 billion hit:
The outbreak could cost the African economy $32 billion over the next two years if it spreads to its larger neighbors, the World Bank estimates.
The steps some countries have taken to prevent the spread of the Ebola virus amount to "putting a towel under the door of a building on fire," World Bank president Jim Kim told CNN's Richard Quest on Thursday.
Complete coverage on Ebola
Liberia postpones election:
Liberia's President on Thursday postponed a senatorial election that had been set for next week, citing the Ebola outbreak in the country.
The nation's election commission had recommended the delay, saying that the prevalence of the virus, authorities' efforts to combat it and citizens' efforts to isolate themselves weren't conducive to a free and open election.
Officials have not yet revealed any new date for the election, which had been set for Tuesday.
U.S. troops arrive in Liberia:
A group of 90 U.S. Marines and airmen arrived in Liberia on Thursday to help Ebola response efforts, along with four V-22 Osprey aircraft and two C-130 transport planes.
Their arrival brings the total number of U.S. troops deployed in Liberia to 334, military spokesman Lt. Col. Dave Doherty said. And there are more coming. In late October, 700 troops from the 101st Airborne Division are scheduled to deploy to Liberia.
Liberian leader a 'bit more confident':
Liberian President Ellen Johnson Sirleaf on Thursday acknowledged the human and economic toll that Ebola has taken on her country since beginning in March and during the ensuing intensifying weeks, before adding, "We are a bit more confident (now) that our collective response will turn the curve away from the dire projections."
Sirleaf outlined several steps to overcome the crisis. They include a "more timely and decisive response" to the Ebola crisis, including new testing, treatment and burying centers;" improving the nation's normal health care system; and bolstering the economy overall, including through infrastructure and other projects.
U.S. CASES
Thomas Duncan dies:
Thomas Eric Duncan, the first person diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died Wednesday, 10 days after he was admitted to Dallas' Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital. His family wonders whether the outcome would have been different if doctors had admitted Duncan to a hospital on September 25, the first time he showed up with a fever and stomach pain.
Duncan's family has criticized the care he received. The Dallas hospital that treated him says staff members did everything they could.
Ebola test negative for Dallas deputy:
An Ebola test was negative for a Dallas deputy who was hospitalized with possible symptoms of the deadly virus, officials said. The deputy, Sgt. Michael Monnig, didn't have any direct contact with Duncan but had reported contact with Duncan's family.
Physicians at Texas Health Presbyterian discharged him Thursday, soon after the negative test came back, hospital spokeswoman Candace White said.
New travel screening:
Five of America's biggest, busiest airports are beefing up measures. Now, people arriving from the three nations hardest hit by Ebola will get special screening, including having their temperature taken. The airports are: New York's JFK, Washington Dulles, Newark, Chicago O'Hare and Atlanta international airports.
IN OTHER COUNTRIES
Spain ramps up response:
After a nurse's assistant in Spain became the first person to contract Ebola outside Africa, five people related to the case were being monitored in a Madrid hospital, including her husband, an emergency room doctor and the neighborhood doctor who saw her before the case was confirmed.
'Save Excalibur' fails:
Despite a public push to save its life, Excalibur -- the Spanish nurse assistant's dog -- was euthanized because of concern it may have become infected with Ebola. Critics said the dog should have been quarantined, just like the assistant's husband has been.
Sporadic infections unavoidable, the WHO says:
Sporadic Ebola infections will be unavoidable in some European countries because of direct travel from their hubs to hotspot areas in West Africa, the World Health Organization said Wednesday. But the risk of spread, it said, is avoidable and extremely low.
Australia scare:
A 57-year-old woman who returned to Australia after treating Ebola patients in Sierra Leone has been isolated at a hospital and is undergoing tests, including one for the deadly virus, authorities said. She had isolated herself at home and checked her temperature twice daily since her return, as recommended by national guidelines.
The Queensland Department of Health announced early Friday that initial tests on the woman came back negative for Ebola.
United Kingdom:
The UK's Heathrow and Gatwick airports and Eurostar railway terminals will begin screening passengers arriving from Ebola-affected Liberia, Sierra Leone and Guinea, a government spokesman said. Screening will involve assessing passengers' recent travel history, who they have been in contact with and future travel arrangements, as well as a possible assessment performed by medical personnel.
Macedonia:
A Macedonian hotel has closed after a person staying there died two hours after being taken to a hospital, the country's health ministry announced Thursday. The patient did not live in one of the West African countries most affected by Ebola, nor did he have a high temperature that's symptomatic of the virus.
Still, even though there's a "rather high chance" this person did not have Ebola, "we are undertaking all the necessary measures" just in case, according to the health ministry. That includes not only shutting down the hotel, but also quarantining those who were in the same hotel, as well as medical staff who had direct contact with the patient.
Dominican Republic:
Dominican authorities met US Airways Flight 845 on Wednesday after it landed in Punta Cana from Philadelphia "due to a possible health issue on board," airline spokeswoman Michelle Mohr said.
"Strictly adhering to all CDC guidelines for airlines in response to the Ebola virus," officials checked and eventually cleared the plane, according to Mohr.
CNN's Greg Botelho, Alexander Felton, Khushbu Shah, Saskya Vandoorne, Richard Quest, Brent Swails and Nima Elbagir contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Spanish Ebola patient's condition worsens, doctor says</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/health/ebola-spain/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: 14 total are in a Madrid hospital; Romero is the only one with confirmed Ebola
Doctor declines to give further details about Teresa Romero Ramos' condition, treatment
Another doctor, who tended to patient, says his protective sleeves were inadequate
The nurse's assistant treated missionaries from Africa who had Ebola
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>9</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2251</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Perez-Maestro, Jason Hanna and Greg Botelho, CNN</author>
            <text>Madrid (CNN) -- A nurse's assistant in Spain -- the first person to contract Ebola outside Africa -- has taken a turn for the worse.
Dr. Yolanda Fuentes, who works at Madrid's Carlos III hospital, said Thursday that Teresa Romero Ramos' condition had worsened but declined to give further details.
Romero became sick after she helped treat an Ebola-stricken Spanish missionary. Her case has prompted questions from her fellow medical professionals about whether they are properly equipped to safely treat Ebola patients, and about why a week passed before she was treated.
The update on her condition comes 10 days after Romero first began feeling sick and three days after she called an ambulance to take her to a hospital.
Carlos III hospital indicated late Thursday that seven more people -- a doctor, three nurses, two beauticians, a doctor and a hospital staffer -- have been admitted for observation. This is in addition to seven others already in the hospital, though none of these besides Romero has tested positive for Ebola.
"The reason why we are seeing so many people admitted showing no symptoms is because the 80 people or so that are being monitored outside the hospital have been given the choice to do it at home or come into the hospital," said a hospital spokeswoman, who is not named, as is customary in Spain.
In addition to concerns about Romero and these individuals' health, the entire situation has raised serious questions about how the entire case was handled -- from how the nurse's assistant got the disease to how medical officials handled her care once she got sick.
Physician: My protection suit was too short
One of the physicians sounding the alarm -- Dr. Juan Manuel Parra, who treated Romero at a different Madrid hospital earlier in the week -- published an open letter Thursday indicating that his staff was ill-equipped to handle her.
Concerned about his exposure to Romero, Parra then checked himself into Carlos III. Parra was among five who the hospital said had no symptoms.
Parra says he cared for Romero on Monday at Madrid's Alcorcon Hospital, where an ambulance had taken her that morning. He wrote that the sleeves on the protective suits available to him were too short, exposing parts of his arms.
In his letter, published Thursday by Spanish news outlets, Parra wrote that Romero was in an isolation room. He said he visited her 12 times in isolation from 8 a.m. to midnight, when she was transferred to Carlos III, which specializes in infectious diseases.
Her condition worsened throughout the day, and by the evening she had tested positive twice for Ebola, he wrote. But Parra said he learned of both positive results from media before hospital officials told him.
Deadliest Ebola outbreak: What you need to know
He said he was told of the second positive test at 7 p.m., but it took five more hours for an ambulance to collect her for the trip to Carlos III, he wrote.
Parra adds to a chorus of Spanish medical professionals who've expressed alarm.
Speaking about what's unfolding in Madrid, Health Minister Ana Mato told Parliament earlier this week Spain is going to revise its protocols for handling Ebola.
Prime Minister Mariano Rajoy said that his country is "facing a matter that is of international concern." But that doesn't mean Spaniards should hunker down or become overly alarmed, he said, and urged them to "keep calm."
How NYC is preparing for Ebola
Dismay in Madrid
The Ebola virus has infected more than 8,000 people and killed at least 3,800 in the current outbreak, according to the World Health Organization. It's also been largely confined -- as far as we know so far, every person has caught the disease in West Africa except for Romero.
Romero's case began after two Spanish missionaries -- Miguel Pajares and Manuel Garcia Viejo -- contracted Ebola in West Africa. They were sent to Spain, specifically Carlos III, for treatment. Romero twice had contact with one of the priests as part of his care, on September 24 and September 25, the WHO said.
Both priests eventually died at the hospital. Romero's patient died on September 25; on September 29, she began feeling ill.
That Romero may have gotten Ebola at Carlos III is a major cause of concern, especially if she did -- as she told Spanish newspaper El Mundo -- follow the necessary protocols while caring for the missionaries.
How did Spanish nurse catch Ebola?
Dr. German Ramirez, who is among those treating her, said Romero may have been exposed while removing protective gear she'd donned to treat one of the priests.
"That's what we were working on -- on the errors possibly made while removing the protective suit," Ramirez told reporters this week, saying it's possible the protective suit or gloves may have touched her face.
On Tuesday -- the morning that Romero was transferred from Alcorcon to Carlos III for treatment -- angry doctors and nurses outside Carlos III said they were outraged that the two priests, almost dead when they arrived, had been brought there.
Also prompting concern is how long it took for Romero to be treated -- and how long she may have exposed other people to the deadly virus while she was contagious.
According to a Carlos III hospital spokeswoman, Romero started feeling ill on September 29. She went the next day to her doctor, who did not properly identify her problem and sent her home.
But Romero didn't get better. She called Carlos III hospital on October 2 and was directed, per protocol, to an external medical department under the umbrella of Madrid's regional health service, the hospital spokesman said.
Romero ended up back home again. On Monday, she called an ambulance, which took her to Alcorcon hospital, which diagnosed her over a 16-hour period and sent her to Carlos III.
Parra's letter didn't address how long Romero might have been outside an isolation room at Alcorcon. A worker at that hospital told CNN on condition of anonymity earlier this week that Romero lay in the emergency room -- exposed to other patients as well as medical staff -- for eight hours before she was transferred to Carlos III.
Romero's experience is similar to that of Thomas Eric Duncan, the Liberian citizen who was sent home from a Dallas, Texas, hospital days before eventually being admitted for Ebola. Duncan, the first person diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died Wednesday.
Romero's dog put down
Authorities said Tuesday that a total of 30 people from Carlos III Hospital and 22 others -- from the Alcorcon hospital where the woman first sought care, plus family members -- were being monitored.
Madrid health authorities on Wednesday put down Romero's dog, Excalibur, despite a public outcry to save it.
'Save Excalibur' campaign fails
About 400,000 people signed an online petition to save the dog from being killed, contending that that "it would be much easier to isolate or quarantine the dog just as they have the victim's husband," rather than forcing the couple to lose "one of the family."
But health authorities insisted they had to take action in case Excalibur had the disease.
It's not known if Ebola can be passed through canines. The World Health Organization has said that it's infected chimpanzees, gorillas, fruit bats, monkeys, forest antelope and porcupines. Human infections, to date, have not been linked to dogs.
Complete Ebola coverage
CNN's Laura Perez-Maestro reported from Madrid. CNN's Jason Hanna and Greg Botelho reported and wrote in Atlanta. CNN's Al Goodman, Isa Soares and Laura Smith-Spark contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Germany humbled by Poland in Euro 2016 qualifier</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/sport/football/germany-poland-warsaw-euro-2016/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>Poland defeat Germany in Euro 2016 qualification match-up
Goals from Arkadiusz Milik and Sebastian Mila secure 2-0 victory
Result marks Poland's first ever win over Germany
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2230</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Eoghan Macguire, for CNN</author>
            <text>Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Becoming world champions for the fourth time, defeating the illustrious Brazil 7-1 in their own back yard along the way before returning to the adulation of a million people at the Brandenburg Gate in Berlin -- 2014 has been just about the perfect year for Germany's football stars.
But things didn't quite go to plan on Saturday as Joachim Low's side was defeated 2-0 by a well organized Poland in Euro 2016 qualifying.
The result marks the first time Poland has ever defeated Germany -- a fact not lost on the raucous home crowd who seemed to expend as much energy singing and shouting over the course of this pulsating Group D match as their heroes did on the pitch.
After a goalless first half, Arkadiusz Milik gave the Poles the lead in the 50th minute, rising to nod beyond Germany goalkeeper, Manuel Neuer.
Poland's star-striker Robert Lewandoski then showed great strength to hold-off former Borussia Dortmund teammate Erik Durm late on before squaring to substitute Sebastian Mila who arrowed a fine strike beyond Neuer to make sure of the win.
Goalkeeper Wojciech Szczesny saved well from German sharp-shooters Andre Schurle and Mario Gotze in the moments after Poland took the lead while Lukas Podolski crashed a left-footed off the crossbar from eight yards out with 10 minutes remaining.
Despite having much of the possession, Germany struggled to break down their hosts who were happy to sit deep and play on the counter-attack.
"Obviously, we're disappointed." Low said in quotes carried by the German FA's website after the match.
"I can't blame my team for much, maybe only that we were too careless with our chances. Poland then made it 1-0 with their very first shot."
Low's frustration was echoed by Neuer who admitted to being caught out for Poland's first strike.
"It was an avoidable defeat," Neuer said. "We didn't play badly. If we had scored the first goal, then we would have won."
"I came out bravely for the first goal, but I was too late -- it was a mistake by me."
Qualification for Euro 2016 in a group that also features Scotland, the Republic of Ireland and Georgia now seems wide open, although the World Champions will still be favorites to qualify.
In Saturday's other Group D fixtures, Robbie Keane scored a hat-trick in the first 18 minutes of the Republic of Ireland's 7-0 romp against tournament debutants Gibraltar.
Scotland overcame Georgia 1-0 in Glasgow, meanwhile, thanks to an own goal from Akaki Khubutia who turned into his own net after a vicious shot from Shaun Maloney.
Poland now top the group with six points, ahead of Ireland on goal difference.
Germany and Scotland lie three points back in third and fourth position respectively.
The Poles have the chance to stretch their lead when they welcome Scotland on Wednesday while Germany will aim to get back on track by defeating the Irish in Gelsenkirchen.
Northern Ireland wins, Greeks and Danes draw
Elsewhere in Euro 2016 qualifying Saturday, Northern Ireland rose to the top of Group F thanks to a 2-0 home victory over minnows the Faroe Islands.
In the group's other matches, Finland held Greece 1-1 in Helsinki while a stunning free-kick from Balasz Dzsudzsak earned Hungary a 1-1 draw with Romania in Bucharest.
A late goal from substitute Lasse Vibe spared Denmark's blushes against Albania and ensured the Danes remain top of Group I.
Armenia held Serbia 1-1 in Hrazdan in Group I's earlier fixture.
Read: Brazil beats Argentina, Suarez returns
Read: India's first professional soccer league kicks off

</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141011215256-germaqny-poland-euro-2016-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Roger Federer eases Novak Djokovic aside to reach Shanghai final</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/sport/tennis/federer-djokovic-shanghai-murray-ferrer/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>Roger Federer defeats Novak Djokovic in Shanghai Masters semifinal
Djokovic was unbeaten in 28 matches on Chinese soil coming into match
Federer will face Giles Simon of France in Sunday's final
Murray and Ferrer take on extra tournaments in bid to reach ATP World Tour Finals
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2245</time>
            </date>
            <author></author>
            <text>Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- Roger Federer produced an imperious performance to end Novak Djokovic's 28 match winning streak on Chinese courts and claim a place in the final of the Shanghai Masters tournament Saturday.
The Swiss was in a confident, aggressive mood all evening, serving eight aces and firing down 35 winners, on his way to a 6-4 6-4 straight sets victory in just over an hour-and-a-half.
Federer will now face the unseeded Giles Simon in Sunday's final after the 29-year-old Frenchman overcame Feliciano Lopez of Spain 6-2 7-6 (7/1) in the day's earlier semifinal matchup.
"I'm not going to come into the match and play terrible," Federer said in quotes carried by the ATP website. "It just won't happen - not in the finals, not against Simon. That's the confidence I have right now."
"There was nothing in the game today that wasn't working. I think it was a high-level match. I'm unbelievably happy with the way it went."
The vanquished Djokovic was humble in defeat and paid tribute to his opponent's ruthlessness.
"I think I did not play too bad," said Djokovic, whose impressive China run included Shanghai Masters titles in 2012 and 2013 as well as three straight wins at the China Open in Beijing.
"It's just that he played everything he wanted to play," Djokovic added. "He played the perfect match ...an amazing match."
Federer's passage to the Shanghai final coupled with Rafael Nadal's early exit means he is now guaranteed to return to No.2 in the ATP world rankings on Monday no matter the outcome of Sunday's match.
Simon last reached the final of a Masters tournament six years ago and has dropped as low as 44th in the world this year but could rise to as high as 15th if he defeats Federer.
"I just know that I can do it," Simon told reporters after defeating Lopez. "When I'm playing good, I can play at (Federer's) level."
"The question is whether I will be able to do it tomorrow."
The race to London
Andy Murray and David Ferrer have both announced they will take on an extra tournament next week in a bid to qualify for November's ATP World Tour Finals in London.
Only the top eight ranked players qualify for the season-concluding event with a potential $2 million prize pot. Ferrer is currently ranked ninth while Murray is two places adrift in eleventh.
Both players have registered to take part in the Vienna Open which begins Tuesday and will also appear at tournaments in Valencia and Paris later in October.
Only three players, Djokovic, Federer and Nadal, have the rankings points to guarantee their participation in London.
Others with a shot of appearing in the British capital include Milos Raonic, Kei Nishikori, Tomas Berdych, Stan Wawrinka and Grigor Dimitrov.
Read: Nadal plays through pain barrier
Read: Federer like you've never seen him before

</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141011200147-federer-shanghai-djokovic-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Queen Elizabeth names Angelina Jolie honorary dame</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/showbiz/britain-angelina-jolie/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>Jolie is recognized for her campaign to end war-zone sexual violence
She is made Honorary Dame Grand Cross of the Most Distinguished Order of St. Michael and St. George
Jolie, 39, co-founded the Preventing Sexual Violence Initiative
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2128</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Ray Sanchez, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Britain's Queen Elizabeth II on Friday made Hollywood star Angelina Jolie an honorary dame for her campaign to end the scourge of sexual violence in war zones.
In a ceremony at Buckingham Palace, Jolie was presented with the Insignia of an Honorary Dame Grand Cross of the Most Distinguished Order of St. Michael and St. George.
Jolie, 39, is a special envoy to the U.N. High Commissioner for Refugees, and she co-founded the Preventing Sexual Violence Initiative with former British Foreign Secretary William Hague.
"It is a myth that rape is an inevitable part of conflict," Jolie said in June during the London opening of the biggest summit of its kind aimed at ending sexual violence in conflict. "There's nothing inevitable about it. It is a weapon of war aimed at civilians. It has nothing to do with sex, everything to do with power."
The Global Summit to End Sexual Violence in Conflict, hosted by the UK government, brought together representatives of more than 100 countries, as well as hundreds more experts, survivors, faith leaders, and staffers from NGOs and international organizations.
According to UNICEF, the United Nations children's agency, more than 150 million young girls and 73 million boys experience sexual violence every year, and children in conflict-affected countries are the most vulnerable.
Few perpetrators are ever prosecuted or convicted.
CNN's Max Foster contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Ex-Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev leaves hospital, report says</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/world/europe/russia-gorbachev-hospital/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev says he's left hospital, news agency says
NEW: He says he is not feeling "well" yet but is pleased to be back at work
After a disease recurrence, "I'm monitored, wires all over me," he told a radio station earlier
Gorbachev suffers from a severe form of diabetes, according to state media
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1319</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark and Matthew Chance, CNN</author>
            <text>Moscow (CNN) -- Former Soviet President Mikhail Gorbachev has left a hospital and is back at work, Russia's state-run RIA Novosti reported Friday.
Asked by RIA Novosti how he was feeling, he said that "well" was an overstatement, but that he was aiming for satisfactory and it was "already not bad" to be back at work.
The former leader had told a radio station, Russia News Service, on Thursday that he had been admitted to a hospital with "a disease recurrence," the news agency reported earlier Friday.
"I'm monitored, wires all over me," Gorbachev was quoted as saying to the station.
Gorbachev suffers from a severe form of diabetes and has often received treatment in German hospitals, according to RIA Novosti.
He was President of the Soviet Union from 1985 until his resignation in 1991, during which time he embarked on a process of change and increased openness to the West that became known as "perestroika."
He was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1990 for helping end the Cold War.

</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/131106142318-26-gorbachev-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Can the empire strike back?: England football chief plots brighter future</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/sport/football/football-greg-dyke-black-managers-england/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>English FA chairman Greg Dyke committed to recruiting more black coaches
England "miles behind" European neighbors, says English FA head Greg Dyke
Dyke desperate to nurture young talent but needs help of Premier League, he says
England's domestic league has boomed while country's international fortunes flag
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1725</time>
            </date>
            <author>By James Masters, for CNN</author>
            <text>Follow us at @WorldSportCNN and like us on Facebook
(CNN) -- It's a problem which is there in black and white.
There are 92 professional clubs in the English Football League -- but just two of those are led by black managers and according to the latest English Football Association report, while there are only 15 black or ethnic minority coaches working across the professional game.
It is a damning statistic which shames English football and the FA's chairman Greg Dyke says that must change with the FA currently discussing the merits of the Rooney rule which is used in the NFL as a way of bringing more black or ethnic minorities into the sport.
Chelsea manager Jose Mourinho recently said "there is no racism in football" but Dyke, who took over from David Bernstein in July 2013, is concerned about minority representation saying English football must implement its own Rooney rule.
"It has to happen," Greg Dyke, chairman of the FA told CNN, referring to the rule, which was introduced in the U.S. states to ensure teams should interview at least one black of ethnic minority candidate.
In the U.S. the number of black assistant coaches working in NFL rose from 14 in 1980 to 199 out of 610 in 2012 -- a rise of 32.6%.
Some 25 years ago, there was only one black head coach, Art Shell, who managed the Oakland Raiders, while now there are currently four with Lovie Smith, Mike Tomlin, Jim Caldwell and Marvin Lewis all leading the way.
But English football has not progressed with one former player, Sol Campbell, complaining that he would have to move abroad to pursue coaching opportunities because of the "archaic" attitudes towards black coaches.
"You go anywhere in the country to watch football now and there's a disproportionate amount of ethnic minorities and yet why are they not coming through the game?" pondered Dyke.
"We've got an inclusion group looking at whether the Rooney Rule would work. We apply the Rooney Rule when we're applying for coaches. You need to know it's going to work."
Rio Ferdinand, the former Manchester United and England defender, has advocated such a system and Dyke, has not discounted it.
"There's no point saying if you're going to interview five people with one from an ethnic minority if they're never going to get the job," he added.
"That's damaging. You need to know it's going to work which is why you have to get more coaches through."
The lack of leading Black, Asian and minority ethnic (BAME) coaches working in English football is just one problem facing Dyke and his commission.
Lagging behind European rivals
By the sound of it English football is effectively broken.
According to the latest report, there are only 205 English coaches with a UEFA pro-licence, the top qualification, compared to 2,353 in Spain and 1,304 in Germany.
Even lower down the ranking, Italy boasts 37,742 coaches with a 'B' licence compared to just 9,548 in England -- the lowest out of the five top leagues in Europe.
While the FA says there are 50,000 coaches active in England, 39,000 of those do not possess qualifications above the Youth Award 3 -- the level below the 'B' licence.
"We're miles behind, miles behind," said Dyke when commenting on coaching.
"We're miles behind on coaching and facilities. Can we catch up? Yes, but it will take five or 10 years."
The latest proposals would involve the FA set up a coach education organization which will be led by a new head of education who will sit on the governing body's executive.
The FA plans to build 'football hubs' in 30 different cities across England including London, Birmingham, Manchester, Liverpool and Sheffield with 230 million being invested in the project over the next five years, though bear in mind the Dutch FA is plowing 1 billion ($1.3 billion) into their domestic game every year.
The hubs will boast state of the art facilities including 3G artificial pitches which are widely used across Europe with Germany boasting 3,735 such surfaces compared to just 639 in England.
England has one synthetic pitch for every 42,000 people according to the FA report, while the Netherlands has one for every 13,000 -- a significant advantage for the development of young players.
Each hub will also have floodlights, changing rooms, a classroom and changing facilities all of which will be cared for by a local body.
There are also plans in place to increase those holding the very top coaching qualification to 300, while taking the number of Youth Award Level 3 coaches from 800 to 3,000.
"One of the criteria when we are setting up these coaching courses is that we want to get more people through it so we get more coaches," said Dyke.
"It's their job to analyze the constraints why people aren't coming. Is it that there isn't enough supply? Is it cost? Time?
"If you're an ex-Premier League footballer then cost doesn't matter. Therefore do you approach it by reducing the cost or by putting aside a fund for those who can't afford it?"
Leagues apart
While the FA counts every penny in its budget, the Premier League posted revenues of over 3 billion ($4.8 billion) last June, according to financial analysts Deloitte.
The Premier League has already secured a domestic television deal worth over 3 billion which lasts until the end of the 2016 season, while foreign broadcasters have paid 2.3 billion for the same period.
But have those riches damaged the English game with young domestic talent often not being the opportunity to shine with big money being spent on overseas stars?
According to the latest figures from the FA, Premier League starts made by English players were recorded at just 32%, while the figure for those at the top six clubs have decreased from 28% to 25%. That figure was at 69% two decades ago.
During the last transfer window, which ended on August 31, Premier League club spent a record 835 million on players.
The drought of young English talent has had a knock on effect with the national team suffering with the country not having reached the semifinals of a major tournament since 1996.
Speaking at the Leaders Conference in London earlier this week, Christian Seifert, the chief executive of the German Bundesliga, said the sheer amount of money within the Premier League was having a negative effect on player development.
He said: "If you have so much money compared to us ... and you can afford nearly every player around the world, how motivated are you to put the cards on young players who need one or two years?"
Seifert claims that the success of the German national team, which came following a through review of the country's failings during the dire 2000 European Championship campaign, benefited from the relationship with the nation's FA and the Bundesliga.
Dyke concedes that the FA cannot help transform the fortunes of English football alone -- he knows that without the cooperation of the Premier League, England could remain in the international wilderness without a supply line of fresh, young talent.
"The trouble is that because we're the richest league in the world, they've got enough money not to worry about bringing kids through," said Dyke.
"The average Premier League manager reign lasts a year. So, he's not going to do think about the five-year development, he's going to think about how to save his job.
"He can save his job by going to Belgium and buying a 22-year-old who has already played 200 games at a decent level.
"No we can't do it without the Premier League, but the Premier League and the clubs recognize the issue.
"At some stage, some of the owners of the clubs are going to say, 'I'm spending six or seven million on an academy and getting nothing out of it.
"It needs money and they've got money. I think they'll contribute as long as other people contribute."
Read more: FIFA's sexism own goal?
Read more: Managerial spat boils over

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>UK police arrest 5th suspect in alleged terror plot</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/world/europe/uk-terror-arrests/index.html?hpt=ieu_c2</url>
            <highlits>Police said Islamic terrorism was "the clear reason" for alleged plot
Two weeks ago, 10 others were arrested on suspicion of terror offenses
Authorities not saying where or when attacks might have happened
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>9</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2053</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Ralph Ellis, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A fifth man has been arrested on suspicion of planning an act of terrorism, British police said Thursday.
All the men, ages 20 and 21, remain in custody at central London police stations. The warrant for further detention has been granted until October 14, police said.
The arrests come nearly two weeks after police arrested at least 10 other men in the United Kingdom on suspicion of terror offenses, including supporting a banned organization and encouraging terrorism.
A UK security source said Tuesday that authorities may have foiled a terror plot aimed at Britain in its early stages. Islamic terrorism was "the clear reason" for the plot, according to the source.
After four men were arrested earlier this week, Scotland Yard said they are being held on suspicion related to the "commission, preparation or instigation of act of terrorism."
Authorities have not detailed exactly where or when such terrorist attacks might have occurred or what or who they might have involved.
Metropolitan Police Commissioner Bernard Hogan-Howe, in an interview with BBC local radio, said many recent arrests are "linked back to Syria and Iraq."
In the latest arrests, authorities said they searched residences and vehicles in west and central London as part of the investigation.
UK police arrest 4 men suspected of terror plot
CNN's Alex Felton in London contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-latin-america">
        <news>
            <title>Mexico captures Vicente Carrillo Fuentes, alleged Juarez Cartel chief</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/world/americas/mexico-juarez-cartel-leader-captured/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Mexican federal police have captured Vicente Carrillo Fuentes
NEW: Authorities captured him at a checkpoint in Torreon, Mexico
Alleged Juarez Cartel boss was one of Mexico's most wanted criminals
He's apparently led the cartel since 1997, when his brother died during plastic surgery
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>212</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- His cartel helped give Ciudad Juarez its infamous reputation as one of the world's most violent cities.
But no shots were fired when Mexican federal police captured alleged Juarez Cartel boss Vicente Carrillo Fuentes, authorities said Thursday.
The 51-year-old kingpin was detained alongside a bodyguard in a "discreet operation" at a checkpoint in the northern city of Torreon, said Monte Alejandro Rubido, head of Mexico's National Security Council.
The driver's license Carrillo Fuentes flashed at a checkpoint concealed his identity. But once he realized he'd been found out, Carrillo Fuentes admitted who he was, Rubido said.
Carrillo Fuentes, known as "El Viceroy," was one of Mexico's most wanted alleged criminals.
U.S. authorities had been offering a reward of up to $5 million for information leading to his arrest or conviction.
A list of the U.S. Drug Enforcement Administration's most wanted fugitives describes Carrillo Fuentes as a former Mexican police officer and notes that he "occasionally travels to El Paso, TX."
A State Department Narcotics Rewards Program description of the notorious drug lord describes him as a "known user of narcotics" who is "believed to have had plastic surgery" and may have scars around his face.
Cartel's influence had been waning
In the United States, Carrillo Fuentes faces a number of charges, including drug trafficking, conspiracy, money laundering, tampering with a witness and "ordering the intentional killing of individuals to prevent communication of information," the State Department said.
There were five arrest warrants for his capture in Mexico, where authorities were offering a reward of 30 million pesos ($2.2 million).
Analysts have said the Juarez Cartel's influence had been waning after a lengthy battle for territory with the Sinaloa Cartel.
Some speculate that violence dropped in Ciudad Juarez, located across the border from El Paso, Texas, after the Sinaloa Cartel won the fight for control.
But at one time, the Juarez Cartel was one of the most powerful in Mexico.
Its former leader Amado Carrillo Fuentes was known as the "Lord of the Skies" because of the large fleet of jetliners he used to transport cocaine from Colombia to Mexico.
He died while undergoing plastic surgery in 1997, leaving his brother, Vicente, in charge of the cartel.
Arrest comes as government faces criticism
His reported arrest comes a week after another top cartel leader was caught. Authorities said last week that they arrested Hector Beltran Leyva, leader of the Beltran Leyva Cartel, while he was dining in a seafood restaurant in San Miguel de Allende.
The high-profile captures come as Mexican authorities face fierce public criticism over a surge in violence in Iguala, where 43 students went missing during a recent night of shootouts.
On Monday, the government ordered local police to lay down their weapons and sent federal forces to the area, where investigators have found mass graves full of unidentified human remains.
Critics accuse local authorities of involvement in the grisly crime, and say the government hasn't done enough to solve it.
So far, 34 people have been detained in connection with the case, including nearly two dozen local police officers, Mexican Attorney General Jesus Murillo Karam told reporters Thursday.
Hours later at another press conference, Murillo trumpeted news of Carrillo Fuentes' capture as the "result of enormous effort by the federal government," noting that it shows how much authorities have strengthened their abilities in investigation and intelligence.
"He was one of the most important of the most important that Mexican justice had to capture," he said.
CNN en Espaol's Fidel Gutierrez and Danny Guerra contributed to this report.
</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141009172838-carillo-fuentes-restricted-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>What to tell your kid about Christopher Columbus</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/opinion/perry-columbus-day-what-to-tell-your-kid/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>David Perry's daughter came home from school with some notions about Columbus
Much of what we think we know about the explorer turns out to be incorrect, Perry says
Perry: Columbus didn't prove Earth was round, didn't really "discover" a continent
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>11</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1543</time>
            </date>
            <author>By David M. Perry</author>
            <text>Editor's note: David M. Perry is an associate professor of history at Dominican University in Illinois. He writes regularly at the blog How Did We Get Into This Mess? Follow him on Twitter. The opinions expressed in this commentary are solely those of the author.
(CNN) -- In October 2013, my daughter came home from school excited about Christopher Columbus. He had come to visit her class! During his visit, he told the children that he had figured out the world was round and then bravely led his crew to discover America. Then they all made telescopes.
As a father and history professor, I was caught off-guard. Columbus actually didn't figure out the world was round. He didn't really discover America, either. And telescopes weren't around until about a century after Columbus died. But what do you tell a 5-year-old who has bought into a myth? And how do you do it without constructing an anti-myth, pegging the explorer as one of the most evil people to walk the Earth? What should we tell our children about Columbus?
I asked that question of William Phillips, professor of history at the University of Minnesota and co-author of "The Worlds of Christopher Columbus," and of LeAnne Howe, the Eidson Professor in American Literature at the University of Georgia and an enrolled member of the Choctaw Nation. In both cases, professors started from the same principle: Tell the kids the truth.
The story goes that Columbus had to persevere against the odds to get support for his venture, because everyone but him believed the Earth was flat. This just isn't true. The ancient Greeks proved that the Earth was round about 2,000 years ago, and one even used the shadow of the Earth on the moon during an eclipse to estimate its circumference. The problem for Columbus is that he was bad at math and worse at geography, and everyone with an education knew it.
"He failed to get funding for a long time," Phillips wrote, "because his calculations of the earth were on the small side, he thought that dry land covered more of the sphere than it does, and he believed Japan was some 1500 miles off the coast of China." In other words, most people knew roughly the distance between the west coast of Europe and the east coast of Asia but believed it was filled with a vast ocean in which Columbus would surely die.
Columbus was stubborn. Despite all the evidence to the contrary, he refused to give up his plan, and because he was so stubborn, he kept fighting for funding until he finally broke through to the Queen of Spain. His stubbornness also, as both professors noted, kept him from ever admitting that he hadn't reached Asia. For Columbus, the idea of a whole new continent and unknown peoples just didn't fit his worldview.
The indigenous peoples of the Caribbean, however, were used to hosting strange arrivals from all over the Americas in their towns, according to Howe. Their settlements were decades or even centuries old, built in part on transcontinental trade, and Columbus did not seem so outlandish. These were settled lands with rich societies, not, as often depicted, simple or primitive.
That's one of the real tragedies of the story of Columbus and probably the hardest part to explain to children. The complex indigenous societies of the Americas were decimated by exposure to Old World diseases, crumbling under the weight of epidemic. By the time later waves of settlers arrived in North America, they often found wilderness. It was a new wilderness, born of drastic population decline.
Columbus didn't know that his voyage would spread diseases across the continents, of course, but disease wasn't the only problem. Columbus sailed the ocean blue not for the love of exploration but because he wanted access to Asian gold. Instead, he found marvelous soft cotton, which Howe says was far superior to similar cloth in Europe. He also took slaves for display back home and to work in his conquered lands. Cloth and slavery defined the Columbian exchange from the beginning.
Despite all this, it's not correct to simply demonize Columbus. He was a brave man, launching his ships into an uncertain fate, driven by greed, faith and hope. Like many brave men, he believed very strongly that he knew what he was doing -- even though he was wrong about so many details -- and it's OK to be impressed by his bravery.
Moreover, his voyages had an undeniable historical impact, sparking the great age of Atlantic exploration, trade and eventually colonization by Europeans. In a very real way, this era reshaped the world, the languages we speak, the religions we follow, the foods we eat and the diseases we catch. I don't know if that's a reason to have a school holiday, exactly, but it's definitely worth remembering.
So if your child comes home in the leadup to Columbus Day, like mine did, full of praise for the explorer's bravery and vision, that's a fine place to start, even if he didn't really "discover" the Americas or figure out that the Earth was round. He was, indeed, brave.
But then explain that brave people can do bad things, and worse things can happen without any planning. That's one of the lessons of history.

Read CNNOpinion's new Flipboard magazine.
Follow us on Twitter @CNNOpinion.
Join us on Facebook.com/CNNOpinion.

</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/130205155638-christopher-columbus-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Lightning strike kills 11 in Colombia</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/06/world/americas/colombia-lightning-strike/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: A witness says a ceremonial hut caught fire; "you only heard men screaming"
Military helicopters airlift injured victims for medical treatment
11 members of an indigenous tribe were killed by a lightning strike, authorities say
"Nothing like this has ever happened here," the sister of one victim says
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>7</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1152</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A lightning strike killed 11 members of an indigenous tribe in northern Colombia Monday after an electrical storm broke out during an early morning ritual.
Helicopters airlifted 13 injured people to hospitals for treatment, Gen. German Saavedra told reporters.
The lightning struck around 3 a.m. Monday during a ritual of the Wiwa community's government in the remote Sierra Nevada mountains, CNN affiliate Caracol TV reported.
Bernardo Gil Moscote, a member of the community, told Colombia's El Tiempo newspaper that villagers were gathered in a ceremonial hut to discuss problems the community was facing. He had stepped out to get a drink when he heard crashing thunder that shook the mountains.
One dead, 13 injured after lightning strikes at beach
"When I got back, the hut was on fire," he told the newspaper, "and you only heard men screaming."
Colombian President Juan Manuel Santos tweeted his condolences and said military and police helicopters were evacuating the victims.
"I know that this is normal, that it is something that comes from nature, but nothing like this has ever happened there," said Marta Cecilia Gil, who tearfully told Caracol her brother and brother-in-law died in the lightning strike.
Lightning strikes in Colorado park kill 2 people in 2 days

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Death row inmate freed after nine years in Texas prison</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/08/justice/texas-death-row-convict-freed/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>Manuel Velez was convicted of murdering the year-old child of his girlfriend
But the death sentence is overturned, and a new trial ordered
A judge cites "ineffective assistance of counsel"
"We should be ashamed of the errors that put Manuel on the brink of execution," ACLU says
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>9</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>3</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Michael Martinez, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- An intellectually disabled construction worker was freed Wednesday after nine years in a Texas prison, including four of them on death row, after his initial conviction for murdering a year-old infant was overturned.
Manuel Velez, whose IQ is 65 and who is functionally illiterate in his native Spanish as well as English, was convicted in Brownsville in 2008 for murdering the year-old son of his then-girlfriend. But the American Civil Liberties Union, which represented Velez in his appeal, said Velez was 1,000 miles away working construction in Tennessee when the child was injured.
Velez's initial court-appointed attorneys failed to discover that evidence, and "after his conviction, Manuel received the death penalty, largely because a state prison expert presented false testimony to persuade the jury that Manuel would pose a danger to society if given life without parole instead," the ACLU said.
On Wednesday, an ACLU attorney described Velez, now 49, as an innocent man who was put on death row for a crime he didn't commit.
"Manuel never belonged in prison, let alone on death row waiting to be executed. He is indisputably innocent," Brian Stull of the American Civil Liberties Union's Capital Punishment Project said in a statement. "My joy for him and his family today is tinged with sadness for the years our criminal justice system stole from him, all because he was too poor to afford better counsel than the lawyer the state appointed to him.
"We should be ashamed of the errors that put Manuel on the brink of execution. He is far from the only innocent person to receive a death sentence," Stull said.
Cameron County District Attorney Luis V. Saenz called Stull's statement "factually inaccurate and full of half-truths."
"Nowhere near the child"
Attorneys for the ACLU contended that prosecutor's medical expert's records showed "clear proof that the head injuries the baby sustained occurred when Velez was nowhere near the child," the ACLU said.
During the trial, Velez's court-appointed lawyer also failed to "discover and present the testimony of the many witnesses who said the girlfriend threw, hit, and dropped the baby and abused her children, while Manuel was never physically rough and always peaceful," the ACLU said.
Velez's attorney also "bungled his challenge to the typewritten statement that police persuaded Velez to sign, which said he had mistreated the child," the ACLU said.
In fact, Velez was unable to read the statement, written in English, as he is functionally illiterate in both English and Spanish, the ACLU said. Also, Velez' primary language is Spanish, and he is a seventh-grade dropout, the ACLU said.
Child's mother pleaded guilty
The child's mother, Acela Moreno, also was indicted for intentionally or knowingly causing the death of her son, Angel, by striking the boy's head with a hand or unknown object or against a hard surface in October 2005, according to court papers provided by the ACLU.
Moreno accepted "a plea bargain offer" and pleaded guilty to a lesser charge of intentionally or knowingly causing bodily injury to her son, and she was sentenced to 10 years in prison, the court papers said.
In exchange for the reduced charge, Moreno agreed to testify against Velez, but stated that Velez didn't strike her son on the day he was rushed to the hospital, where the child died two days later, the documents said.
A jury convicted Velez of capital murder and sentenced him to death.
An appeals court reversed the death sentence but affirmed the conviction in 2012, the court papers said.
Saenz, the district attorney, said the Texas Court of Criminal Appeals rejected all but one of the Velez legal team's claims of 45 points of errors in the conviction. That one point of error was the testimony by A.P. Merillat, a prosecution expert on the death penalty.
Opinion: Execution, a 19th-century relic we still can't get right
'Ineffective' defense attorneys
Merillat, a former police officer, was condemned by Texas' highest criminal court in 2012 for giving false testimony, the New York Times reported.
"In October 2008...Mr. Merillat testified that after 10 years of serving life without parole for Capital Murder, an inmate could gain a less restrictive classification from the Texas Department of Justice Institutional Division," Saenz said in a statement.
"In September 2005, Texas Department of Justice Institutional Division changed its regulations and no longer allowed for a less restrictive classification for inmates serving life without the possibility of parole in Capital Murder cases. Based on that testimony, and based on that alone, the Texas Court of Criminal Appeals overturned the punishment of Manuel Velez," Saenz said.
In 2013, Judge Elia Cornejo Lopez granted Velez a new trial "on the grounds of ineffective assistance of counsel because of the actions and conduct by both Hector Villarreal and O. Rene Flores," the court papers said.
Villarreal was deceased at the time of the ruling, and Flores wasn't immediately available for comment Wednesday.
Death penalty facts that may surprise you
Prosecutor's response
The ACLU continued to criticize prosecutors Wednesday, saying that "after Velez's conviction was overturned, and in the face of overwhelming evidence of his innocence, the State refused to dismiss the murder charge against him unless he took a plea," the ACLU said.
Velez pleaded no contest to a lesser charge of injury to a child "rather than face a new trial that could be plagued by the same injustices that sent him to death row," the ACLU said.
But in his statement Wednesday, Saenz pointed out that "at no point did any court, trial or appellate, or any jury make any finding that Mr. Velez was actually innocent of murdering Angel Moreno.
"In fact, every time the issue was brought up, it was found to be without merit. It was and continues to be the position of the Cameron County District Attorney's Office that Manuel Velez did contribute to the death of Angel Moreno, and he was and is being punished for that crime," Saenz said.
DNA frees North Carolina's longest-serving death row resident

</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141008171110-manuel-velez-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>6.2-magnitude quake strikes off coast of Mexico</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/07/world/americas/mexico-earthquake/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <date>
                <day>8</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1926</time>
            </date>
            <author>From Dave Alsup, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A 6.2-magnitude quake struck Tuesday northeast of San Jose Del Cabo, Mexico, the U.S. Geological Survey said.
The earthquake was about 10 kilometers (6.2 miles) deep.
Measuring the magnitude of earthquakes
The epicenter of the quake was off shore, between the Baja California peninsula and mainland Mexico.
There were no immediate reports of damages.
What to know about earthquakes

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Brazil presidential vote headed for runoff</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/05/world/americas/brazil-presidential-election/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: With more than 99% of votes counted, Dilma Rousseff has more than 41% of votes
NEW: Exit polls say she'll face Aecio Neves in a runoff
Rousseff is Brazil's first female President and was once a Marxist rebel
Neves, an economist, is a well known career politician who vows to fight inflation
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>6</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>222</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Shasta Darlington, Catherine E. Shoichet and Ben Brumfield, CNN</author>
            <text>Sao Paulo, Brazil (CNN) -- Brazil's presidential vote is headed for a runoff.
Preliminary election results from the South American country show President Dilma Rousseff in the lead. But she didn't get the majority necessary to win in the first round.
With more than 99% of votes counted, Rousseff had 41.56% of votes, Brazil's Supreme Electoral Court said. Aecio Neves was in second place with 33.60%. And Marina Silva was in third place with 21.30%.
Exit polls Sunday indicated there would be a runoff between Rousseff, the incumbent, and Neves, a center-right candidate. In a poll conducted by the Ibope public research firm, Rousseff won 44% of votes, Neves won 30% and Silva won 22%.
Silva, an environmentalist candidate for the Brazilian Socialist Party, had gained momentum and backing from a growing number of supporters leading up to the vote, with polls before the election placing her in second place.
She joined the race after candidate Eduardo Campos died in a plane crash and was seen as a political outsider who could combat corruption. But while she succeeded in gaining much broader support that polls had initially predicted for her party, her third-place finish puts her out of the running for the presidency.
Rousseff, 66, was once a Marxist rebel who was allegedly tortured in the early 1970s during Brazil's former dictatorship.
With her trademark pixie-short hair style and thick glasses, she became one of most Brazil's most wanted fugitives, branded by some as a "subversive Joan of Arc."
She has a solid track record in running the executive office. Before becoming the country's first female president in 2011, Rousseff, from the Workers' Party, was chief of staff to former President Lula da Silva.
She democratized Brazil's electricity sector through the "Luz Para Todos" (Light for All) program, which made electricity widely available, even in rural areas.
Rousseff presided over the soccer World Cup in Brazil, but she took a lot of political flack over how public money was spent.
Streets filled with hundreds of thousands of demonstrators questioning the morality of pumping so much money into stadiums instead of programs to fight poverty and build infrastructure.
Rousseff defended the spending, saying the vast majority of funds earmarked for infrastructure projects were spent on projects for the nation, not the soccer tournament.
And Rousseff claims that under the presidencies of her predecessor and herself, masses of Brazilians have risen out of poverty.
"We have also mainstreamed into the middle class no less than 42 million people," she has said.
But inflation is now weighing down that progress.
Neves, a 54-year-old economist, is a well-known name and a career politician. His campaign slogan promises reforms to lower inflation and encourage more investment in the country: "The sure path for Brazil to really change."
The pro-business candidate belongs to the Brazilian Social Democratic Party, one of the country's strongest.
His grandfather, Tancredo Neves, was elected to become Brazil's president in 1985 but died before taking office. Neves says he began his political career campaigning at his grandfather's side.
"What motivates me in politics is an enormous love of Brazil, a limitless desire to see things improve, to see Brazil go the right way," he says in a campaign video.
While he'd been trailing in some polls leading up to the election, Neves said the only poll that mattered was Sunday's official vote.
"Let's get to the second round," he said in a YouTube video on Saturday.
Both Rousseff and Neves thanked supporters in speeches Sunday night.
Rousseff has promised her second term will be different, running under the slogan of "New Government, New Ideas."
"Once again, the people have honored me with their trust by giving me victory in the first round," she said.
Em Belo Horizonte, Acio  carregado por populares.#Acio45 https://t.co/jiTEve6YLa
A video posted on Neves' Twitter feed Sunday night showed cheering supporters carrying him as cameras flashed.
This has been one of the tightest election competitions in recent years, and it's likely to intensify in the coming weeks, with both candidates vying for the votes that went to Silva in the first round.
There will be three more weeks of campaigning before the runoff.
CNN's Shasta Darlington reported from Sao Paulo. Catherine E. Shoichet and Ben Brumfield reported and wrote from Atlanta.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Mexican troops head to site of mass graves, where 43 students went missing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/06/world/americas/mexico-iguala-mass-graves-missing-students/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>Mexican federal forces are taking over security in the municipality of Iguala
43 students went missing there more than a week ago, and mass graves were found
"I am outraged and troubled by this situation," Mexico's President says
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>7</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>207</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Catherine E. Shoichet, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Federal troops are on the way to a southern Mexican town where 43 students went missing, and local police have been ordered to lay down their weapons.
Mexico's federal Gendarmerie force will take over security in the southern municipality of Iguala along with the Mexican Army, the head of the country's National Security council told reporters Monday.
Monte Alejandro Rubido Garcia, head of the commission, said President Enrique Pea Nieto had ordered the takeover, according to Mexico's state-run Notimex news agency. Mexican Army and Federal Police forces are on the way to the municipality, where authorities are investigating the disappearance of 43 students after a night of violence last month.
Authorities have accused local police of involvement in shootouts the night of September 26, when gunmen opened fire on buses carrying dozens of students and soccer players.
Since then, 43 students from a rural teachers' college have been missing.
Investigators found unmarked mass graves near the town over the weekend, and they say the graves could be connected to the case. State prosecutors say the remains of at least 28 people were in the graves, but the bodies were covered with gasoline and burned before they were buried, and it could take months to identify them.
La @PoliciaFedMx traslada contingente a #Iguala #Guerrero para realizar tareas de seguridad. pic.twitter.com/0IDYAnwTrq
On their Twitter account Monday, Mexican Federal Police posted a photograph of vehicles on the way to Iguala, lights flashing.
The case has drawn widespread attention and sharp criticism of officials in Iguala and Mexico's Guerrero state.
"Like all of Mexican society, I am outraged and troubled by this situation, and I assure you there will not be impunity," Pea Nieto said in a Twitter post Monday.
Mexico's Attorney General's Office also said Monday that it was forming a special team to investigate the students' disappearance.
CNNMexico.com contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Are missing students in mass graves found near Iguala, Mexico?</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/05/world/americas/mexico-mass-graves-missing-students/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: The remains of at least 28 people were inside mass graves, an official says
Authorities found the near area where dozens went missing in southern Mexico
43 students studying to be school teachers disappeared after a series of shootouts
Authorities offer a reward of 1 million pesos for information to find them
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>6</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1216</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Catherine E. Shoichet and Krupskaia Alis, CNN</author>
            <text>Read this story in Spanish at CNNMexico.com
(CNN) -- Gunmen opened fire at buses carrying students and soccer players in southern Mexico.
It's been more than a week since that violent night of shootouts in Iguala, Mexico. Authorities say three students were among six people killed in the September 26 violence, and 43 students remain missing.
Where are they? Authorities and witnesses fear they may be close to unraveling the mystery.
Along a dirt road in a remote part of Mexico's Guerrero state, authorities turned up unmarked graves full of human remains on Saturday.
Investigators found the remains of at least 28 people inside the graves, Guerrero State Attorney General Iaky Blanco Cabrera told reporters Sunday. The bodies were covered in gasoline and burned before they were buried, he said, and it could take between two weeks and two months to identify them.
A tip from suspects detained after the shootouts led them to the grave sites, authorities said.
The missing students, who were studying to become school teachers at Escuela Normal Rural de Ayotzinapa, were mostly young men in their 20s, according to a website state government officials have set up to help in the search.
"Help us find them!" the website says, offering a reward of 1 million pesos ($74,000) for information leading to the missing students.
State officials, who've faced sharp criticism over the students' disappearance, released a statement Sunday detailing their investigative efforts. So far more than 30 people have been detained, including 22 local police officers.
The police have denied attacking anyone, according to a government statement on their detention.
But protesters from the school have said officials aren't doing enough.
"NOW IT IS MORE DANGEROUS TO BE A STUDENT THAN A CRIMINAL," one post on a Facebook page dedicated to the school said.
Witnesses have accused police of orchestrating and participating in the shootings.
"The goal of the police was to kill any person that was inside the perimeter they had," one student from the school told CNN en Espaol.
Guerrero state Gov. Angel Aguirre has defended his government's response and called for calm in the face of protests.
"To the family and friends of those who were savagely massacred, I offer all my solidarity and support," he said in a series of Twitter post Saturday. "It would be highly condemnable, those who want to take advantage or politically profit from a situation like the one that today overwhelms and saddens us."
A bus carrying members of the third division Chilpancingo Hornets soccer club was also among those ambushed in what authorities described as three attacks on September 26. A 15-year-old player on the team was killed.
Omar Sanchez, one of his teammates, described the ambush to CNN en Espaol.
"We were just watching a movie and we saw the bullets come in and then it was like we were going off a cliff and the bus tipped over. And it was then that they started firing at us with machine guns," he said. "It sounded so ugly, the gunshots and my teammates screaming, 'Help, leave us alone, we are injured.' A teacher said, 'you have already blinded me, please, we are the team from Chilpancingo."
The armed men said they weren't going anywhere, ordering the team to open the door.
"Now you are going to be taken, we are going to kill all of you," the gunmen said, according to Sanchez.
When the teacher refused to open the door, Sanchez said, the men opened fire again.
The case has left many troubling questions unanswered. Key among them: Who gave the orders to open fire, and what was their motive?
State prosecutors first said last week that the violence started after the college students commandeered three buses, and city police opened fire.
Since then, evidence has tied the Guerreros Unidos criminal group, and police connected with them, to the shooting and the students' disappearance, Blanco told reporters Saturday.
In 2013: 54 bodies found in mass graves in Mexico
For years Guerrero state, which includes Iguala and the well-known resort city of Acapulco, has ranked among the Mexican states with the highest homicide rates, a crime statistic regularly used by officials and analysts when discussing the overall security situation.
Figures released by Mexico's National Statistics and Geography Institute last year painted a grim picture of kidnapping throughout the country.
A survey revealed that there were more than 105,000 kidnappings nationwide in 2012, the institute said, but only about 1,300 of them were reported to authorities.
CNNMexico.com contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Former Haitian dictator 'Baby Doc' Duvalier dies at 63</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/04/world/americas/jean-claude-duvalier-death/index.html?hpt=ila_c2</url>
            <highlits>Jean-Claude "Baby Doc" Duvalier has died of a heart attack
He ruled Haiti with an iron fist from 1971 to 1986
He fled Haiti, was accused of human rights violations, but evaded prosecution
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>5</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>3</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Mariano Castillo, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Former Haitian dictator Jean-Claude Duvalier died of a heart attack in Port-au-Prince at the age of 63, a family member told CNN Saturday.
Known by his nickname "Baby Doc," the so-called "President for life" actually fled Haiti in 1986 and stunned Haiti when he returned 25 years later.
He was charged with human rights crimes within days of his return, but he successfully argued in court that the statute of limitations had expired on charges that included torture, rape and extrajudicial killings.
Human rights groups decried the court ruling that spared Duvalier.
In February, a Haitian appeals court ruled that the lower court was wrong and that there is no statute of limitations for human rights violations. The ruling reopened the possibility that Duvalier could face such charges, but he died before a judicial investigation decided whether to pursue the charges.
Duvalier inherited the title of "President for life" in 1971 upon the death of his father, Francois "Papa Doc" Duvalier, who had ruled with an iron fist through his paramilitary force, the Tonton Macoute.
Just 19 years old when he came to power, Baby Doc became one of the world's youngest heads of state.
Haitians initially celebrated his ascension, thinking the young man would be less oppressive than his father, but that didn't turn out to be the case.
Duvalier used his father's security apparatus to continue ruling in a totalitarian fashion.
Fast facts on Duvalier
His 15 years of rule were a time of repression in Haiti that included the torture of opponents and the taking of political prisoners.
In addition, there were allegations that "Baby Doc" embezzled hundreds of millions of dollars.
Human Rights Watch and Amnesty International had documented what they call systematic human rights violations under Duvalier's rule. Both organizations accuse Duvalier of imprisoning and torturing hundreds of Haitians, including journalists, and using violent means to silence voices of opposition.
2012: Human rights groups denounce Duvalier decision
Amnesty gave the public prosecutor in the Duvalier case 100 documents that it said detailed cases of human rights violations.
Amnesty International's documents told the experiences of cobblers, taxi drivers, filmmakers, mechanics, distillers and even hairdressers, all of whom, they say, were arrested for anti-government activity.
Notable deaths in 2014
CNN's Pierre Meilhan and Moni Basu contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-middle-east">
        <news>
            <title>ISIS states its justification for the enslavement of women</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/meast/isis-justification-slavery/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>In an online magazine, the terror group says it is legitimate under Islamic law
The Muslim world at large repudiates that interpretation as a perversion of Islam
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1702</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Salma Abdelaziz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- In a new publication, ISIS justifies its kidnapping of women as sex slaves citing Islamic theology, an interpretation that is rejected by the Muslim world at large as a perversion of Islam.
"One should remember that enslaving the families of the kuffar -- the infidels -- and taking their women as concubines is a firmly established aspect of the Shariah, or Islamic law," the group says in an online magazine published Sunday.
The title of the article sums up the ISIS point of view: "The revival (of) slavery before the Hour," referring to Judgment Day.
The fourth edition of the group's English-language digital magazine called "Dabiq" said that female members of the Yazidi sect, an ethnically Kurdish minority living mostly in Iraq, may legitimately be captured and forcibly made concubines or sexual slaves.
The rationalization for a return to slavery -- repudiated around the world -- coincided with the release of a Human Rights Watch report on crimes committed by ISIS against the Yazidis in Iraq based on interviews with 76 displaced people in Dohuk.
"The Islamic State's litany of horrific crimes against the Yazidis in Iraq only keeps growing," said Fred Abrahams, special adviser at Human Rights Watch. "We heard shocking stories of forced religious conversions, forced marriage, and even sexual assault and slavery -- and some of the victims were children."
A 17-year-old kidnapped girl named Adlee recounts how a large bearded man forced her into a home in Falluja, where she was beaten and endured violent sexual advances before escaping two days later, the Human Rights Watch report reads.
ISIS forced tens of thousands of Yazidis to flee their homes in August when the extremists stormed many of the community's towns and cities in Iraqi Kurdistan. Displaced families and monitoring groups reported jihadists kidnapped hundreds of Yazidi women and girls, and many were sold or given away to militants as "spoils of war."
The terror group's 56-page propaganda publication also boasts of a "massacre against (Kurdish) PKK soldiers" alongside graphic images of slain men dressed in fatigues. On the next page, ISIS glorifies its "Services for Muslims" with photographs of a care home for the elderly and a cancer treatment center for children.
The issue, titled "The Failed Crusade," includes an alleged copy of slain American journalist Steven Sotloff's last letter to his mother and says the victim's Jewish identity warranted his beheading by ISIS.
Another ISIS captive, British journalist John Cantlie, allegedly pens the last section of the magazine, saying he expects to be killed soon, and "unless something changes very quickly and very radically, I await my turn."

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Blasts target government in Iraqi Kurdish town, killing 20 people</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/meast/iraq-explosions/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>113 people are injured, and many are in critical condition, a hospital source says
At least 20 killed in Qarah Tabeh, Iraq, which is under Kurdish control
Blasts target high-security complex in town in Diyala province
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1624</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Yousuf Basil, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- At least 20 people were killed and dozens more wounded in series of explosions in the Iraqi town of Qarah Tabeh on Sunday, police said.
The blasts targeted a high-security complex in the town under Kurdish control in Diyala province.
A medical source at Diyala hospital said at least 113 people were wounded in the explosions and added that many of them are in critical condition.
Government bureaus, the mayor's office, a police station and the offices of the two main Kurdish political parties are in the complex, provincial police said.
The explosions happened in short succession.
On Saturday, at least 43 people were killed and more than 40 injured in three car bombings in Baghdad.
Those attacks took place in Shia neighborhoods, sources said.
Pakistani airstrikes kill at least 21 militants
Kareem Khadder in Baghdad contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Rebuilding Gaza could cost $4 billion; reconstruction conference kicks off</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/meast/egypt-gaza-reconstruction/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: U.N. secretary-general: "The cycle of building and destroying must end"
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry announces additional contribution of $212 million
The Palestinian Authority says rebuilding Gaza after this year's conflict will cost $4 billion
Egypt and Norway are hosting a conference in Cairo to help raise the funds needed
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1734</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Chandrika Narayan and Ben Brumfield, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon made an urgent plea as a donor conference to rebuild Gaza kicked off Sunday morning in Cairo.
"The cycle of building and destroying must end," Ban said in his opening remarks. "Donors may be fatigued, but the people of Gaza are bruised and bloody. Enough is enough."
He said he hoped this would be the last Gaza reconstruction conference.
"It is time to chart a course to a just and final peace between Israelis and Palestinians -- one that addresses all the outstanding issues," he said.
The U.N. chief plans to visit Gaza on Tuesday to listen directly to its people and survey the situation. He will also visit Israel.
Rebuilding Gaza after this year's conflict with Israel will cost $4 billion, says the Palestinian Authority, which is presenting a reconstruction plan Sunday.
The governments of Egypt and Norway are hosting the Cairo conference to help raise the funds needed, according to Egypt's Foreign Affairs Ministry.
Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas and Deputy Prime Minister Mohammad Mustafa will be joined by some of the world's most powerful diplomats, including the foreign ministers of Japan, France and Italy.
They will speak about the challenges of rebuilding and how to approach the international response.
Multiple global aid organizations are also participating.
Officials announce aid to Gaza
U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry announced an additional $212 million in aid to rebuild Gaza, shortly after he arrived in Cairo early Sunday.
The money doubles the amount already pledged, bringing the total U.S. contribution to $414 million.
Kerry said that raising funds should not be the only goal of the conference.
"I say clearly and with deep conviction here today, the United States remains fully and totally committed to returning to negotiations not just for the sake of it, but because the goal of this conference and the future of the region demand it," he said.
He called for long-term investments in the Palestinian economy to create a vibrant private sector.
Qatar announced a $1 billion dollar donation Sunday.
"Well, I think it won't simply be Qatar pledging money; all the other Arab countries will pledge money as well," former British Prime Minister Tony Blair, a Middle East Quartet representative, told CNN's Becky Anderson. He said the money would go through the right channels.
"If the Palestinian Authority as envisaged are in charge of that process of reconstruction, this money will go through them, will go through a proper treasury account properly administered," Blair said. "So we are taking a lot of painstaking efforts to make sure the money goes for the purpose for which it was intended and goes to benefit the people in Gaza."
The Quartet is an informal diplomatic group made up of officials from the United States, United Nations, European Union and Russia. It aims to promote Middle East peace and Palestinian development.
Israeli response
Israel was not invited to the conference, but that does not mean that it wants to prevent the reconstruction of Gaza, Israeli Foreign Minister Avigdor Lieberman said in an interview with Israel Radio on Sunday
Lieberman said that it was important that funds raised in Cairo not be used to produce weapons or build tunnels in Gaza.
He added that it was up to Palestinians to prevent another operation in Gaza.
"We are not looking for adventures, but if the rocket is renewed, Israel has a right to defend itself," he said.
Operation Protective Edge
Israel launched Operation Protective Edge in Gaza in July, saying the military operation was aimed at stopping Hamas rocket attacks and destroying a network of tunnels that extended under the border with Israel.
More than 2,130 Palestinians, mostly civilians, were killed in Gaza during the 50 days of fighting that followed. The United Nations estimates that more than 70% were civilians, but Israel reports a higher number of militants among the dead.
Sixty-eight people were killed on the Israeli side, two of whom were civilians.
Many homes, schools and other buildings in Gaza were destroyed or damaged before a ceasefire was reached in late August.
The United Nations estimates that 60,000 Gazans were still living in shelters in late September.
CNN's Michael Schwartz in Jerusalem contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Baghdad car bombs kill 43 in Shia neighborhoods</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/11/world/meast/baghdad-car-bombs/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <date>
                <day>12</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1652</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Ralph Ellis</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- At least 43 people were killed and more than 40 injured in three car-bomb attacks in Baghdad, Iraqi medical sources said Saturday.
The three attacks took place in Shia neighborhoods, the sources said.
One explosion occurred at a checkpoint at the entrance of al-Shaula neighborhood in northern Baghdad, killing a number of Iraqi security forces and injuring others staffing the checkpoint, the sources said.
Another bomb went off at another checkpoint 3 kilometers away at the entrance of al-Kadhimya, also a northern Baghdad neighborhood, the sources said. Iraqi security forces were killed and injured.
The third blast occurred in the al-Mashahda neighborhood.
Blasts target government in Iraqi Kurdish town, killing 20 people
CNN's Kareem Khadder in Baghdad contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Despite public pressure, Turkey says it won't go it alone on ground against ISIS</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/world/meast/isis-threat/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Report: 30 die amid protests; 2 police assessing protest sites also killed
Group: ISIS controls about one-third of Kobani, a Kurdish enclave near the Turkish border
Syrian Kurd: "The massacre is about to happen, and we have to act very ... promptly"
Minister: Turkey will do "its part" against ISIS, but won't dispatch ground troops solo
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>116</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark and Greg Botelho, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Refusing to buckle to violent protests demanding more action, Turkey's foreign minister insisted Thursday his nation "is on Kobani's side" -- referring to the Syrian border town in imminent danger of falling to ISIS -- but still won't unilaterally send ground troops to save it.
Time may be running out. Smoke rose over Kobani, a Kurdish enclave in Syria that's a stone's throw from the Turkish border, as U.S. warplanes pounded ISIS targets from above while Kurdish fighters tried to fend off the Islamist extremist group from below.
But ISIS isn't backing down. It seems to have wrested control of one-third of Kobani, said the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a London-based monitoring group.
Speaking alongside visiting NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlut Cavusoglu stressed his country vehemently opposed ISIS and its actions in Kobani and elsewhere.
Like it or not, Turkey is already knee deep in the regional unrest, having taken in more than 1.5 million people from Syria and Iraq, including some 200,000 Syrians from the Kobani region in the past two weeks.
Cavusoglu said Turkey supports the U.S.-led airstrikes against ISIS, though he stated these can only be so effective.
"Maybe you can stop them for a short period but you cannot clean the whole region from ISIS or some other terrorist organizations," the foreign minister said. "You need to take into consideration all options, including an operation on the ground."
The group that could help beat ISIS
That's what protesters around Turkey and outside of it have demanded, warning innocent people will be killed in mass -- much like what ISIS has been accused of in many other communities around Syria and Iraq, since it stepped up its armed campaign to take over territory amid Syria's yearslong civil war -- if something drastic isn't done.
There are ongoing talks about what the international approach to the crisis could look like. "Once there is a (common) decision, Turkey will not be reluctant to do its part," Cavusoglu said.
"It is not realistic to expect Turkey to conduct a ground operation on its own," Cavusoglu said.
Who's doing what in the coalition battle
Erdogan lashes out against protests calling for action
This position won't satisfy those who have hit the streets around Turkey in recent days.
They've chanted, marched and clashed with authorities using tear gas and other means.
"We want more airstrikes, we want a clear message," said Rebar Hajo, a Syrian Kurdish politician. "... The massacre is about to happen, and we have to act very ... promptly and intensify our attacks on them."
According to Anadolu, the nation's semiofficial news agency, 30 people have been killed since Wednesday across eight locations during what it calls the "illegal protests." This figure does not include six killed Thursday in Bingol, including two police officers shot while "doing damage assessment from the protests."
Dozens more have been injured in the protests nationwide, including at least three police officers in Istanbul alone.
Agriculture Minister Mehdi Eker said 116 people had been arrested in connection with the violence and another 294 face charges for curfew violations.
President Recep Erdogan criticized the demonstrations, claiming they were tied to connected to the outlawed Kurdistan Workers Party and aimed to "manipulate perceptions of Turkey's policies," according to another Anadolu story. In a statement, he vowed that Turkish authorities will go after those behind "these acts of violence, vandalism and looting."
Turkey's tough choice: Take on ISIS or the PKK?
"Turkey will never tolerate any traps against our peace, stability or sense of brotherhood," Erdogan said.
At the same time, the Turkish government says it stands with Kurds on both sides of the Syrian border unnerved by ISIS' advance.
Cavusoglu rejected the suggestion that Turkey had hung back, saying it has "never acted reluctantly on this issue. "
He also denied "discrimination on a sectarian basis" -- i.e., not choosing to act because Kurds were the primary victims in Kobani -- was in play in Turkey's decisions.
Last week, Parliament passed a resolution last week authorizing action against the terrorist group. The main opposition party, the Republican People's Party, said it will back this motion to authorize the army's ground operations as long as it is limited to rescuing Kobani and repelling ISIS.
Witnesses: ISIS' gets reinforced, situation 'very bad'
If ISIS manages to take Kobani, it will control a complete swath of land between its self-declared capital of Raqqa, Syria, and Turkey -- a stretch of more than 100 kilometers (62 miles).
The United States wants Turkey to do more, U.S. administration officials said, and is urging Turkey to at least fire artillery at ISIS targets across the border.
Witnesses inside Kobani told CNN that airstrikes Wednesday had been welcome but that the situation worsened Thursday.
One fighter said that the situation was "very bad" and that ISIS had received reinforcements, in the form of a "large" number of fighters and vehicles, overnight.
The fighter said ISIS troops have re-entered the eastern side of the city and called for the U.S.-led coalition to launch airstrikes there, where the onslaught is greatest. He said there had been only two strikes Thursday morning.
A media activist also in the town described intense street-to-street fighting around the Kurdish security forces' headquarters, near the center of Kobani, as well as in the south of the town.
He also called for more airstrikes against ISIS, saying the two so far Thursday were not enough.
The U.S. military announced Thursday that it had launched six airstrikes south of Kobani, destroying two buildings, one tank, one heavy machine gun, as well as hitting one large and two small groups of ISIS fighters. Another three airstrikes north of Kobani hit two small ISIS groups and destroyed two buildings.
This was on top of other coalition efforts to go after the Islamist extremist group, including a pair of U.S. airstrikes near Sinjar in Iraq.
Oil and crime make ISIS rich
CNN's Nic Robertson, Hamdi Alkhshali, Ray Sanchez, Ingrid Formanek, Mohammed Tawfeeq and Adam Levine contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Kassig's mother plea to ISIS leader: 'I am an old woman, and (he) is my only child'</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/08/us/isis-captive-kassig/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>In the letter, she says she would like to talk to al Baghdadi
ISIS has threatened to kill Kassig next
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>9</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>2013</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Ed Payne, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Saying she's an "old woman" trying to find out the fate of her only son, the mother of American hostage Abdul-Rahman Kassig has sent a tweet meant for ISIS leader Abu Bakr al Baghdadi.
"I am trying to get in touch with the Islamic State about my son's fate," she says in the tweet, which is a photograph of a letter written to al Baghdadi.
"I am an old woman, and Abdul Rahman is my only child.
"My husband and I are on our own, with no help from the government. We would like to talk to you. How can we reach you?"
A Letter from Abdul-Rahman Kassig's Mother to IS Caliph Al Baghdadi pic.twitter.com/QUXTXluVnY
Abdul-Rahman Kassig, whose given name is Peter, was detained on October 1 in eastern Syria while doing humanitarian work. ISIS has threatened to kill him next.
Since the announcement -- made in an ISIS video showing the apparent beheading of of British aid worker Alan Henning -- Kassig's has issued repeated pleas asking his captors to show mercy and free him.
Over the weekend, they released a YouTube video, imploring his captors to "use their power to let our son go."
Wednesday night, Kassig's parents attended a vigil at Indiana's Butler University, Kassig's alma mater.
'I am an idealist'
Kassig, 26, had already finished a tour in the Middle East as a U.S. Army Ranger stationed in Iraq. But he felt compelled to go back to the region to help Syrians caught in a bloody conflict that has killed roughly 200,000 people
He expressed his fear in captivity in a letter sent to his parents in June.
"I am obviously pretty scared to die, but the hardest part is not knowing, wondering, hoping, and wondering if I should even hope at all," Kassig wrote.

</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Blast kills 47 at Houthi protest in Yemen, officials say</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/world/meast/yemen-violence/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <date>
                <day>9</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1902</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Hakim Almasmari and Jason Hanna, CNN</author>
            <text>Sanaa, Yemen (CNN) -- At least 47 people were killed by an explosion at an anti-government protest by Houthis in Yemen's capital on Thursday, the Yemen health ministry said -- marking just the latest violence during weeks of sectarian and political strife in the country.
The explosion occurred at Sanaa's Tahrir Square, where Houthis -- a religious minority in Yemen -- were engaged in their latest protest against the government, the health ministry said. Eyewitnesses said the explosion came from a suicide bomber who had been near a bank, but the Interior Ministry did not confirm that account.
Houthis, followers of a sect of Shia Islam in a country where Sunni Muslims are the majority, have been protesting for weeks against the government, prompting the resignations of two prime ministers in two weeks.
Among the killed were eight children who participated in the protests, Houthi medical sources said. At least 11 people -- all protesters -- were taken to hospitals in critical condition, the sources said.
No group immediately announced responsibility for the attack, but al Qaeda -- the Sunni Muslim terrorist network -- has for months threatened to kill Houthis after Houthi fighters defeated Sunni tribes in several provinces.
Yemen bombing kills 7 near hospital
Journalist Hakim Almasmari reported and wrote from Sanaa. CNN's Jason Hanna reported and wrote from Atlanta.
</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/141009132448-yemen-explosion-story-top.jpg</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Despite public pressure, Turkey says it won't go it alone on ground against ISIS</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/09/world/meast/isis-threat/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Report: 30 die amid protests; 2 police assessing protest sites also killed
Group: ISIS controls about one-third of Kobani, a Kurdish enclave near the Turkish border
Syrian Kurd: "The massacre is about to happen, and we have to act very ... promptly"
Minister: Turkey will do "its part" against ISIS, but won't dispatch ground troops solo
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>10</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>116</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark and Greg Botelho, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Refusing to buckle to violent protests demanding more action, Turkey's foreign minister insisted Thursday his nation "is on Kobani's side" -- referring to the Syrian border town in imminent danger of falling to ISIS -- but still won't unilaterally send ground troops to save it.
Time may be running out. Smoke rose over Kobani, a Kurdish enclave in Syria that's a stone's throw from the Turkish border, as U.S. warplanes pounded ISIS targets from above while Kurdish fighters tried to fend off the Islamist extremist group from below.
But ISIS isn't backing down. It seems to have wrested control of one-third of Kobani, said the Syrian Observatory for Human Rights, a London-based monitoring group.
Speaking alongside visiting NATO Secretary General Jens Stoltenberg, Turkish Foreign Minister Mevlut Cavusoglu stressed his country vehemently opposed ISIS and its actions in Kobani and elsewhere.
Like it or not, Turkey is already knee deep in the regional unrest, having taken in more than 1.5 million people from Syria and Iraq, including some 200,000 Syrians from the Kobani region in the past two weeks.
Cavusoglu said Turkey supports the U.S.-led airstrikes against ISIS, though he stated these can only be so effective.
"Maybe you can stop them for a short period but you cannot clean the whole region from ISIS or some other terrorist organizations," the foreign minister said. "You need to take into consideration all options, including an operation on the ground."
The group that could help beat ISIS
That's what protesters around Turkey and outside of it have demanded, warning innocent people will be killed in mass -- much like what ISIS has been accused of in many other communities around Syria and Iraq, since it stepped up its armed campaign to take over territory amid Syria's yearslong civil war -- if something drastic isn't done.
There are ongoing talks about what the international approach to the crisis could look like. "Once there is a (common) decision, Turkey will not be reluctant to do its part," Cavusoglu said.
"It is not realistic to expect Turkey to conduct a ground operation on its own," Cavusoglu said.
Who's doing what in the coalition battle
Erdogan lashes out against protests calling for action
This position won't satisfy those who have hit the streets around Turkey in recent days.
They've chanted, marched and clashed with authorities using tear gas and other means.
"We want more airstrikes, we want a clear message," said Rebar Hajo, a Syrian Kurdish politician. "... The massacre is about to happen, and we have to act very ... promptly and intensify our attacks on them."
According to Anadolu, the nation's semiofficial news agency, 30 people have been killed since Wednesday across eight locations during what it calls the "illegal protests." This figure does not include six killed Thursday in Bingol, including two police officers shot while "doing damage assessment from the protests."
Dozens more have been injured in the protests nationwide, including at least three police officers in Istanbul alone.
Agriculture Minister Mehdi Eker said 116 people had been arrested in connection with the violence and another 294 face charges for curfew violations.
President Recep Erdogan criticized the demonstrations, claiming they were tied to connected to the outlawed Kurdistan Workers Party and aimed to "manipulate perceptions of Turkey's policies," according to another Anadolu story. In a statement, he vowed that Turkish authorities will go after those behind "these acts of violence, vandalism and looting."
Turkey's tough choice: Take on ISIS or the PKK?
"Turkey will never tolerate any traps against our peace, stability or sense of brotherhood," Erdogan said.
At the same time, the Turkish government says it stands with Kurds on both sides of the Syrian border unnerved by ISIS' advance.
Cavusoglu rejected the suggestion that Turkey had hung back, saying it has "never acted reluctantly on this issue. "
He also denied "discrimination on a sectarian basis" -- i.e., not choosing to act because Kurds were the primary victims in Kobani -- was in play in Turkey's decisions.
Last week, Parliament passed a resolution last week authorizing action against the terrorist group. The main opposition party, the Republican People's Party, said it will back this motion to authorize the army's ground operations as long as it is limited to rescuing Kobani and repelling ISIS.
Witnesses: ISIS' gets reinforced, situation 'very bad'
If ISIS manages to take Kobani, it will control a complete swath of land between its self-declared capital of Raqqa, Syria, and Turkey -- a stretch of more than 100 kilometers (62 miles).
The United States wants Turkey to do more, U.S. administration officials said, and is urging Turkey to at least fire artillery at ISIS targets across the border.
Witnesses inside Kobani told CNN that airstrikes Wednesday had been welcome but that the situation worsened Thursday.
One fighter said that the situation was "very bad" and that ISIS had received reinforcements, in the form of a "large" number of fighters and vehicles, overnight.
The fighter said ISIS troops have re-entered the eastern side of the city and called for the U.S.-led coalition to launch airstrikes there, where the onslaught is greatest. He said there had been only two strikes Thursday morning.
A media activist also in the town described intense street-to-street fighting around the Kurdish security forces' headquarters, near the center of Kobani, as well as in the south of the town.
He also called for more airstrikes against ISIS, saying the two so far Thursday were not enough.
The U.S. military announced Thursday that it had launched six airstrikes south of Kobani, destroying two buildings, one tank, one heavy machine gun, as well as hitting one large and two small groups of ISIS fighters. Another three airstrikes north of Kobani hit two small ISIS groups and destroyed two buildings.
This was on top of other coalition efforts to go after the Islamist extremist group, including a pair of U.S. airstrikes near Sinjar in Iraq.
Oil and crime make ISIS rich
CNN's Nic Robertson, Hamdi Alkhshali, Ray Sanchez, Ingrid Formanek, Mohammed Tawfeeq and Adam Levine contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Diplomat: Syria has four chemical weapons facilities it didn't disclose</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/07/world/meast/syria-chemical-weapons/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>Investigators also detail August chlorine attack allegations
"All fingers point to Assad," U.S. ambassador says
A U.N. special envoy briefs the Security Council on lingering chemical weapons
Syria has four chemical weapons facilities it didn't previously disclose
</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>8</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1308</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Lorenzo Ferrigno, Ann Roche and Richard Roth, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Syria has four chemical weapons facilities that it did not previously disclose to the United Nations, a Western diplomat told CNN on Tuesday.
The diplomat said Sigrid Kaag, the U.N. special envoy overseeing the destruction of Syria's chemical stockpiles, briefed the U.N. Security Council.
Three of the sites are research and development facilities and one is a production facility, according to the source.
Syria disclosed the information during ongoing meetings between the Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons and Syrian authorities, Kaag told the council members, according to the source.
UN's @SigridKaag said 4 facilities identified that regime failed to declare. Must keep pressure on regime so it doesn't hide CW capability.
U.S. Ambassador to the United Nations Samantha Power tweeted shortly after: "Must keep pressure on regime so it doesn't hide (chemical weapons) capability."
In August 2013, U.N. spokesman Martin Nesirky told reporters that a team of experts had gathered to go to Syria to investigate reports of chemical weapons.
In September 2013, U.N. Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon released the inspectors' report, which says there was "clear and convincing evidence" that sarin, a nerve agent developed for chemical warfare, was used in a Damascus attack.
Later that month, the U.N. Security Council passed a resolution requiring Syria to eliminate its chemical weapons arsenal, and President Bashar al-Assad promised to adhere to the resolution. The following month, Syria began dismantling its chemical weapons program.
In July, 600 metric tons of chemical weapons from Syria were transferred to a U.S. ship for destruction in what marked the demise of the last of the country's declared chemical weapons stockpiles.
At the time, officials said it was a major milestone.
But inspectors have said they couldn't say for sure whether some undeclared weapons were still lurking somewhere in the country.
And in August, there were new allegations of chlorine attacks, officials said. After inspectors' findings were detailed in Tuesday's closed-door Security Council briefing, diplomats took to Twitter with statements that echoed accusations aimed at the Syrian government a year ago.
"Witnesses of chlorine gas attacks described them as carried out by helicopters, which only Syrian regime has. All fingers point to Assad," Power said.
Connect the dots: @OPCW sure chlorine used in #Syria, witnesses saw it dropped by helicopters,which only Assad has. Who's responsible? #UNSC
"Connect the dots: @OPCW sure chlorine used in #Syria, witnesses saw it dropped by helicopters, which only Assad has. Who's responsible? #UNSC," the Lithuanian mission to the United Nations, a current member of the Security Council, tweeted.
The Syrian mission to the United Nations did not immediately respond to CNN.
Asked about the revelation of additional Syrian chemical weapons facilities, State Department spokeswoman Jen Psaki pointed to a recent statement from Secretary of State John Kerry, which said the United States was "gravely concerned" about the recent reports of chlorine attacks in Syria.
"This finding, coupled with deep concerns regarding the accuracy and completeness of Syria's declaration to the (Organization for the Prohibition of Chemical Weapons), raises especially troubling concerns that continued chemical attacks on the Syrian people by the regime could occur," Kerry said last month.
CNN's Ashley Fantz, Ben Brumfield, Diana Magnay and Catherine E. Shoichet contributed to this report.
</text>
        </news>
    </region>
</regions>
