<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<regions>
    <region area="nav-world">
        <news>
            <title>Chinese court sentences cult members to death over McDonald's killing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/asia/china-eastern-lightning-death-sentence/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>Five members of a Chinese cult have been sentenced for a murder in a McDonald's Two were sentenced to death for the killing of a woman who refused to give them her number The group, Church of Almighty God, has been banned in China since 1995 Its members believe Jesus has been reincarnated as a Chinese woman</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>809</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Two members of a banned Chinese doomsday cult were sentenced to death Saturday for the brutal murder of a woman in a McDonald's restaurant in May, Chinese state media reported. Zhang Fan and Zhang Lidong were among five members of the Church of Almighty God, or "Quannengshen," tried on murder charges in August over the killing in Zhaoyuan, Shandong Province, the state-run Xinhua agency reported. Three fellow cult members, Lyu Yingchun, Zhang Hang and Zhang Qiaolian, were sentenced to life, 10 and seven years in prison respectively for their roles in the attack. The four Zhangs were related, according to the report. A court statement said the victim, a 37-year-old woman named Wu Shuoyan, was attacked after refusing to give her phone number to the group, who were allegedly attempting to recruit new members. Zhang Fan and Lyu called her an "evil spirit," before Zhang bludgeoned her head with a chair, then jumped on her and trampled her head, the statement said. Zhang Lidong bashed the victim's head with a mop hard enough to break it, and stomped on her face and head, while Lyu kicked her waist and prevented McDonald's staff from intervening, the court statement said. IN DEPTH: 'Eastern Lightning,' the banned religious group that has China worried Linked to kidnappings, violence and extortion, the Church of Almighty God has been on a list of 14 banned religious groups issued by China's Ministry of Public Security since 1995. Founded in the 1990s in Henan Province, the group believes that Jesus has been reincarnated as Yang Xiangbin, the wife of the group's founder, Zhao Weishan. The couple fled to the United States in 2000, Xinhua reported. The group, also known as Eastern Lightning ("Dongfang Shandian"), preaches that the righteous are engaged in an apocalyptic struggle against China's Communist Party -- which it refers to as the "great red dragon." Belonging to a tradition of heterodox, quasi-Christian Chinese religious movements, the cult was estimated as having between several hundred thousand and one million members, according to Emily Dunn, an Asian studies academic at the University of Melbourne who wrote her doctoral thesis on the group. In August, Chinese state media reported that police had arrested nearly 1,000 suspected members of the group, including nearly 100 "backbone members." The report said those arrested were responsible for "numerous" suicides and murders, including those of their own family. In 2012, hundreds of members were rounded up after the group publicly proclaimed the end of the world was imminent. In a statement provided to CNN in June, Hong Kong-based members of the group responsible for its English-language website said it was "very natural" for the Chinese Communist Party to blame the group for the McDonald's death because the party slandered and then suppressed those that disagreed with it. "They always find some excuse in advance and fabricate things and slander them," said the statement. READ MORE: The future of Christianity in China CNN's Dayu Zhang and Katie Hunt contributed to this report.</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140604013136-eastern-lightning-split-story-top.png</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Oscar Pistorius a 'broken man,' psychologist says at sentencing hearing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/africa/south-africa-pistorius-sentencing/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Oscar Pistorius "will be able to love somebody else," prosecutor says The judge in his case cleared him of murder but found him guilty of culpable homicide There is no legal minimum or maximum term for culpable homicide Pistorius will also be sentenced on one weapons-related charge involving a restaurant shooting</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1359</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Laura Smith-Spark and Faith Karimi, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Oscar Pistorius is a "broken man" after the death of his girlfriend, a psychologist said Monday, as his defense used a sentencing hearing to try to convince a judge of his fragile emotional state. Dr. Lore Hartzenberg said the Olympian described his girlfriend, Reeva Steenkamp, as the love of his life. He lost faith in himself and his abilities after the killing, she said. But the prosecution dismissed her findings. "We're dealing with a broken man, but he's still alive," Prosecutor Gerrie Nel said in an apparent reference to the fact that Steenkamp is not. "He has lost his love relationship ... but he will be able to love somebody else like that." What would Pistorius face if he's sent to prison New woman? Nel questioned the psychologist about a woman the Olympian allegedly started seeing after the death of his girlfriend. Hartzenberg said she's not aware of his new relationship, and the two never discussed it during their sessions. The onetime South African sporting hero was found guilty of negligent killing last month in Steenkamp's death. The hearing that will determine whether he's going to prison began Monday and is scheduled to continue Tuesday. Joel Maringa, a social worker at the South Africa Department of Correctional Services, recommended "correctional supervision" rather than prison time. His report was at the request of the defense. Guilty of culpable homicide Judge Thokozile Masipa, who presided over Pistorius' high-profile trial and delivered the verdict last month, will decide his sentence. Pistorius was found guilty of culpable homicide, the South African term for unintentionally, but unlawfully, killing a person. However, the judge cleared him of murder in Steenkamp's death and granted him bail pending the sentencing hearing. The hearing is likely to take several days, as the prosecution and defense put their arguments before the court. There is no legal minimum sentence for culpable homicide in South African law, so it will be up to the judge to decide. A typical sentence is five to eight years. But it is a principle of South African law that the sentence should be tailored to the culprit as a whole person, as opposed to the crime. That makes predicting a sentence difficult, said Kelly Phelps, a CNN legal analyst. The judge also found Pistorius guilty of one weapons-related charge involving a shooting at a restaurant. The maximum penalty for that is five years behind bars. But he could get a lesser sentence, such as a fine or the loss of his gun license. What would prison life be like? If Pistorius is sent to prison, it's unclear whether his disability would allow him any special treatment. And daily life behind bars probably would not be easy. Born with a congenital abnormality, he had his legs amputated below the knee before his first birthday and uses prosthetic limbs to get around. The carbon-fiber blades he used to compete on the track -- before Steenkamp's killing abruptly halted his running career -- earned him the nickname "Blade Runner." During his trial, his defense highlighted his vulnerability when on his stumps and a court-ordered psychiatric assessment found he was depressed, suffering from post-traumatic stress and a suicide risk. South Africa's prisons are notorious for overcrowding, which puts a strain on sanitation, ventilation and medical care for inmates. Pistorius probably would receive far better treatment than the average prisoner, as he has throughout the judicial process, said Nooshin Erfani-Ghadimi, project coordinator for the Johannesburg-based Wits Justice Project, a civil society group. Even so, she said, it will not make much difference. "I don't think anyone with a disability necessarily will be able to be provided for at the moment in a way that ensures that they would have the correct medical treatment, that they have the correct physical structures," she said. Steenkamp: model and law graduate with 'wicked' sense of humor 'Conduct was negligent' Pistorius, 27, has always admitted firing the bullets that killed Steenkamp, 29, a model and reality TV star. He pleaded not guilty to murdering her in his home on Valentine's Day last year, saying he mistook her for an intruder. But in grabbing his gun and heading toward the supposed threat, Pistorius "acted too hastily and used excessive force," the judge ruled last month. "His conduct was negligent" and not what a reasonable man would do in the circumstances -- not even a disabled one, she said. Who is 'Blade Runner' Oscar Pistorius? Appeals process Pistorius can appeal the verdict or the sentence, potentially to the Supreme Court of Appeal and even eventually to the South African Constitutional Court. The state can appeal only if it believes the judge misinterpreted the law in reaching her verdict. The right to appeal depends on whether, based on the facts of the case, the initial judge or magistrate believes a different court could possibly reach a different verdict. CNN's Emily Smith and Richard Allen Greene contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Taliban attack on military convoy kills 14 Afghan soldiers and police</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/asia/afghanistan-attacks/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>Insurgents strike a military convoy in northern Afghanistan and kill 14 people, officials say 200 Taliban fighters attack 180 Afghan forces in a remote part of Sar-e-Pul province Taliban capture six soldiers, Afghan forces kill 23 Taliban in the fighting, officials say A suicide car bomb in Wardak province kills 14 people, including nine civilians</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1444</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Susanna Capelouto and Masoud Popalzai, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Taliban insurgents have killed 14 Afghan National Security forces, including two policemen, in northern Afghanistan, government officials said. About 180 Afghan security forces were traveling in a convoy Sunday when more than 200 Taliban fighters attacked them in a very remote part of Sar-e-Pul province, Gov. Abdul Jabar Haqbeen told CNN. The Taliban captured six soldiers, 17 others were injured, and 23 Taliban insurgents were killed in the fighting, Haqbeen said. Also on Sunday, a suicide attack in Wardak province killed 14 people, including nine civilians, a province spokesman said. A car full of explosives blew up near an Afghan National Army vehicle, according to Wardak officials. Two other vehicles with civilians were also destroyed in the blast, and six people were injured, officials said. Drone strikes kill 8 in Afghanistan, Pakistan Mohammad Ehsan Popalzai contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Scuffles as protest opponents try to tear down Hong Kong barricades</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/china-hong-kong-protest/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Scuffles as people opposing occuption try to remove protest barricades Democracy campaigners have been blocking key routes through the city C.Y. Leung: Protests a "mass movement that has spun out of control" Students write open letter to Chinese President Xi Jinping</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>852</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Hilary Whiteman, CNN</author>
            <text>Hong Kong (CNN) -- Rowdy scenes erupted at the main Occupy Central protest site in Hong Kong on Monday after hundreds of people opposing the pro-democracy occupation tried to tear down protest barricades. Police formed a human chain to separate the protesters and people intent on breaking up their three-week long occupation of the Admiralty district, near the city's financial center. Dozens of men, some wearing surgical masks, were seen jostling with protesters and demanding that police remove the barricades and clear the roads, according to live images from local television station iCable. They were heard screaming at protesters, accusing them of damaging their livelihoods. The television commentator identified them as taxi drivers, transport industry workers and other people who said they weren't affiliated with any groups. However, protesters could be heard yelling, "there are triads here," a reference to criminal gangs in the city known for controlling smuggling, prostitution and illegal gambling rings. Police on loudspeakers called for calm, and eventually convinced protesters to form a corridor to allow their opponents to leave. Earlier, police started to remove barricades from protest sites in Admiralty and Mong Kok, but issued a statement saying they were moving "obstacles" to relieve traffic "not to clear the scene." Police "pushed back a couple of barricades, dismantling them," said CNN's Ivan Watson, from the Admiralty protest site. He said the protesters had responded by moving their tents closer to the barrier but the streets had remained peaceful. READ: Who is C.Y. Leung? Protest disruption At the peak of the protests, which started in late September, tens of thousands of demonstrators crowded onto the streets demanding a greater say in how the city is run. Protesters have been guarding barricades erected at the protest sites, and for many nights slept in the open air on bitumen before the arrival of reinforcements with tents on the weekend. Traffic in the other parts of the city has been clogged due to road closures, bus and tram cancellations and the need for cars to drive around the protest sites. Taxi drivers say their takings are down, and businesses have claimed the protests have cost them income. While protest numbers dwindled towards the end of last week, they started building again over the weekend when protest leaders called for reinforcements after the government called off talks planned for Friday. First live address Over the weekend, Hong Kong Chief Executive C.Y. Leung made his first live address since protesters blocked key routes through the city. Speaking on local free-to-air station TVB, Leung said the protests were not a "revolution," but a "mass movement that has spun out of control." He said student leaders had "almost zero chance" of pushing Beijing to chance its stance on how Hong Kong's leader is elected. He added he would not accede to the protesters' demands that he resign, because his resignation "will not solve the problem." "It is because the students and other occupation protesters demand more than that. They want the Standing Committee to withdraw its August 31 decision. That is impossible," he said. READ: Who's who in the protests? Beijing white paper He was referring to the white paper issued by the Standing Committee of China's National People's Congress stating that Hongkongers would be able to vote on their leader in 2017, but only from an approved shortlist of candidates. In response to Leung's comments, the three main groups leading the occupy campaign said it was the government that was out of control -- "a government that fires tear-gas at unarmed citizens and unilaterally terminated dialogue with the students (sic)." On September 28, police fired 87 tear gas rounds into the crowd after protesters failed to disperse. The move was seen as a miscalculation and only served to garner support for the protesters who accused the government of heavy handedness and of stifling free speech. READ: The end of police trust? Open letter to China Over the weekend, student leaders from protest group Scholarism and the Hong Kong Federation of Students wrote an open letter to Chinese President Xi Jinping, urging him to closely consider their cause. "There will only be more citizens, disillusioned with our corrupted institutions, marching and protesting, as long as no genuine democracy is practiced in this place," they wrote. The letter said the occupation was "definitely not a colour revolution or its alike, but rather a movement for democracy," referring to the term "umbrella revolution" which was coined after protesters used umbrellas to shield themselves from pepper spray and tear gas. View from China Xi has not commented on the protests, but Chinese censors have been busy blocking reports of the movement, including access to the photo-sharing site Instagram. A commentary published in China's state-controlled People's Daily on Monday, entitled "Why is the U.S. so keen on Color Revolutions?", accused the U.S. of meddling in Hong Kong affairs. "It is hardly likely that the U.S. will admit to manipulating the "Occupy Central" movement, just as it will not admit to manipulating other anti-China forces. It sees such activities as justified by "democracy," "freedom," "human rights" and other values," it said. It said the mainstream U.S. media had shown "exceptional interest" in "Occupy Central" and had tried to portray it as Hong Kong's version of a "Color Revolution," referring to pro-democracy movements around the world including the "Arab Spring" and Ukraine's "Orange Revolution." "The U.S. may enjoy the sweet taste of interfering in other countries' internal affairs, but on the issue of Hong Kong it stands little chance of overcoming the determination of the Chinese government to maintain stability and prosperity," it added. CNN's Wilfred Chan and Anjali Tsui contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Vongfong slams into Kyushu, continues destructive path across Japan</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/tropical-storm-vongfong-japan/index.html?hpt=wo_c2</url>
            <highlits>Tropical Storm Vongfong hits Kyushu, the southernmost of Japan's four main islands At least 36 injuries have been reported Japan's four main islands are expected to get up to 40cm of rain</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1408</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Junko Ogura and Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>Tokyo (CNN) -- The latest and strongest in a string of powerful storms to hit Japan -- Vongfong -- slammed into Kyushu, the southernmost of the country's four main islands, Monday morning as it continued its destructive path across the country. Vongfong first made landfall in Japan in Okinawa early Sunday. It wreaked havoc across the prefecture, knocking out power before losing strength and being downgraded from a typhoon to a tropical storm. Meteorologists expect the storm to pass over the country's largest island, Honshu, hitting the capital, Tokyo, before dawn on Tuesday. At least 36 injuries related to the storm were reported across Okinawa, Kagoshima and Miyazaki prefectures, officials said, while at least 44,000 across the country were without power. Authorities have ordered more than 100,000 people to evacuate their homes. Police in Shizuoka said one man remained missing after three people were swept into water on Sunday at the city's port. Although a high-wave advisory had been issued at the time of the accident, the incident was classified as a water accident and not officially linked to the storm, according to Shizuoka police. Flights in and out of Kyushu and neighboring Shikoku were canceled Monday, along with local ferry and train operations. The Japan Meteorological Agency said Vongfong was expected to bring up to 40 centimeters of rain. The storm comes on the heels of Typhoon Phanfone, which swept over southern Japan last week, washing three U.S. airmen out to sea off Okinawa. U.S. and Japanese search crews found the last airman's body on Wednesday, according to a news release issued by authorities at Kadena. Japan was previously saturated by storms Halong, Neoguri and Nakri. CNN's Tom Sater contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-us">
        <news>
            <title>Judge overturns Alaska's same-sex marriage ban that dates to 1998</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/us/alaska-same-sex-marriage/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>The state says it will appeal the judge's ruling But how much luck it will have remains to be seen Five gay couples sued the state in May to overturn the ban Sunday's ruling is yet another victory for supporters of same-sex marriage</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1145</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Saeed Ahmed, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- In 1998, Alaska became the first of two states to pass a constitutional amendment to ban same-sex marriage. On Sunday, a federal judge overturned the 16-year ban, saying the Constitution guarantees equal protection to all. The judge's ruling makes Alaska the latest state where gay and lesbian couples can legally marry. "The plaintiffs in this case do not ask the court to recognize an entirely new fundamental right to same-sex marriage; rather, plaintiffs wish to participate in the existing liberty granted to other couples to make a deeply personal choice about a private family matter," U.S. District Judge Timothy Burgess wrote in his 25-page ruling. Alaska says it will appeal. "As Alaska's governor, I have a duty to defend and uphold the law and the Alaska Constitution," Gov. Sean Parnell said. But how much luck the state will have going that route remains to be seen. An appeal will take the case to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, which last week ruled against Idaho and Nevada in similar cases. First-in-the-nation ban Alaska passed its amendment in 1998 and joined Hawaii as the first of two states to define marriage as a union between a man and a woman. At the time, Alaska said the ban "does not target anybody or deny anybody their rights." Burgess said it does. "By singling out homosexual couples and banning their ability to marry an individual of their choosing, it is impossible to assert that all Alaskans are equal under the state's laws." Five gay couples sued the state in May to get the constitutional amendment overturned. Another victory Sunday's ruling is yet another victory for supporters of same-sex marriage. In a surprise move on October 6, the Supreme Court refused to get involved in the constitutional debate over same-sex marriage. That decision allowed same-sex couples to wed legally in five states -- Virginia, Utah, Oklahoma, Indiana and Wisconsin. Then, a three-judge panel from the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit concluded the bans in Idaho and Nevada violated the equal protection rights of homosexuals to legally marry. On Friday, a federal judge in North Carolina ruled that same-sex marriage can begin there. "Alaska had the misfortune of being the first state, in 1998, to ban equal marriage and bake discrimination into our constitution," said Joshua Decker, executive director of the Alaska ACLU. "Today's decision allows Alaskans to marry and to have their outside marriages recognized here. This victory brings equal rights to thousands of Alaskan couples who are in loving, committed relationships." Like dominoes falling Here's where things stand. At least 27 states now allow same-sex marriage -- an increase of at least 13 states since the beginning of the month. Those states are: California, Colorado, Connecticut, Delaware, Hawaii, Idaho, Illinois, Indiana, Iowa, Maine, Maryland, Massachusetts, Minnesota, Nevada, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New Mexico, New York, Oklahoma, Oregon, Pennsylvania, Rhode Island, Utah, Vermont, Virginia, Washington state and Wisconsin, plus the District of Columbia. Eight more states, including Alaska, could soon legalize it, after the cases wind their way through the federal appeals process: Alaska, Arizona, Kansas, North Carolina, Montana, South Carolina, West Virginia and Wyoming. CNN's Bill Mears contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Ferguson protests: Weekend of demonstrations, day of action</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/us/ferguson-protests/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>NEW: Protest organizers: "Police brutalized peaceful people protesting their brutality" About 2,000 people attended an interfaith rally where activist Cornel West spoke Demonstrators are angry about police killings of Vonderrit Myers and Michael Brown, both 18 At St. Louis QuikTrip, police pepper spray protesters in reminder of violence in Ferguson</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1409</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Sara Sidner, CNN</author>
            <text>St. Louis (CNN) -- A weekend of protests is expected to culminate in a day of action in Ferguson, Missouri, on Monday. Demonstrators demanding the arrest of the police officer who killed Michael Brown say they will take part in a "series of actions" Monday morning, but they haven't said what or where those will be. On Sunday night, about 2,000 people attended an interfaith rally, where activist and Princeton University professor Cornel West was the featured speaker. Before he took the stage at the St. Louis University's Chaifetz Arena, some protesters demanded a chance to speak. "If you can see a dead black boy lie in the streets for four hours and that doesn't make you angry, you lack humanity," a woman, who didn't give her name, told the crowd. She was referring to how long the body of Brown lay on a street before investigating officers removed it. The protests, dubbed a "Ferguson October" and "Weekend of Resistance," are taking place in Ferguson, St. Louis and the surrounding area. Demonstrations focused on the August 9 encounter between Brown, 18, and Police Officer Darren Wilson, who authorities said shot Brown after he attacked him and tried to take his gun. Mom, daughter trek 750 miles on $100 budget to join 'Weekend of Resistance' But witnesses said the unarmed teenager had his hands in the air when he was shot. The shooting prompted weeks of protests in Ferguson, which sometimes became violent when demonstrators and police clashed. The demonstrators are demanding that Wilson be charged with a crime -- a point that West also made. "Everybody knows if you shoot somebody down, you should be arrested," he said. He asked the crowd to channel their rage into a plan of action for change. New wave of protests Before this week, protests had died down considerably. But early Sunday, protesters threw rocks at police and tried to storm a QuikTrip store, according to tweets from St. Louis Metropolitan Police Chief Sam Dotson. In the Shaw neighborhood of St. Louis, protesters have also rallied against the death of Vonderrit Deondre Myers, 18. Protests erupted there after a white police officer fatally shot the black teenager. But this one was different from the Brown case because the teenager was armed and fired at the officer, according to authorities. #ferguson #shawshooting protestors take moment of silence @st louis university clock tower. #CornelWest in crowd pic.twitter.com/BOOqOECv19 Two groups of hundreds of protesters gathered in Shaw before splitting and reconvening at St. Louis University, according to CNN affiliate KTVI. One group threw a volleyball and jumped rope while chanting, "This is what a game looks like. We aren't playing games." The group marched to a QuikTrip, a reminder of the violence that happened in Ferguson, where protesters destroyed a QuikTrip in the days after the Brown shooting. Police were at the convenience store, which had been closed as a precaution, the station reported. The crowd prompted Dotson to tweet that demonstrators were trying to "storm" the gas station, and he warned that "protesters engaging in illegal behavior will be subject to arrest." After clerks locked the QuikTrip door, fearing the store could be looted and burned like the one in Ferguson, police in riot gear used pepper spray on sitting protesters surrounding the QuikTrip, CNN affiliate KPLR reported. Police told the protesters to disperse, but they wouldn't, so officers moved in, clacking their night sticks on their leg shields as they approached, the station said. Dotson tweeted that protesters threw rocks at police. Seventeen people were arrested for unlawful assembly, but no injuries or property damage was reported, KPLR said. 'They attacked people' Ferguson October, the group that helped organize the protests, took issue with Dotson's tweets, saying they only made matters worse. "Today protestors in St. Louis showed the best of our democracy and the St. Louis police demonstrated the worst of their out-of-control law enforcement agency. The police brutalized peaceful people protesting their brutality," the statement said. "With batons and chemical agents they attacked people peacefully sitting on the ground and the reporters who were there with them." At St. Louis University, roughly 2 miles from the Shaw neighborhood where Myers was shot, about 1,000 protesters gathered on campus, using the hashtag #OccupySLU to convince people and businesses to donate supplies or join an all-night sit-in. As of 5:30 a.m., about 80 protesters remained on campus, CNN affiliate KMOV reported. "The goal was to occupy SLU and to kind of wake up the campus. I think there's a sense in the community that SLU is kinda shut off from what happens outside of SLU. But this latest incident was six blocks from SLU, so it does affect us," freshman David Gramling told the station. Young Nigel waits for the rest of the #FergusonOctober marchers to catch up. pic.twitter.com/p41U76eQOp Early Monday morning, about 200 protesters marched from the site where Myers was shot, holding signs that read, "Black lives matter." Police with riot gear showed up on a bridge near the St. Louis University campus. The protesters turned on the other side of the street, stayed on the sidewalk and walked past them. The demonstrations were peaceful, and the protesters said they were serious about keeping them that way. On Sunday, Ferguson October was training protesters in nonviolent civil disobedience. "Nonviolence is really important because you're not going to change someone's mind by being violent. And also there is just so much more power in taking a stand and doing it nonviolently," Jasmin Maurer, who is taking part in the peaceful training, told KPLR. Meanwhile, authorities also took additional steps to prepare for the protests, as police told KMOV that every patrol officer in St. Louis -- city and county -- is working 12-hour shifts and days off have been canceled. City police would not say how many officers were working in the area, but a county police sergeant told the station there were about 200 officers in Ferguson alone. CNN's Eliott C. McLaughlin contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>113-year-old time capsule found in Boston</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/10/us/boston-time-capsule/index.html?hpt=us_c2</url>
            <highlits>Time capsule hidden since 1901 in Boston is discovered It holds photographs, campaign buttons and news clippings from the day The copper box is found in a statue atop the State House</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1656</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Kevin Conlon</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- A time capsule hidden for more than a hundred years at one of Boston's most popular tourist attractions was opened on Friday in Boston. According to the Bostonian Society, which maintains the 1713-built Old Massachusetts State House, the rectangular copper box containing a variety of artifacts from 1901 was sealed inside one of two iconic statues -- a lion and a unicorn -- that have been a familiar sight atop the Old State House for a couple of centuries. The Bostonian Society didn't -- or couldn't -- fully divulge the 113-year-old time capsule's contents, explaining that "the process of extracting documents that are old and probably fragile will need to be slow and careful." But a Boston Globe article from February 24, 1901, detailed what went into the box, which the story predicted would "prove interesting when the box is opened many years hence." According to the Globe, the box included the photographs and autographs of local statesmen such as Massachusetts Gov. Winthrop M. Crane and Boston Mayor Thomas Norton Hart, as well as news clippings of the day from several city newspapers and even a "letter to posterity from the reporters of the Boston Daily newspapers assigned to City Hall." It also included a photograph of the "5th Massachusetts Regiment on its way to Framingham to be mustered in as U.S. volunteers for service in the war against Spain," as well as "campaign buttons for McKinley, Roosevelt and John D. Long for vice president." The box was sealed inside the lion's head by Samuel Rogers, a local coppersmith who was part of the crew renovating the nearly 200-year-old State House. Although the occasion was detailed in the city's largest newspaper, the Bostonian Society said its current staff was unaware of the time capsule until they received a letter from a descendent of Rogers alerting them to it.</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-africa">
        <news>
            <title>Texas nurse who had worn protective gear tests positive for Ebola</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/health/ebola/index.html?hpt=iaf_c2</url>
            <highlits>A "close contact" of the nurse is being monitored, says CDC The worker helped care for an Ebola patient multiple times, CDC director says He says there was a breach in protocol and his agency is investigating Nurse was wearing protective gear when she helped care for Thomas Eric Duncan</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1112</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Elizabeth Cohen, Steve Almasy and Holly Yan, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- The deadly Ebola virus has been contracted by someone inside the United States for the first time. A nurse who had worn protective gear during her "extensive contact" at a Dallas hospital with an Ebola patient who died tested positive during a preliminary blood test, officials said Sunday. The woman had on a gown, gloves, mask and a shield during her multiple visits with Thomas Eric Duncan, but there was a breach in protocol, health officials said. The patient is a nurse at Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital in Dallas, an official who is familiar with the case told CNN. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in Atlanta conducted testing on the blood sample, and confirmed the results Sunday, marking the first known transmission of Ebola in the United States and the second diagnosis in the country. She was involved in Duncan's care after he was placed in isolation -- his second trip to the hospital after coming to the United States from Liberia -- said Dr. Tom Frieden, the director of the CDC. The nurse is in stable condition, Texas Health Resources chief clinical officer Dan Varga said. Duncan, the first person to be diagnosed with Ebola in the United States, died Wednesday. What's a hospital supposed to do if an Ebola patient shows up? The nurse had "extensive contact" on "multiple occasions" with Duncan, Frieden said. "At some point, there was a breach in protocol, and that breach in protocol resulted in this infection," he said at a news conference Sunday. "The (Ebola treatment) protocols work. ... But we know that even a single lapse or breach can result in infection." Also, Varga said that someone who is a "close contact" of the nurse has been "proactively" placed in isolation. The hazardous materials unit of the Dallas Fire Department has cleaned up and decontaminated the public areas of the health worker's apartment complex, Mayor Mike Rawlings said. Police are keeping people out of the area and are talking to residents nearby. "We have knocked on every door on that block," the mayor said. Hazardous materials units have also cleaned out the nurse's car and will work on her apartment Sunday. "This development is understandably disturbing news for the patient, the patient's family and colleagues and the greater Dallas community," the CDC said in a statement, announcing the nurse's test results. It sought to play down a wider risk. "The CDC and the Texas Department of State Health Services remain confident that wider spread in the community can be prevented with proper public health measures, including ongoing contact tracing, health monitoring among those known to have been in contact with the index patient, and immediate isolations if symptoms develop," the CDC said. Complete coverage on the Ebola outbreak Case was anticipated "We knew a second case could be a reality, and we've been preparing for this possibility," Dr. David Lakey, commissioner of the Texas Department of State Health Services, said in a statement Sunday morning. "We are broadening our team in Dallas and working with extreme diligence to prevent further spread." The nurse reported a low-grade fever Friday night and was isolated, the health department said. The preliminary test result came in late Saturday. President Barack Obama received two briefings Sunday on the second Dallas Ebola case, including one from Health and Human Services Secretary Sylvia Burwell. According to a White House statement, the President wants federal authorities to immediately take further measures to ensure health care professionals are able to follow protocols for treating Ebola patients. 'A sign the system is working' The news that a health care worker might have the disease is not completely unexpected, an infectious disease specialist told CNN's "New Day." "I think we've always expected that there may be another individual who will come down with the Ebola from the transmission of this one particular person, and we always felt that it was going to likely be one of his close contacts or one of the health care workers, because that's the way this virus works," Dr. Frank Esper said. For Ebola caregivers, enormous fear, risk and bravery Esper said Texas officials have been keeping a close eye on people who had contact with Duncan. "I will tell you that the fact that we identified this individual so quickly is actually to me a sign that the system is working," he added. Globally, the disease has wrought catastrophic consequences. The World Health Organization estimates more than 8,300 people have contracted Ebola during this year's outbreak. Of those, more than 4,000 have died. Ebola not very contagious Ebola is actually difficult to catch. People are at risk if they come into very close contact with the blood, saliva, sweat, feces, semen, vomit or soiled clothing of an Ebola patient, or if they travel to affected areas in West Africa and come into contact with someone who has Ebola. Those stricken with Ebola suffer ghastly symptoms, including vomiting, diarrhea, muscle pain, fever and internal bleeding. Three countries -- Sierra Leone, Guinea and Liberia -- have been hardest hit. And many of those who care for the ill have also come down with the disease. The World Health Organization estimates at least 416 health care workers have contracted Ebola, and at least 233 have died. In Liberia, health care workers are threatening to strike if their work conditions don't improve. The first infection outside of Africa happened in a nurse's aide in Spain, Teresa Romero Ramos. She became sick after she helped treat an Ebola-stricken Spanish missionary. Her case has prompted questions from fellow medical professionals about whether they are properly equipped to safely treat Ebola patients. Spanish Ebola patient's condition worsens, doctor says Another search begins For weeks, health officials have been monitoring those who had contact with Duncan before he was hospitalized and isolated. Duncan left Liberia on September 19 and arrived in Dallas on September 20. Four days later, he began feeling ill; the following night, he went to Texas Health Presbyterian Hospital. But despite telling a hospital worker that he had arrived from Liberia, Duncan was sent home with antibiotics. He returned a few days later and tested positive for Ebola. And now, the search begins for all the contacts whom the nurse came in contact with. "We need a whole new crew of people to do contact tracing," said Elizabeth Cohen, CNN senior medical correspondent. Because Ebola's incubation period can last up to 21 days, the health nurse's contacts will have to be monitored for three weeks. The Texas health department said officials have interviewed the patient and are identifying any contacts or potential exposures. "This is not an easy thing," Cohen said. "Keeping track of large numbers of people, taking their temperature twice a day, making sure they don't ... leave town, all of that is a lot of work." CNN's Joe Sutton, Cassie Spodak and Jen Christensen contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-asia">
        <news>
            <title>Chinese court sentences cult members to death over McDonald's killing</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/13/world/asia/china-eastern-lightning-death-sentence/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>Five members of a Chinese cult have been sentenced for a murder in a McDonald's Two were sentenced to death for the killing of a woman who refused to give them her number The group, Church of Almighty God, has been banned in China since 1995 Its members believe Jesus has been reincarnated as a Chinese woman</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>809</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- Two members of a banned Chinese doomsday cult were sentenced to death Saturday for the brutal murder of a woman in a McDonald's restaurant in May, Chinese state media reported. Zhang Fan and Zhang Lidong were among five members of the Church of Almighty God, or "Quannengshen," tried on murder charges in August over the killing in Zhaoyuan, Shandong Province, the state-run Xinhua agency reported. Three fellow cult members, Lyu Yingchun, Zhang Hang and Zhang Qiaolian, were sentenced to life, 10 and seven years in prison respectively for their roles in the attack. The four Zhangs were related, according to the report. A court statement said the victim, a 37-year-old woman named Wu Shuoyan, was attacked after refusing to give her phone number to the group, who were allegedly attempting to recruit new members. Zhang Fan and Lyu called her an "evil spirit," before Zhang bludgeoned her head with a chair, then jumped on her and trampled her head, the statement said. Zhang Lidong bashed the victim's head with a mop hard enough to break it, and stomped on her face and head, while Lyu kicked her waist and prevented McDonald's staff from intervening, the court statement said. IN DEPTH: 'Eastern Lightning,' the banned religious group that has China worried Linked to kidnappings, violence and extortion, the Church of Almighty God has been on a list of 14 banned religious groups issued by China's Ministry of Public Security since 1995. Founded in the 1990s in Henan Province, the group believes that Jesus has been reincarnated as Yang Xiangbin, the wife of the group's founder, Zhao Weishan. The couple fled to the United States in 2000, Xinhua reported. The group, also known as Eastern Lightning ("Dongfang Shandian"), preaches that the righteous are engaged in an apocalyptic struggle against China's Communist Party -- which it refers to as the "great red dragon." Belonging to a tradition of heterodox, quasi-Christian Chinese religious movements, the cult was estimated as having between several hundred thousand and one million members, according to Emily Dunn, an Asian studies academic at the University of Melbourne who wrote her doctoral thesis on the group. In August, Chinese state media reported that police had arrested nearly 1,000 suspected members of the group, including nearly 100 "backbone members." The report said those arrested were responsible for "numerous" suicides and murders, including those of their own family. In 2012, hundreds of members were rounded up after the group publicly proclaimed the end of the world was imminent. In a statement provided to CNN in June, Hong Kong-based members of the group responsible for its English-language website said it was "very natural" for the Chinese Communist Party to blame the group for the McDonald's death because the party slandered and then suppressed those that disagreed with it. "They always find some excuse in advance and fabricate things and slander them," said the statement. READ MORE: The future of Christianity in China CNN's Dayu Zhang and Katie Hunt contributed to this report.</text>
            <photos>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnn/dam/assets/140604013136-eastern-lightning-split-story-top.png</photos>
        </news>
        <news>
            <title>Vongfong slams into Kyushu, continues destructive path across Japan</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/asia/tropical-storm-vongfong-japan/index.html?hpt=ias_c2</url>
            <highlits>Tropical Storm Vongfong hits Kyushu, the southernmost of Japan's four main islands At least 36 injuries have been reported Japan's four main islands are expected to get up to 40cm of rain</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1408</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Junko Ogura and Tim Hume, CNN</author>
            <text>Tokyo (CNN) -- The latest and strongest in a string of powerful storms to hit Japan -- Vongfong -- slammed into Kyushu, the southernmost of the country's four main islands, Monday morning as it continued its destructive path across the country. Vongfong first made landfall in Japan in Okinawa early Sunday. It wreaked havoc across the prefecture, knocking out power before losing strength and being downgraded from a typhoon to a tropical storm. Meteorologists expect the storm to pass over the country's largest island, Honshu, hitting the capital, Tokyo, before dawn on Tuesday. At least 36 injuries related to the storm were reported across Okinawa, Kagoshima and Miyazaki prefectures, officials said, while at least 44,000 across the country were without power. Authorities have ordered more than 100,000 people to evacuate their homes. Police in Shizuoka said one man remained missing after three people were swept into water on Sunday at the city's port. Although a high-wave advisory had been issued at the time of the accident, the incident was classified as a water accident and not officially linked to the storm, according to Shizuoka police. Flights in and out of Kyushu and neighboring Shikoku were canceled Monday, along with local ferry and train operations. The Japan Meteorological Agency said Vongfong was expected to bring up to 40 centimeters of rain. The storm comes on the heels of Typhoon Phanfone, which swept over southern Japan last week, washing three U.S. airmen out to sea off Okinawa. U.S. and Japanese search crews found the last airman's body on Wednesday, according to a news release issued by authorities at Kadena. Japan was previously saturated by storms Halong, Neoguri and Nakri. CNN's Tom Sater contributed to this report.</text>
        </news>
    </region>
    <region area="nav-europe"/>
    <region area="nav-latin-america"/>
    <region area="nav-middle-east">
        <news>
            <title>ISIS states its justification for the enslavement of women</title>
            <url>http://edition.cnn.com/2014/10/12/world/meast/isis-justification-slavery/index.html?hpt=imi_c2</url>
            <highlits>In an online magazine, the terror group says it is legitimate under Islamic law The Muslim world at large repudiates that interpretation as a perversion of Islam</highlits>
            <date>
                <day>13</day>
                <month>October</month>
                <year>2014</year>
                <time>1702</time>
            </date>
            <author>By Salma Abdelaziz, CNN</author>
            <text>(CNN) -- In a new publication, ISIS justifies its kidnapping of women as sex slaves citing Islamic theology, an interpretation that is rejected by the Muslim world at large as a perversion of Islam. "One should remember that enslaving the families of the kuffar -- the infidels -- and taking their women as concubines is a firmly established aspect of the Shariah, or Islamic law," the group says in an online magazine published Sunday. The title of the article sums up the ISIS point of view: "The revival (of) slavery before the Hour," referring to Judgment Day. The fourth edition of the group's English-language digital magazine called "Dabiq" said that female members of the Yazidi sect, an ethnically Kurdish minority living mostly in Iraq, may legitimately be captured and forcibly made concubines or sexual slaves. The rationalization for a return to slavery -- repudiated around the world -- coincided with the release of a Human Rights Watch report on crimes committed by ISIS against the Yazidis in Iraq based on interviews with 76 displaced people in Dohuk. "The Islamic State's litany of horrific crimes against the Yazidis in Iraq only keeps growing," said Fred Abrahams, special adviser at Human Rights Watch. "We heard shocking stories of forced religious conversions, forced marriage, and even sexual assault and slavery -- and some of the victims were children." A 17-year-old kidnapped girl named Adlee recounts how a large bearded man forced her into a home in Falluja, where she was beaten and endured violent sexual advances before escaping two days later, the Human Rights Watch report reads. ISIS forced tens of thousands of Yazidis to flee their homes in August when the extremists stormed many of the community's towns and cities in Iraqi Kurdistan. Displaced families and monitoring groups reported jihadists kidnapped hundreds of Yazidi women and girls, and many were sold or given away to militants as "spoils of war." The terror group's 56-page propaganda publication also boasts of a "massacre against (Kurdish) PKK soldiers" alongside graphic images of slain men dressed in fatigues. On the next page, ISIS glorifies its "Services for Muslims" with photographs of a care home for the elderly and a cancer treatment center for children. The issue, titled "The Failed Crusade," includes an alleged copy of slain American journalist Steven Sotloff's last letter to his mother and says the victim's Jewish identity warranted his beheading by ISIS. Another ISIS captive, British journalist John Cantlie, allegedly pens the last section of the magazine, saying he expects to be killed soon, and "unless something changes very quickly and very radically, I await my turn."</text>
        </news>
    </region>
</regions>
